<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<rss version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <link>https://aws.amazon.com/about-aws/whats-new/recent/</link>
        <title>Recent Announcements</title>
        <description>The AWS Cloud platform expands daily. Learn about announcements, launches,
            news, innovation and more from Amazon Web Services.</description>
        <managingEditor>aws@amazon.com (Amazon Web Services)</managingEditor>
        <lastBuildDate>Fri, 30 Jan 2026 13:09:01 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <pubDate>Fri, 30 Jan 2026 13:09:01 GMT</pubDate>
        <docs>http://blogs.law.harvard.edu/tech/rss</docs>
        <image>
            <url>https://a0.awsstatic.com/main/images/logos/aws_logo_smile_179x109.png</url>
            <link>https://aws.amazon.com/about-aws/whats-new/recent/</link>
            <title>Recent Announcements</title>
            <description>The AWS Cloud platform expands daily. Learn about announcements, launches,
                news, innovation and more from Amazon Web Services.</description>
        </image>
        <item>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">89e14b8ca02de705f1eb30723b8a5491a1e6eaf1</guid>
            <title>Announcing increased 1 MB payload size support in Amazon EventBridge</title>
            <description>
                &lt;p&gt;Amazon EventBridge increases event payload size from 256 KB to 1
                MB, enabling developers to ingest richer, complex payloads for their event-driven
                workloads without the need to split, compress, or externalize data.&lt;br&gt;
                &lt;br&gt; &lt;a href="https://aws.amazon.com/eventbridge/"&gt;Amazon
                EventBridge&lt;/a&gt; is a serverless event router that enables you to create
                scalable event-driven applications by routing events between your applications,
                third-party SaaS applications, and AWS services. These applications often need to
                process rich contextual data, including large-language model prompts, telemetry
                signals, and complex JSON structures for machine learning outputs. The new 1MB
                payload support in EventBridge Event Buses enables developers to streamline their
                architectures by including comprehensive data in a single event, reducing the need
                for complex data chunking or external storage solutions.&lt;br&gt; &lt;br&gt; This
                feature is available in all commercial AWS Regions where Amazon EventBridge is
                offered, except Asia Pacific (New Zealand), Asia Pacific (Thailand), Asia Pacific
                (Malaysia), Asia Pacific (Taipei), and Mexico (Central). For a full list, see the
                &lt;a
                href="https://aws.amazon.com/about-aws/global-infrastructure/regional-product-services/"&gt;AWS
                Regional Services List&lt;/a&gt;. To learn more, visit the EventBridge &lt;a
                href="https://docs.aws.amazon.com/eventbridge/latest/userguide/eb-event-bus.html"&gt;documentation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
            <pubDate>Thu, 29 Jan 2026 18:30:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <category>marketing:marchitecture/serverless</category>
            <author>aws@amazon.com</author>
            <link>
                https://aws.amazon.com/about-aws/whats-new/2026/01/amazon-eventbridge-increases-event-payload-size-256-kb-1-mb</link>
        </item>
        <item>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">29f3a26e52f43060c2eef9bb98a444db1984d163</guid>
            <title>Amazon Bedrock now supports server-side custom tools using the Responses API </title>
            <description>
                &lt;p&gt;Amazon Bedrock now supports server-side tools in the Responses API
                using OpenAI API-compatible service endpoints. Bedrock already supports client-side
                tool use with the Converse, Chat Completions, and Responses APIs. Now, with the
                launch of server-side tool use for Responses API, Amazon Bedrock calls the tools
                directly without going through a client, enabling your AI applications to perform
                real-time, multi-step actions such as searching the web, executing code, and
                updating databases within the organizational, governance, compliance, and security
                boundaries of your AWS accounts. You can either submit your own custom Lambda
                function to run custom tools or use AWS-provided tools, such as notes and
                tasks.&lt;/p&gt;
                &lt;p&gt;Server-side tools using the Responses API is available starting today with
                OpenAI's GPT OSS 20B/120B models in US East (N. Virginia), US East (Ohio), US West
                (Oregon), Asia Pacific (Tokyo), Asia Pacific (Mumbai), South America (São Paulo),
                Europe (Ireland), Europe (London), and Europe (Milan) AWS Regions. Support for other
                regions and models is coming soon.&lt;/p&gt;
                &lt;p&gt;To get started, visit the service &lt;a
                href="https://docs.aws.amazon.com/bedrock/latest/userguide/tool-use.html"&gt;documentation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
            <pubDate>Thu, 29 Jan 2026 18:09:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <category>
                general:products/amazon-bedrock,marketing:marchitecture/artificial-intelligence</category>
            <author>aws@amazon.com</author>
            <link>
                https://aws.amazon.com/about-aws/whats-new/2026/01/amazon-bedrock-server-side-custom-tools-responses-api</link>
        </item>
        <item>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">0df984c93c71f4eac2aac37299126353e6ef1f4f</guid>
            <title>Amazon Cognito introduces inbound federation Lambda triggers</title>
            <description>&lt;p&gt;Amazon Cognito introduces inbound federation Lambda triggers that
                enable you to transform and customize federated user attributes during the
                authentication process. You can now modify responses from external SAML and OIDC
                providers before they are stored in your user pool, providing complete programmatic
                control over the federation flow without requiring changes to your identity provider
                configuration..&lt;/p&gt;
                &lt;p&gt;Inbound federation Lambda trigger addresses current limitations in
                federated authentication workflows, particularly issues caused by attribute size
                limits and the need for selective attribute storage from external identity
                providers. For example, large group attributes from external SAML or OIDC identity
                providers that exceed Cognito’s 2,048 character limit per attribute can block the
                authentication flow. This capability allows you to add, override, or suppress
                attribute values, such as modifying large group attributes, before creating new
                federated users or updating existing federated user profiles in Cognito.&lt;/p&gt;
                &lt;p&gt;The new inbound federation Lambda trigger is available through hosted UI
                (classic) and managed login in all AWS Regions where Amazon Cognito is available. To
                get started, configure the trigger using the AWS Management Console, AWS Command
                Line Interface (CLI), AWS Software Development Kits (SDKs), Cloud Development Kit
                (CDK), or AWS CloudFormation by adding the new&amp;nbsp;parameter to your User
                Pool&amp;nbsp;LambdaConfig. To learn more, see the&amp;nbsp;&lt;a
                href="https://docs.aws.amazon.com/cognito/latest/developerguide/user-pool-lambda-inbound-federation.html"&gt;Amazon
                Cognito Developer Guide&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;for implementation examples and
                best&amp;nbsp;practices.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
            <pubDate>Thu, 29 Jan 2026 18:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <category>
                general:products/amazon-cognito,marketing:marchitecture/security-identity-and-compliance</category>
            <author>aws@amazon.com</author>
            <link>
                https://aws.amazon.com/about-aws/whats-new/2026/01/amazon-cognito-inbound-federation-lambda-trigger/</link>
        </item>
        <item>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">bab5873a16f942ba1d2490008f49d49523f68481</guid>
            <title>Amazon Keyspaces (for Apache Cassandra) introduces pre-warming with
                WarmThroughput for your tables</title>
            <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://aws.amazon.com/keyspaces/"
                target="_blank"&gt;Amazon Keyspaces (for Apache Cassandra)&lt;/a&gt; now supports
                table pre-warming, allowing you to proactively prepare both new and existing tables
                to meet future traffic demands. This capability is available for tables in both
                provisioned and on-demand capacity modes, including multi-Region replicated
                tables.&lt;br&gt; &lt;br&gt; Amazon Keyspaces (for Apache Cassandra) is a scalable,
                highly available, and managed Apache Cassandra–compatible database service. Amazon
                Keyspaces is serverless, so you pay for only the resources that you use and you can
                build applications that serve thousands of requests per second with virtually
                unlimited throughput and storage.&lt;br&gt; &lt;br&gt; While Amazon Keyspaces
                automatically scales to accommodate growing workloads, certain scenarios like
                application launches, marketing campaigns, or seasonal events can create sudden
                traffic spikes that exceed normal scaling patterns. With pre-warming, you can now
                manually specify your expected peak throughput requirements during table creation or
                update operations, ensuring your tables are immediately ready to handle large
                traffic surges without scaling delays or increased error rates.&lt;br&gt; &lt;br&gt;
                The pre-warming process is non-disruptive and runs asynchronously, allowing you to
                continue making other table modifications while pre-warming is in progress.
                Pre-warming incurs a one-time charge based on the difference between your specified
                values and the baseline capacity. The feature is now available in all AWS Commercial
                and AWS GovCloud (US) Regions where Amazon Keyspaces is offered. To learn
                more,&amp;nbsp;visit the &lt;a
                href="https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/database/introducing-pre-warming-for-amazon-keyspaces-tables/"&gt;pre-warming
                launch blog&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a
                href="https://docs.aws.amazon.com/keyspaces/latest/devguide/warm-throughput.html"&gt;Amazon
                Keyspaces documentation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
            <pubDate>Thu, 29 Jan 2026 15:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <category>
                general:products/aws-govcloud-us,marketing:marchitecture/databases,general:products/amazon-keyspaces</category>
            <author>aws@amazon.com</author>
            <link>
                https://aws.amazon.com/about-aws/whats-new/2026/01/amazon-keyspaces-apache-cassandra-pre-warming-warmthroughput-tables</link>
        </item>
        <item>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">3a8eb5fe257edff911ce38c3c6c06b463531fb76</guid>
            <title>Change the server-side encryption type of Amazon S3 objects</title>
            <description>
                &lt;p&gt;You can now change the server-side encryption type of encrypted
                objects in Amazon S3 without any data movement. You can use the
                UpdateObjectEncryption API to atomically change the encryption key of your objects
                regardless of the object size or storage class. With S3 Batch Operations, you can
                use UpdateObjectEncryption at scale to standardize the encryption type on entire
                buckets of objects while preserving object properties and S3 Lifecycle
                eligibility.&lt;br&gt; &lt;br&gt; Customers across many industries face increasingly
                stringent audit and compliance requirements on data security and privacy. A common
                requirement for these compliance frameworks is more rigorous encryption standards
                for data-at-rest, where organizations must encrypt data using a key management
                service. With UpdateObjectEncryption, customers can now change the encryption type
                of existing encrypted objects to move from Amazon S3 managed server-side encryption
                (SSE-S3) to use server-side encryption with AWS KMS keys (SSE-KMS). You can also
                change the customer-managed KMS key used to encrypt your data to comply with custom
                key rotation standards or enable the use of S3 Bucket Keys to reduce your KMS
                requests.&lt;br&gt; &lt;br&gt; The Amazon S3 UpdateObjectEncryption API is available
                in all AWS Regions. To get started, you can use the AWS Management Console or the
                latest AWS SDKs to update the server-side encryption type of your objects. To learn
                more, please visit the &lt;a
                href="https://docs.aws.amazon.com/AmazonS3/latest/userguide/update-sse-encryption.html"&gt;documentation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
            <pubDate>Thu, 29 Jan 2026 13:28:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <category>general:products/amazon-s3,marketing:marchitecture/storage</category>
            <author>aws@amazon.com</author>
            <link>
                https://aws.amazon.com/about-aws/whats-new/2026/01/change-the-server-side-encryption-type-of-s3-objects</link>
        </item>
        <item>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">9c743f4565a371caf970d9b870f7aeb3751edb76</guid>
            <title>AWS announces Deployment Agent SOPs in AWS MCP Server (preview)</title>
            <description>&lt;p&gt;AWS announces the launch of deployment Standard Operating
                Procedures (SOPs) available in the &lt;a
                href="https://docs.aws.amazon.com/aws-mcp/latest/userguide/what-is-mcp-server.html"&gt;AWS
                MCP Server&lt;/a&gt;. SOPs are structured, natural language instructions that guide
                AI agents through complex, multi-step tasks to ensure consistent, reliable, and
                efficient behavior. With these automated procedures, customers can deploy web
                applications to their AWS account using natural language prompts from any
                MCP-compatible IDE or CLI, including Kiro, Kiro CLI, Cursor, and Claude Code.
                Deployment works by generating AWS CDK infrastructure, deploying CloudFormation
                stacks, and creating CI/CD pipelines with recommended AWS security best
                practices.&lt;br&gt; &lt;br&gt; Previously, developers struggled to take their
                vibe-coded applications to production with DevOps best practices in place. Now,
                developers can move quickly from prototype to production in as little as one prompt.
                When you ask your AI assistant configured with AWS MCP Server to deploy your web
                application, your AI agent will follow the multi-step plan defined in Agent SOPs to
                analyze the project structure, generate CDK infrastructure, and deploy a preview
                environment hosted on Amazon S3 and Amazon CloudFront. Once you are ready, it can
                configure AWS CodePipeline for automated production deployments from source
                repositories, setting up CI/CD automatically for your application. The Agent SOPs
                support web applications built with popular frameworks including React, Vue.js,
                Angular, and Next.js. Deployment documentation is automatically created in the
                repository, enabling agents to handle future deployments, query logs for
                troubleshooting and resume work across sessions.&lt;br&gt; &lt;br&gt; The Agent SOPs
                are available in preview as part of the AWS MCP Server at no additional cost in the
                US East (N. Virginia) Region. You pay only for AWS resources you create and
                applicable data transfer costs. To get started, see the &lt;a
                href="https://docs.aws.amazon.com/aws-mcp/latest/userguide/agent-sops-deployment.html"&gt;AWS
                MCP Server documentation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
            <pubDate>Thu, 29 Jan 2026 12:01:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <category>
                general:products/aws-developer-tools,marketing:marchitecture/artificial-intelligence,marketing:marchitecture/front-end-web-mobile,marketing:marchitecture/developer-tools</category>
            <author>aws@amazon.com</author>
            <link>
                https://aws.amazon.com/about-aws/whats-new/2025/01/aws-announces-deployment-agent-sops-in-aws-mcp-server-preview</link>
        </item>
        <item>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">44cf055438d7fce5c2eba09e77870637cdf639cb</guid>
            <title>Amazon GameLift Servers now supports automatic scaling to and from zero instances</title>
            <description>&lt;p&gt;Amazon GameLift Servers now enables automatic scaling to and from
                zero instances, addressing a critical cost optimization challenge for game
                developers. Previously, developers had to maintain running instances even during
                periods of low or no activity in order for Fleet autoscaling to remain active. This
                resulted in unnecessary infrastructure costs during off-peak hours. With automatic
                scaling to and from zero instances, game developers using Amazon GameLift Servers
                can optimize their multiplayer gaming infrastructure costs while maintaining
                responsive performance.&lt;br&gt; &lt;br&gt; By eliminating charges for unused
                instances during inactive periods, while automatically scaling up when game sessions
                are requested, this new capability delivers significant cost savings for game
                developers. This is particularly valuable for games with distinct peak and off-peak
                periods, seasonal or event-based games, new game launches with uncertain traffic
                patterns, and regional games with time-zone specific activity. Additionally, scaling
                decisions no longer need manual intervention, as Amazon GameLift Servers
                intelligently adapts to natural gaming activity patterns.&lt;br&gt; &lt;br&gt; The
                automatic scaling to zero instances capability is available in all Amazon GameLift
                Servers supported regions. To learn more about Amazon GameLift Servers automatic
                scaling capabilities and implementation details, visit the &lt;a
                href="https://docs.aws.amazon.com/gameliftservers/latest/developerguide/release-notes.html"
                target="_blank"&gt;Amazon GameLift Servers documentation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
            <pubDate>Thu, 29 Jan 2026 09:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <category>general:products/amazon-gamelift,marketing:marchitecture/game-development</category>
            <author>aws@amazon.com</author>
            <link>
                https://aws.amazon.com/about-aws/whats-new/2026/01/amazon-gamelift-servers-automatic-scaling</link>
        </item>
        <item>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2ff234ff5855140fd30bfc3d38dc35c995696310</guid>
            <title>Amazon EKS and Amazon EKS Distro now supports Kubernetes version 1.35</title>
            <description>
                &lt;p&gt;Kubernetes version 1.35 introduced several new features and bug
                fixes, and AWS is excited to announce that you can now use &lt;a
                href="https://aws.amazon.com/eks/"&gt;Amazon Elastic Kubernetes Service&lt;/a&gt;
                (EKS) and &lt;a href="https://aws.amazon.com/eks/eks-distro/"&gt;Amazon EKS
                Distro&lt;/a&gt; to run Kubernetes version 1.35. Starting today, you can create new
                EKS clusters using version 1.35 and upgrade existing clusters to version 1.35 using
                the EKS console, the eksctl command line interface, or through an
                infrastructure-as-code tool.&lt;br&gt; &lt;br&gt; Kubernetes version 1.35 introduces
                several key improvements, including In-Place Pod Resource Updates allowing CPU and
                memory adjustments without restarting Pods, and PreferSameNode Traffic Distribution
                prioritizing local endpoints before routing to remote nodes for reduced latency. The
                release brings Node Topology Labels via Downward API enabling Pods to access region
                and zone information without API server queries, alongside Image Volumes delivering
                data artifacts like AI models using OCI container images. To learn more about the
                changes in Kubernetes version 1.35, see our &lt;a
                href="https://docs.aws.amazon.com/eks/latest/userguide/kubernetes-versions-standard.html"&gt;documentation&lt;/a&gt;
                and the Kubernetes project &lt;a
                href="https://github.com/kubernetes/kubernetes/blob/master/CHANGELOG/CHANGELOG-1.35.md"&gt;release
                notes.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br&gt; &lt;br&gt; EKS now supports Kubernetes version 1.35 in
                all the AWS Regions where EKS is available, including the AWS GovCloud (US)
                Regions.&lt;br&gt; &lt;br&gt; You can learn more about the Kubernetes versions
                available on EKS and instructions to update your cluster to version 1.35 by visiting
                EKS documentation. You can use &lt;a
                href="https://docs.aws.amazon.com/eks/latest/userguide/cluster-insights.html"&gt;EKS
                cluster insights&lt;/a&gt; to check if there are any issues that can impact your
                Kubernetes cluster upgrades. EKS Distro builds of Kubernetes version 1.35 are
                available through ECR Public Gallery and GitHub. Learn more about the EKS version
                lifecycle policies in the &lt;a
                href="https://docs.aws.amazon.com/eks/latest/userguide/kubernetes-versions.html"&gt;documentation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
            <pubDate>Wed, 28 Jan 2026 23:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <category>general:products/amazon-eks,marketing:marchitecture/containers</category>
            <author>aws@amazon.com</author>
            <link>
                https://aws.amazon.com/about-aws/whats-new/2026/01/amazon-eks-distro-kubernetes-version-1-35</link>
        </item>
        <item>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">f985ef301df2afe583b112199e1b05a5dbcc6dfa</guid>
            <title>Amazon EC2 R7gd instances are now available in Europe (Paris) Region</title>
            <description>&lt;p&gt;Starting today, Amazon Elastic Compute Cloud (Amazon EC2) R7gd
                instances with up to 3.8 TB of local NVMe-based SSD block-level storage are
                available in Europe (Paris) Region.&lt;br&gt; &lt;br&gt; R7gd are powered by AWS
                Graviton3 processors with DDR5 memory are built on the&amp;nbsp;&lt;a
                href="https://aws.amazon.com/ec2/nitro/" target="_blank"&gt;AWS Nitro
                System&lt;/a&gt;. They are ideal for memory-intensive workloads such as open-source
                databases, in-memory caches, and real-time big data analytics and are a great fit
                for applications that need access to high-speed, low latency local storage,
                including those that need temporary storage of data for scratch space, temporary
                files, and caches.&amp;nbsp;&lt;br&gt; &lt;br&gt; To learn more, see&amp;nbsp;&lt;a
                href="https://aws.amazon.com/ec2/instance-types/r7g/" target="_blank"&gt;Amazon R7gd
                Instances&lt;/a&gt;. To get started, see the&amp;nbsp;&lt;a
                href="https://console.aws.amazon.com/" target="_blank"&gt;AWS Management
                Console&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
            <pubDate>Wed, 28 Jan 2026 18:18:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <category>general:products/amazon-ec2</category>
            <author>aws@amazon.com</author>
            <link>
                https://aws.amazon.com/about-aws/whats-new/2026/01/r7gd-instances-available-in-paris</link>
        </item>
        <item>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">50ef6b11eae7a2ab6501885b414e0a83c0719995</guid>
            <title>Amazon MSK Replicator is now available in Asia Pacific (New Zealand)</title>
            <description>&lt;p&gt;You can now use Amazon MSK Replicator to replicate streaming data
                across Amazon Managed Streaming for Apache Kafka (&lt;a
                href="https://aws.amazon.com/msk/"&gt;Amazon MSK&lt;/a&gt;) clusters in Asia Pacific
                (New Zealand) Region.&lt;br&gt; &lt;br&gt; MSK Replicator is a feature of Amazon MSK
                that enables you to reliably replicate data across Amazon MSK clusters in different
                or the same AWS Region(s) in a few clicks. With MSK Replicator, you can easily build
                regionally resilient streaming applications for increased availability and business
                continuity. MSK Replicator provides automatic asynchronous replication across MSK
                clusters, eliminating the need to write custom code, manage infrastructure, or setup
                cross-region networking. MSK Replicator automatically scales the underlying
                resources so that you can replicate data on-demand without having to monitor or
                scale capacity. MSK Replicator also replicates the necessary Kafka metadata
                including topic configurations, Access Control Lists (ACLs), and consumer group
                offsets. If an unexpected event occurs in a region, you can failover to the other
                AWS Region and seamlessly resume processing.&lt;br&gt; &lt;br&gt; You can get
                started with MSK Replicator from the Amazon MSK console or the Amazon CLI. With this
                launch, MSK Replicator is now available in thirty six AWS Regions. To learn more,
                visit the MSK Replicator &lt;a
                href="https://docs.aws.amazon.com/msk/latest/developerguide/msk-replicator.html"&gt;documentation&lt;/a&gt;,
                &lt;a href="https://aws.amazon.com/msk/features/msk-replicator/"&gt;product
                page&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href="https://aws.amazon.com/msk/pricing/"&gt;pricing
                page&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
            <pubDate>Wed, 28 Jan 2026 16:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <category>marketing:marchitecture/analytics,general:products/amazon-msk</category>
            <author>aws@amazon.com</author>
            <link>
                https://aws.amazon.com/about-aws/whats-new/2026/01/amazon-msk-replicator-asia-pacific-new-zealand</link>
        </item>
        <item>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">5315cc73011c15a251c084e4bc03353c0116b0e0</guid>
            <title>Amazon DynamoDB global tables with multi-Region strong consistency now supports
                application resiliency testing with AWS Fault Injection Service</title>
            <description>&lt;p&gt;Amazon &lt;a
                href="https://aws.amazon.com/dynamodb/"&gt;DynamoDB&lt;/a&gt; global tables with
                multi-Region strong consistency (MRSC) now supports application resiliency testing
                with AWS &lt;a href="https://aws.amazon.com/fis/"&gt;Fault Injection
                Service&lt;/a&gt; (FIS), a fully managed service for running controlled fault
                injection experiments to improve application performance, observability, and
                resilience. With this launch, you can create real-world failure scenarios to MRSC
                global tables, such as during regional failures, enabling you to observe how your
                applications respond to these disruptions and validate your resilience
                mechanisms.&lt;br&gt; &lt;br&gt; MRSC global tables replicate your DynamoDB tables
                automatically across your choice of AWS Regions to achieve fast, strongly consistent
                read and write performance, providing you &lt;a
                href="https://aws.amazon.com/dynamodb/sla/"&gt;99.999% availability&lt;/a&gt;,
                increased application resiliency, and improved business continuity. FIS is a fully
                managed service for running controlled fault injection experiments to improve an
                application’s performance, observability, and resilience.&amp;nbsp;You can use the
                new FIS action to observe how your application responds to a pause in regional
                replication and tune monitoring and recovery processes to improve resiliency and
                application availability.&lt;br&gt; &lt;br&gt; MRSC global tables support for FIS is
                available in the following &lt;a
                href="https://aws.amazon.com/about-aws/global-infrastructure/regional-product-services/"&gt;AWS
                Regions&lt;/a&gt;: US East (N. Virginia), US East (Ohio), US West (Oregon), Asia
                Pacific (Tokyo), Asia Pacific (Osaka), Asia Pacific (Seoul), Europe (Ireland),
                Europe (London), Europe (Frankfurt), and Europe (Paris). To get started, visit the
                &lt;a
                href="https://docs.aws.amazon.com/fis/latest/userguide/fis-actions-reference.html#dynamodb-actions-reference"&gt;DynamoDB
                FIS actions documentation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
            <pubDate>Wed, 28 Jan 2026 11:38:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <category>marketing:marchitecture/databases,general:products/amazon-dynamodb</category>
            <author>aws@amazon.com</author>
            <link>
                https://aws.amazon.com/about-aws/whats-new/2026/01/amazon-dynamodb-global-tables-with-mrsc-fis/</link>
        </item>
        <item>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">5027b1b721aa64b572dada3be1d7ef60127dc466</guid>
            <title>AWS Deadline Cloud now supports editing job name and description</title>
            <description>&lt;p&gt;AWS Deadline Cloud now supports editing job names and descriptions
                after submission. This new feature makes it easier to organize and identify jobs
                after submission by updating names or adding useful tracking details in the
                description field.&lt;br&gt; &lt;br&gt; Job names and descriptions are critical
                metadata for organizing and understanding between users and projects, often tracking
                things like shot and sequence number across systems. Previously they could only be
                set at job creation during submission, being able to edit them after submission
                allows you to fix issues in naming as well as add key tracking information to the
                job description for other users.&lt;br&gt; &lt;br&gt; You can edit job names and
                descriptions using the AWS SDK, Deadline client, and Deadline Monitor. To learn more
                see the&amp;nbsp;&lt;a
                href="https://docs.aws.amazon.com/deadline-cloud/latest/userguide/jobs-monitoring.html"&gt;AWS
                Deadline Cloud documentation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
            <pubDate>Tue, 27 Jan 2026 19:21:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <category>general:products/aws-deadline-cloud,marketing:marchitecture/media-services</category>
            <author>aws@amazon.com</author>
            <link>
                https://aws.amazon.com/about-aws/whats-new/2026/01/aws-deadline-cloud-editing-job-name-description/</link>
        </item>
        <item>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">80eff4b4070fa927fc8befe0d8142d94e14ec597</guid>
            <title>AWS Network Firewall now supports GenAI traffic visibility and enforcement with
                Web category-based filtering</title>
            <description>&lt;p&gt;AWS Network Firewall now provides visibility into generative AI
                (GenAI) application traffic and supports traffic filtering based on web categories.
                This new capability simplifies governance by enabling you to identify and control
                access to GenAI services, social media platforms, streaming sites, and other web
                categories directly within your firewall rules using pre-defined URL
                categories.&lt;br&gt; &lt;br&gt; This approach of inspecting traffic based on URL
                categories helps security and compliance teams enforce consistent policies across
                their AWS environments while providing visibility into usage of emerging
                technologies like GenAI. You can now easily block access to inappropriate or
                high-risk domains, restrict GenAI tool usage to approved services, and meet
                regulatory requirements—all while reducing operational overhead. When combined with
                AWS Network Firewall's TLS inspection feature, you can inspect the full URL path
                using category-based rules for even more granular control.&lt;br&gt; &lt;br&gt; This
                feature is available in all AWS commercial regions where AWS Network Firewall is
                supported.&lt;br&gt; &lt;br&gt; To learn more about URL category filtering in AWS
                Network Firewall, visit AWS Network Firewall &lt;a
                href="https://aws.amazon.com/network-firewall/" target="_blank"&gt;product
                page&lt;/a&gt; and service &lt;a
                href="https://docs.aws.amazon.com/network-firewall/latest/developerguide/rule-groups-url-filtering.html"
                target="_blank"&gt;documentation&lt;/a&gt;. You can get started by updating your
                stateful rule groups in the AWS Management Console, AWS CLI, or AWS
                SDKs.&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="https://aws.amazon.com"
                target="_blank"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
            <pubDate>Tue, 27 Jan 2026 19:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <category>
                marketing:marchitecture/networking-and-content-delivery,general:products/aws-network-firewall,marketing:marchitecture/networking,marketing:marchitecture/security-identity-and-compliance</category>
            <author>aws@amazon.com</author>
            <link>
                https://aws.amazon.com/about-aws/whats-new/2026/01/aws-network-firewall-web-category-based-filtering</link>
        </item>
        <item>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">51445502116b6c8c2f203b8836c5698e4c730a41</guid>
            <title>AWS Marketplace expands AMI self-service listing experience to FPGA products</title>
            <description>&lt;p&gt;AWS Marketplace now offers a self-service listing experience for
                sellers listing Amazon Machine Image (AMI) products with FPGA (Field Programmable
                Gate Array) images. This new capability eliminates the previous dependency on manual
                Product Load Forms and accelerates time-to-market for AWS partners that offer
                specialized hardware accelerators using FPGA technology on supported Amazon F2
                instance types.&lt;br&gt; &lt;br&gt; With this launch, sellers can now create and
                manage AMIs with Amazon FPGA images using a new UI experience or programmatically
                through the AWS Marketplace Catalog API. During listing creation, sellers are guided
                through a step-by-step workflow to fill in required information about their listings
                including up to 15 Amazon FPGA images. The self-service experience includes
                comprehensive inline validation and error messages to help sellers identify and
                resolve configuration issues before submission, streamlining the publishing process
                and improving speed to market.&lt;br&gt; &lt;br&gt; To learn more, see the &lt;a
                href="https://docs.aws.amazon.com/marketplace/latest/userguide/ami-getting-started.html#ami-fpga-products"&gt;AWS
                Marketplace Seller Guide&lt;/a&gt; and the AWS Marketplace &lt;a
                href="https://docs.aws.amazon.com/marketplace/latest/APIReference/work-with-single-ami-products.html"&gt;Catalog
                API guide&lt;/a&gt;. To get started, visit the server &lt;a
                href="https://aws.amazon.com/marketplace/management/products/server?refid=a1eab8e1-44df-4b59-97a0-7f429e638b4b"&gt;product
                page&lt;/a&gt; in the AWS Marketplace Management Portal.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
            <pubDate>Tue, 27 Jan 2026 17:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <category>general:products/aws-marketplace</category>
            <author>aws@amazon.com</author>
            <link>
                https://aws.amazon.com/about-aws/whats-new/2026/01/aws-marketplace-expands-ami-self-service-listing-experience-to-fpga-products</link>
        </item>
        <item>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">d44143c054e2b2c23915ddffa150d40661cc371c</guid>
            <title>Amazon WorkSpaces announces advanced printer redirection</title>
            <description>&lt;p&gt;AWS announces advanced printer redirection for Amazon WorkSpaces
                Personal, enabling Windows users to access the full feature set of their printers
                from their virtual desktop environments. With this feature, customers can now use
                printer-specific capabilities such as double-sided printing, paper tray selection,
                finishing options (stapling, hole-punching), and color management directly from
                their Windows WorkSpaces.&lt;/p&gt;
                &lt;p&gt;Advanced printer redirection addresses the need for specialized printing
                features that require printer-specific drivers rather than generic drivers. This
                capability is ideal for organizations with users who need advanced printing features
                for professional documents, labels, or specialized output. The feature includes
                configurable driver validation modes (exact match, partial match, or name-only
                matching) to balance compatibility with feature support, allowing administrators to
                optimize for their specific environment. When matching drivers are not found,
                WorkSpaces automatically falls back to basic printing mode, ensuring users can
                always print.&lt;/p&gt;
                &lt;p&gt;This feature is available in all AWS Regions where Amazon WorkSpaces
                Personal is offered. Advanced printer redirection is supported on Windows WorkSpaces
                with Windows clients only, and requires WorkSpaces Agent version 2.2.0.2116 or later
                and Windows client version 5.31 or later. Matching printer drivers must be installed
                on both the WorkSpace and the client device.&lt;/p&gt;
                &lt;p&gt;For more information about advanced printer redirection in Amazon
                WorkSpaces, see &lt;a
                href="https://docs.aws.amazon.com/workspaces/latest/adminguide/group_policy.html"
                target="_blank"&gt;Configure Printer Support for DCV&lt;/a&gt; in the Amazon
                WorkSpaces Administration Guide, or visit the &lt;a
                href="https://aws.amazon.com/workspaces-family/workspaces/"
                target="_blank"&gt;Amazon WorkSpaces&lt;/a&gt; page to learn more about virtual
                desktop solutions from AWS.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
            <pubDate>Tue, 27 Jan 2026 17:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <category>
                general:products/nice-dcv,general:products/amazon-workspaces,marketing:marchitecture/desktop-and-app-streaming</category>
            <author>aws@amazon.com</author>
            <link>
                https://aws.amazon.com/about-aws/whats-new/2026/01/amazon-workspaces-advanced-printer-redirection/</link>
        </item>
        <item>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">48a65aba2f63ad1325353cbb732078b80b80cb01</guid>
            <title>Amazon RDS for PostgreSQL, MySQL and MariaDB now support r6id and r6gd database
                instances in additional AWS Regions </title>
            <description>&lt;p&gt;AWS memory optimized R6id database instances are now generally
                available for Amazon RDS for PostgreSQL, MySQL, and MariaDB in the Tel Aviv region.
                R6gd instances are now supported for Amazon RDS for PostgreSQL, MySQL, and MariaDB
                in Asia Pacific (Osaka), and EU (Spain, Zurich) regions.&lt;br&gt; &lt;br&gt;
                &amp;nbsp;AWS Graviton2-based instances provide up to 40% performance improvement
                over R5-based instances of equivalent sizes on Amazon Aurora and Amazon RDS
                databases, depending on database engine, version, and workload. R6gd instances also
                deliver local NVMe-based block level storage for low latency local storage.
                Memory-optimized R6id instances offer 58% higher TB storage per vCPU and 15% better
                price performance when compared with R5d instances.&lt;br&gt; &lt;br&gt; You can
                easily launch R6gd or R6id database instances through the &lt;a
                href="https://console.aws.amazon.com/rds/home" target="_blank"&gt;Amazon RDS
                Management Console&lt;/a&gt; or by using the &lt;a
                href="https://docs.aws.amazon.com/AmazonRDS/latest/AuroraUserGuide/Aurora.CreateInstance.html"
                target="_blank"&gt;AWS Command Line Interface&lt;/a&gt; (CLI). For detailed
                information about specific engine versions that support these database instance
                types, please refer to the &lt;a
                href="https://docs.aws.amazon.com/AmazonRDS/latest/AuroraUserGuide/Concepts.DBInstanceClass.SupportAurora.html"
                target="_blank"&gt;Aurora&amp;nbsp;&lt;/a&gt;and &lt;a
                href="https://docs.aws.amazon.com/AmazonRDS/latest/UserGuide/Concepts.DBInstanceClass.Support.html"
                target="_blank"&gt;RDS&lt;/a&gt; documentation. For complete information on pricing
                and regional availability, please refer to the Amazon RDS &lt;a
                href="https://aws.amazon.com/rds/pricing/" target="_blank"&gt;pricing
                page&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
            <pubDate>Tue, 27 Jan 2026 17:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <category>marketing:marchitecture/databases,general:products/amazon-rds</category>
            <author>aws@amazon.com</author>
            <link>
                https://aws.amazon.com/about-aws/whats-new/2026/01/aws-product-generally-available-rds-r6id-r6gd-expansion</link>
        </item>
        <item>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">fdb388804a2d44d980e6e3b717b0e4bfeb69cd30</guid>
            <title>Amazon Connect now supports granular access controls for cases</title>
            <description>&lt;p&gt;Amazon Connect now enables you to apply tag-based access control
                to cases, giving administrators more control over who can view and manage case data.
                With this capability, you can associate tags with case templates and configure
                security profiles to control which users can access cases that include specific
                tags. For example, you can tag fraud-related cases and restrict access so that only
                users assigned to a fraud security profile can view or edit those cases, helping you
                enforce internal controls and data access policies.&lt;br&gt; &lt;br&gt; Amazon
                Connect Cases is available in the following AWS regions: US East (N. Virginia), US
                West (Oregon), Canada (Central), Europe (Frankfurt), Europe (London), Asia Pacific
                (Seoul), Asia Pacific (Singapore), Asia Pacific (Sydney), Asia Pacific (Tokyo), and
                Africa (Cape Town) AWS regions. To learn more and get started, visit the Amazon
                Connect Cases &lt;a href="https://aws.amazon.com/connect/cases/"
                target="_blank"&gt;webpage&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a
                href="https://docs.aws.amazon.com/connect/latest/adminguide/cases-tag-based-access-control.html"
                target="_blank"&gt;documentation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
            <pubDate>Tue, 27 Jan 2026 16:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <category>
                marketing:marchitecture/business-productivity,marketing:marchitecture/messaging,general:products/amazon-connect,marketing:marchitecture/contact-center</category>
            <author>aws@amazon.com</author>
            <link>
                https://aws.amazon.com/about-aws/whats-new/2026/01/amazon-connect-cases-granular-access-controls/</link>
        </item>
        <item>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">523acd98da3a6314e8cbc0c7a210df956d6f7f59</guid>
            <title>Amazon Lightsail expands blueprint selection with updated support for Node.js,
                LAMP, and Ruby on Rails blueprints</title>
            <description>&lt;p&gt;Amazon Lightsail now offers new Node.js, LAMP, and Ruby on Rails
                blueprints. These new blueprints have Instance Metadata Service Version 2 (IMDSv2)
                enforced by default. With just a few clicks, you can create a Lightsail virtual
                private server (VPS) of your preferred size with Node.js, LAMP, or Ruby on Rails
                preinstalled.&lt;br&gt; &lt;br&gt; With Lightsail, you can easily get started on the
                cloud by choosing a blueprint and an instance bundle to build your web application.
                Lightsail instance bundles include instances preinstalled with your preferred
                operating system, storage, and monthly data transfer allowance, giving you
                everything you need to get up and running quickly.&lt;br&gt; &lt;br&gt; These new
                blueprints are now available in all &lt;a
                href="https://docs.aws.amazon.com/en_us/lightsail/latest/userguide/understanding-regions-and-availability-zones-in-amazon-lightsail.html"&gt;AWS
                Regions where Lightsail is available&lt;/a&gt;. For more information on blueprints
                supported on Lightsail, see &lt;a
                href="https://lightsail.aws.amazon.com/ls/docs/en_us/articles/compare-options-choose-lightsail-instance-image"&gt;Lightsail
                documentation&lt;/a&gt;. For more information on pricing, or to get started with
                your free trial, &lt;a href="https://aws.amazon.com/lightsail/pricing/"&gt;click
                here.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
            <pubDate>Mon, 26 Jan 2026 22:45:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <category>marketing:marchitecture/compute,general:products/amazon-lightsail</category>
            <author>aws@amazon.com</author>
            <link>
                https://aws.amazon.com/about-aws/whats-new/2026/01/amazon-lightsail-nodejs-lamp-and-ruby-on-rails/</link>
        </item>
        <item>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">61c7a87af109ab66f8e1a46e5af117317ac517d1</guid>
            <title>Amazon Bedrock now supports 1-hour duration for prompt caching</title>
            <description>&lt;p&gt;Amazon Bedrock now supports a 1-hour time-to-live (TTL) option for
                prompt caching for select Anthropic Claude models. With this update, you can extend
                the persistence of cached prompt prefixes from the default 5 minutes to 1 hour,
                improving cost efficiency and performance for long-running agentic workflows and
                multi-turn conversations.&lt;br&gt; &lt;br&gt; Previously, cached content remained
                active for a fixed 5-minute window and refreshed when reused. With the new 1-hour
                TTL option, you can maintain context for users who interact less frequently, or for
                complex agents that require more time between steps—such as tool use, retrieval, and
                orchestration. The 1-hour TTL is also useful for longer sessions and batch
                processing where you want cached content to persist across extended
                periods.&lt;br&gt; &lt;br&gt; 1-hour TTL prompt caching is generally available for
                Anthropic’s Claude Sonnet 4.5, Claude Haiku 4.5, and Claude Opus 4.5 in all
                commercial &lt;a href="https://docs.aws.amazon.com/general/latest/gr/bedrock.html"
                target="_blank"&gt;AWS Regions&lt;/a&gt; and AWS GovCloud (US) Regions where these
                models are available. The 1-hour cache is billed at a different rate than the
                standard 5-minute cache. To learn more, refer to the &lt;a
                href="https://docs.aws.amazon.com/bedrock/latest/userguide/prompt-caching.html"
                target="_blank"&gt;Amazon Bedrock documentation&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a
                href="https://aws.amazon.com/bedrock/pricing/" target="_blank"&gt;Amazon Bedrock
                Pricing&lt;/a&gt; page.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
            <pubDate>Mon, 26 Jan 2026 22:30:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <category>
                general:products/amazon-bedrock,marketing:marchitecture/artificial-intelligence</category>
            <author>aws@amazon.com</author>
            <link>
                https://aws.amazon.com/about-aws/whats-new/2026/01/amazon-bedrock-one-hour-duration-prompt-caching/</link>
        </item>
        <item>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">843b33d4ec940f392839f6e3ebbb020279652be3</guid>
            <title>AWS IAM Identity Center now supports IPv6</title>
            <description>&lt;p&gt;AWS IAM Identity Center now supports Internet Protocol version 6
                (IPv6) through new dual-stack endpoints. Customers can now connect to AWS IAM
                Identity Center using IPv6, IPv4, or dual-stack clients. The existing AWS IAM
                Identity Center endpoints supporting IPv4 remain available for backward
                compatibility.&lt;br&gt; &lt;br&gt; IAM Identity Center allows customers to enable
                workforce access to AWS managed applications and AWS accounts. When your client,
                such as a browsers or an application, makes a request to a dual-stack endpoint, the
                endpoint resolves to an IPv4 or IPv6 address, depending on the protocol used by your
                network and client. This launch helps you meet IPv6 compliance requirements, and
                minimize the need for complex NAT infrastructure.&lt;br&gt; &lt;br&gt; IPv6 support
                is available in all &lt;a
                href="https://aws.amazon.com/about-aws/global-infrastructure/regional-product-services/"
                target="_blank"&gt;AWS Regions&lt;/a&gt; where IAM Identity Center is available,
                except the AWS GovCloud (US) Regions and the Taipei Region. To learn more, visit the
                &lt;a href="https://docs.aws.amazon.com/singlesignon/latest/userguide/what-is.html"
                target="_blank"&gt;IAM Identity Center User Guide&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
            <pubDate>Mon, 26 Jan 2026 18:02:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <category>marketing:marchitecture/management-tools</category>
            <author>aws@amazon.com</author>
            <link>
                https://aws.amazon.com/about-aws/whats-new/2026/01/iam-identity-center-ipv6-dualstack-support/</link>
        </item>
        <item>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">4fb5a131c3bde46e7748f41a7d9ba4621e7ab5b9</guid>
            <title>Amazon WorkSpaces Core announces monthly pricing for managed instances </title>
            <description>&lt;p&gt;AWS is announcing flexible billing for Amazon WorkSpaces Core
                managed instances, adding monthly flat-rate pricing alongside existing hourly
                billing. Customers can now choose the optimal pricing model based on their end user
                usage patterns. Monthly billing is ideal for predictable full-time desktops and
                hourly billing is ideal for variable usage patterns. Both options are pay-as-you-go
                with no long-term commitments.&lt;br&gt; &lt;br&gt; Amazon WorkSpaces Core managed
                instances simplifies virtual desktop infrastructure (VDI) migrations with highly
                customizable instance configurations. WorkSpaces Core managed instances provisions
                resources in your AWS account, handling infrastructure lifecycle management for both
                persistent and non-persistent workloads. Monthly pricing delivers savings vs hourly
                billing at always-on utilization, optimized for real-world VDI use cases.&lt;br&gt;
                &lt;br&gt; With flexible billing, customers benefit from predictable costs for
                persistent desktop workloads and the flexibility to mix hourly and monthly billing
                within the same deployment. VDI partners utilizing WorkSpaces Core managed instances
                including &lt;b&gt;Citrix&lt;/b&gt;, &lt;b&gt;Workspot&lt;/b&gt;,
                &lt;b&gt;Dizzion&lt;/b&gt;, and &lt;b&gt;Leostream&lt;/b&gt; can now integrate with
                new WorkSpaces API billing features to enable the monthly billing option when
                instances are created. Hourly billing remains the default billing option for managed
                instances.&lt;br&gt; &lt;br&gt; In addition, starting today, hourly utility rates
                for WorkSpaces Core managed instances will now be combined and billed by Amazon
                WorkSpaces to simplify pricing. Previously, hourly rates were split between Amazon
                EC2 and Amazon WorkSpaces on customer bills. There is no change to the effective
                rates for on-demand hourly usage of WorkSpaces Core Managed Instances with this
                announcement.&lt;br&gt; &lt;br&gt; To learn more about Amazon WorkSpaces Core
                managed instances flexible billing, visit the &lt;a
                href="https://aws.amazon.com/workspaces/vdi-partners/pricing/"&gt;WorkSpaces for VDI
                partners pricing page&lt;/a&gt;. For more information, see the &lt;a
                href="https://aws.amazon.com/workspaces/vdi-partners/"&gt;WorkSpaces for VDI
                partners product page&lt;/a&gt;. For technical documentation, see the &lt;a
                href="https://docs.aws.amazon.com/workspaces-core/"&gt;Amazon WorkSpaces Core
                Documentation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
            <pubDate>Mon, 26 Jan 2026 15:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <category />
            <author>aws@amazon.com</author>
            <link>
                https://aws.amazon.com/about-aws/whats-new/2026/1/amazon-workspaces-core-managed-instances-flexible-billing/</link>
        </item>
        <item>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">d06644b0479dd17f555e3024a1aa1bc4f98970f4</guid>
            <title>Amazon Managed Grafana now available in the AWS GovCloud (US) Regions</title>
            <description>&lt;p&gt;Amazon Managed Grafana is now available in both AWS GovCloud
                (US-West) and AWS GovCloud (US-East) Regions, enabling government customers and
                regulated industries to securely visualize and analyze their operational data while
                meeting stringent compliance requirements. Amazon Managed Grafana is a fully managed
                service based on open-source Grafana that makes it easier for you to visualize and
                analyze your operational data at scale.&lt;br&gt; &lt;br&gt; All Amazon Managed
                Grafana features are supported in AWS GovCloud (US) Regions except for Enterprise
                plugins. To get started with Amazon Managed Grafana, visit the &lt;a
                href="https://console.aws.amazon.com/grafana/home/" target="_blank"&gt;AWS
                Console&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a
                href="https://docs.aws.amazon.com/grafana/latest/userguide/what-is-Amazon-Managed-Service-Grafana.html"
                target="_blank"&gt;Amazon Managed Grafana user guide&lt;/a&gt;. To learn more about
                Amazon Managed Grafana, visit the &lt;a href="https://aws.amazon.com/grafana/"
                target="_blank"&gt;product page&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a
                href="https://aws.amazon.com/grafana/pricing/" target="_blank"&gt;pricing
                page&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
            <pubDate>Mon, 26 Jan 2026 15:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <category>
                general:products/aws-govcloud-us,general:products/amazon-managed-service-for-grafana</category>
            <author>aws@amazon.com</author>
            <link>
                https://aws.amazon.com/about-aws/whats-new/2026/01/amazon-managed-grafana-aws-govcloud-us-regions</link>
        </item>
        <item>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">e9c47fd3de92fc8c53e042c8c03fa9a8dc938174</guid>
            <title>AWS Transfer Family now supports Amazon FSx for NetApp ONTAP </title>
            <description>&lt;p&gt;AWS Transfer Family customers can now access file system data
                stored in Amazon FSx for NetApp ONTAP over SFTP, FTPS, and FTP.&amp;nbsp;&lt;br&gt;
                &lt;br&gt; AWS Transfer Family provides fully managed file transfers over SFTP, FTP,
                FTPS, AS2, and web browser-based interfaces. With this launch, you can now access
                FSx for ONTAP file systems over Transfer Family’s supported protocols through S3
                Access Points, while maintaining access via native file protocols (NFS/SMB). This
                allows you to maintain existing file system workflows while adding secure access via
                industry-standard protocols for external partners and internal users. Access is
                controlled through standard IAM policies and S3 Access Point configurations, helping
                you meet data security and compliance requirements.&lt;br&gt; &lt;br&gt; Transfer
                Family support for FSx for ONTAP is available in select&amp;nbsp;&lt;a
                href="https://docs.aws.amazon.com/fsx/latest/ONTAPGuide/accessing-data-via-s3-access-points.html#access-points-for-fsx-ontap-supported-regions"
                target="_blank"&gt;AWS Regions&lt;/a&gt;.&amp;nbsp;To get started, visit the AWS
                Transfer Family console, or use AWS CLI/SDK.&amp;nbsp;To learn more, visit the
                Transfer Family&amp;nbsp;&lt;a
                href="https://docs.aws.amazon.com/transfer/latest/userguide/fsx-s3-access-points.html"
                target="_blank"&gt;User Guide&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
            <pubDate>Mon, 26 Jan 2026 13:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <category>
                marketing:marchitecture/migration,general:products/aws-transfer-for-sftp,general:products/aws-transfer-family</category>
            <author>aws@amazon.com</author>
            <link>
                https://aws.amazon.com/about-aws/whats-new/2026/01/aws-transfer-family-amazon-fsx-netapp-ontap</link>
        </item>
        <item>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">7fbf46727ba1eeaa5fdbd95d04290d3f04f63c27</guid>
            <title>Amazon Route 53 Domains adds support for .ai, and other top-level domains</title>
            <description>&lt;p&gt;Amazon Route 53 Domains now supports registration and management
                of ten new top-level domains (TLDs): .ai, .nz, .shop, .bot, .moi, .spot, .free,
                .deal, .now, and .hot. This expansion enhances Route 53's capabilities as a domain
                registration and DNS management service, offering customers more options to
                establish their online presence. With these additions, businesses and individuals
                can now leverage domain names tailored to specific industries, regions, or purposes
                directly through Amazon Web Services (AWS).&lt;br&gt; &lt;br&gt; The new TLDs cater
                to various use cases. To name a few, the .ai domain, originally for Anguilla, has
                become popular among artificial intelligence companies. E-commerce sites can utilize
                .shop for their online storefronts. The .bot domain suits chatbot and AI-related
                services. The .now domain works well for time-sensitive services and instant
                delivery platforms. Users can register these domains through the Route 53 console,
                AWS CLI, or SDKs, enjoying integrated DNS management and automatic renewal features.
                This seamless integration allows for efficient domain administration alongside
                existing Route 53 hosted zones and DNS records.&lt;br&gt; &lt;br&gt; To learn more
                about Amazon Route 53 Domains and start registering new domains, visit the &lt;a
                href="https://aws.amazon.com/route53/"&gt;Amazon Route 53 page&lt;/a&gt;. Domain
                registration pricing varies by TLD. Visit the &lt;a
                href="http://aws.amazon.com/route53/pricing/"&gt;pricing page&lt;/a&gt; for detailed
                pricing information.&lt;/p&gt;
                &lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
            <pubDate>Fri, 23 Jan 2026 20:07:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <category>
                marketing:marchitecture/networking-and-content-delivery,general:products/amazon-route-53</category>
            <author>aws@amazon.com</author>
            <link>
                https://aws.amazon.com/about-aws/whats-new/2026/1/amazon-route-53-domains-adds-support-for-.ai-and-other-top-level-domains/</link>
        </item>
        <item>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">3ecec5a82e6cfae7e765635724ee22a77c398905</guid>
            <title>EC2 Auto Scaling Introduces New Mechanisms for Group Deletion Protection</title>
            <description>&lt;p&gt;EC2 Auto Scaling is introducing a new policy condition key &lt;a
                href="https://docs.aws.amazon.com/service-authorization/latest/reference/list_amazonec2autoscaling.html#amazonec2autoscaling-policy-keys"
                target="_blank"&gt;autoscaling:ForceDelete&lt;/a&gt;. This condition key is used
                with the DeleteAutoScalingGroup action to control whether the ForceDelete parameter
                can be used during deletion, which determines if an Auto Scaling group (ASG) can be
                deleted while it still contains running instances. You can use this condition key in
                IAM policies to restrict deletion permissions. This provides a safety measure to
                prevent accidental deletion of ASGs that still have running instances.&lt;br&gt;
                &lt;br&gt; Furthermore, EC2 Auto Scaling now offers deletion protection at the group
                level. The new deletion-protection configuration can be set either when you create
                your ASGs or update them. This new feature lets you set enhanced controls based on
                your workload's criticality, with multiple protection levels available to safeguard
                against accidental deletions and help maintain application availability.&lt;br&gt;
                &lt;br&gt; Combining the autoscaling:ForceDelete condition key with deletion
                protection at the group level provides a layered defense against unwanted ASG
                termination by allowing you to both restrict IAM permissions for force-delete
                operations and set enhanced protection controls directly on critical ASGs.&lt;br&gt;
                &lt;br&gt; The features now available in all &lt;a
                href="https://aws.amazon.com/about-aws/global-infrastructure/regional-product-services/"
                target="_blank"&gt;AWS Regions&lt;/a&gt; and AWS GovCloud (US) Regions. To get
                started, visit the EC2 Auto Scaling console or refer to our &lt;a
                href="https://docs.aws.amazon.com/autoscaling/ec2/userguide/resource-deletion-protection.html"
                target="_blank"&gt;technical documentation for deletion protection&lt;/a&gt; and
                &lt;a
                href="https://docs.aws.amazon.com/autoscaling/ec2/userguide/control-access-using-iam.html#policy-auto-scaling-condition-keys"
                target="_blank"&gt;policy condition keys&lt;/a&gt; for Amazon EC2 Auto
                Scaling.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
            <pubDate>Fri, 23 Jan 2026 19:09:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <category>
                marketing:marchitecture/compute,general:products/amazon-ec2,general:products/aws-govcloud-us</category>
            <author>aws@amazon.com</author>
            <link>
                https://aws.amazon.com/about-aws/whats-new/2026/01/ec2-auto-scaling-new-mechanisms-group-deletion-protection</link>
        </item>
        <item>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">9cd6f787e2f649455deef7a19426d8d110c4f293</guid>
            <title>Amazon EVS now supports multiple VMware NSX Edge Gateways</title>
            <description>&lt;p&gt;Today, we're announcing that Amazon Elastic VMware Service (Amazon
                EVS) now supports the ability to deploy multiple VMware NSX Tier-0 Gateways within
                VMware Software-Defined Data Centers (SDDC), enabling enhanced network segmentation
                and more flexible routing configurations.&lt;br&gt; &lt;br&gt; Multiple NSX Tier-0
                Gateways allow for better performance and scale by distributing network traffic
                across multiple NSX Edge Clusters. This latest enhancement enables improved network
                segmentation, allowing you to isolate different workload environments and maintain
                distinct security policies for each gateway. You can also use multiple gateways to
                create separate test environments for validating network configurations and
                performing gateway upgrades with minimal impact to production workloads. This
                architecture flexibility helps you align your network topology with specific
                business requirements while maintaining operational efficiency in running your
                VMware workloads on AWS with Amazon EVS.&amp;nbsp;&lt;br&gt; &lt;br&gt; To learn
                more about this newest enhancement, read this &lt;a
                href="https://repost.aws/articles/ARUttZpYUrSIKLLyaR3txGkA"
                target="_blank"&gt;re:Post article&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;that walks you through the
                process of deploying multiple NSX Edge Clusters within your EVS environment. To get
                started with Amazon EVS, visit the&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="https://aws.amazon.com/evs/"
                target="_blank"&gt;product detail page&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;and &lt;a
                href="https://docs.aws.amazon.com/evs/latest/userguide/what-is-evs.html"
                target="_blank"&gt;user guide&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
            <pubDate>Fri, 23 Jan 2026 17:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <category>marketing:marchitecture/migration,marketing:marchitecture/compute</category>
            <author>aws@amazon.com</author>
            <link>
                https://aws.amazon.com/about-aws/whats-new/2026/01/amazon-evs-multiple-vmware-nsx-edge-gateways</link>
        </item>
        <item>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">34d98ce085d92826a5760d2e3cd3093156350b4c</guid>
            <title>Announcing general availability of Amazon EC2 M4 Max Mac instances</title>
            <description>&lt;p&gt;Amazon Web Services announces general availability of Amazon EC2
                M4 Max Mac instances, powered by the latest Mac Studio hardware. Amazon EC2 M4 Max
                Mac instances are the next-generation EC2 Mac instances, that enable Apple
                developers to migrate their most demanding build and test workloads onto AWS. These
                instances are ideal for building and testing applications for Apple platforms such
                as iOS, macOS, iPadOS, tvOS, watchOS, visionOS, and Safari.&lt;br&gt; &lt;br&gt;
                Amazon EC2 M4 Max Mac instances offer up to 25% better application build performance
                compared to Amazon EC2 M1 Ultra Mac instances. M4 Max Mac instances are powered by
                the AWS Nitro System, providing up to 10 Gbps network bandwidth and 8 Gbps of Amazon
                Elastic Block Store (Amazon EBS) storage bandwidth. These instances are built on
                Apple M4 Max Mac Studio computers featuring a 16-core CPU, 40-core GPU, 16-core
                Neural Engine, and 128GB of unified memory.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
                &lt;p&gt;Amazon EC2 M4 Max Mac instances are available in US East (N. Virginia) and
                US West (Oregon).&amp;nbsp; To learn more about Amazon EC2 M4 Max Mac instances,
                visit the &lt;a href="https://aws.amazon.com/ec2/instance-types/mac/"&gt;Amazon EC2
                Mac page.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
            <pubDate>Fri, 23 Jan 2026 16:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <category>general:products/amazon-ec2,marketing:marchitecture/compute</category>
            <author>aws@amazon.com</author>
            <link>
                https://aws.amazon.com/about-aws/whats-new/2026/01/amazon-ec2-m4-max-mac-instances-ga</link>
        </item>
        <item>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">cce050ee51a2ef6ef8a7f858fd43a981adb13711</guid>
            <title>Amazon RDS for Oracle now supports replicas in Oracle multi-tenant configuration</title>
            <description>&lt;p&gt;Amazon RDS for Oracle now supports database replicas for instances
                set up in Oracle multi-tenant configuration. Oracle multi-tenant configuration
                allows customers to host multiple, isolated pluggable databases in a single
                container database, which allows for cost reduction through consolidation and easier
                management. With support for replicas in Oracle multi-tenant configuration,
                customers can now distribute read workloads to a replica to scale workloads, or
                setup cross-Region replicas. In disaster recovery situations, customers can promote
                replicas to serve as a new standalone database, or execute a switchover to reverse
                roles between the primary database and the replica for a quick recovery.&lt;/p&gt;
                &lt;p&gt;To set up replicas in Oracle multi-tenant configuration, customers can
                create a replica in either mounted or read-only mode using the AWS management
                console, AWS CLI, or AWS SDK. Once a replica is set up, Amazon RDS for Oracle
                manages asynchronous physical replication between primary and replica database
                instances using Oracle Data Guard.&lt;/p&gt;
                &lt;p&gt;Amazon RDS for Oracle read replicas use Oracle Data Guard. Using mounted
                mode replicas require an Oracle Database Enterprise Edition (EE) license, and using
                read-only mode replicas require additional Oracle Active Data Guard licenses. We
                recommend customers to consult their Oracle licensing expert to determine Oracle
                licensing requirements. Refer to &lt;a
                href="https://docs.aws.amazon.com/AmazonRDS/latest/UserGuide/oracle-read-replicas.overview.html#oracle-read-replicas.overview.data-guard"&gt;RDS
                for Oracle User Guide&lt;/a&gt; for more information, and &lt;a
                href="https://aws.amazon.com/rds/oracle/pricing/"&gt;Amazon RDS for Oracle
                pricing&lt;/a&gt; for available instance configurations, pricing, and region
                availability.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
            <pubDate>Fri, 23 Jan 2026 16:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <category>marketing:marchitecture/databases</category>
            <author>aws@amazon.com</author>
            <link>
                https://aws.amazon.com/about-aws/whats-new/2026/01/amazon-rds-for-oracle-replica-multi-tenant-configuration-support</link>
        </item>
        <item>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">e895d668e9b7ee9b6788c25cf0999d7c24761f47</guid>
            <title>Amazon Connect adds conditional logic and real-time updates to Step-by-Step
                Guides</title>
            <description>&lt;p&gt;Amazon Connect Step-by-Step Guides now enables managers to build
                more dynamic and responsive guided experiences. Managers can create conditional user
                interfaces that adapt based on user interactions, making workflows more efficient.
                For example, managers can configure dropdown menus to show or hide fields, change
                default values, or adjust required fields based on the input in prior fields,
                creating tailored experiences for different scenarios.&lt;br&gt; &lt;br&gt; In
                addition, Step-by-Step Guides can now automatically refresh data from Connect
                resources such as flow modules at specified intervals, ensuring agents always work
                with the most current information.&lt;br&gt; &lt;br&gt; Amazon Connect Step-by-Step
                Guides is available in the following &lt;a
                href="https://aws.amazon.com/about-aws/global-infrastructure/regional-product-services/"
                target="_blank"&gt;AWS regions&lt;/a&gt;: US East (N. Virginia), US West (Oregon),
                Canada (Central), Africa (Cape Town), Asia Pacific (Seoul), Asia Pacific
                (Singapore), Asia Pacific (Sydney), Asia Pacific (Tokyo), Europe (Frankfurt), Europe
                (London), and the AWS GovCloud (US-West) Region. To learn more and get started,
                visit the Amazon Connect &lt;a
                href="https://aws.amazon.com/connect/agent-workspace/"
                target="_blank"&gt;webpage&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a
                href="https://docs.aws.amazon.com/connect/latest/adminguide/agent-workspace.html"
                target="_blank"&gt;documentation.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
            <pubDate>Fri, 23 Jan 2026 13:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <category>general:products/amazon-connect,marketing:marchitecture/contact-center</category>
            <author>aws@amazon.com</author>
            <link>
                https://aws.amazon.com/about-aws/whats-new/2026/01/amazon-connect-conditional-logic-real-time-updates-step-by-step-guides/</link>
        </item>
        <item>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">16f4da2ceccc71933ebb21d1c90c9831f9c027f6</guid>
            <title>Amazon EC2 C8i instances are now available in AWS Europe (London) region</title>
            <description>&lt;p&gt;Starting today, Amazon Elastic Compute Cloud (Amazon EC2) C8i
                instances are available in the Europe (London) region. These instances are powered
                by custom Intel Xeon 6 processors, available only on AWS, delivering the highest
                performance and fastest memory bandwidth among comparable Intel processors in the
                cloud. These C8i instances offer up to 15% better price-performance, and 2.5x more
                memory bandwidth compared to previous generation Intel-based instances. They deliver
                up to 20% higher performance than C7i instances, with even higher gains for specific
                workloads. The C8i are up to 60% faster for NGINX web applications, up to 40% faster
                for AI deep learning recommendation models, and 35% faster for Memcached stores
                compared to C7i.&lt;br&gt; &lt;br&gt; &lt;br&gt; C8i instances are a great choice
                for all memory-intensive workloads, especially for workloads that need the largest
                instance sizes or continuous high CPU usage. C8i instances offer 13 sizes including
                2 bare metal sizes and the new 96xlarge size for the largest applications.&lt;br&gt;
                &lt;br&gt; To get started, sign in to the &lt;a
                href="https://aws.amazon.com/console/" target="_blank"&gt;AWS Management
                Console&lt;/a&gt;. Customers can purchase these instances via Savings Plans,
                On-Demand instances, and Spot instances. For more information about the new &lt;a
                href="https://aws.amazon.com/ec2/instance-types/c8i/"
                target="_blank"&gt;C8i&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;instances visit the &lt;a
                href="https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/aws/introducing-new-compute-optimized-amazon-ec2-c8i-and-c8i-flex-instances/"
                target="_blank"&gt;AWS News blog&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
            <pubDate>Thu, 22 Jan 2026 20:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <category>marketing:marchitecture/compute,general:products/amazon-ec2</category>
            <author>aws@amazon.com</author>
            <link>
                https://aws.amazon.com/about-aws/whats-new/2026/01/amazon-ec2-c8i-instances-europe-london-region</link>
        </item>
        <item>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">4330ea079d6ea6b574be5e26fbade42af18b8216</guid>
            <title>Amazon EC2 C8i and C8i-flex instances are now available in Asia Pacific (Sydney)
                and Europe (Frankfurt) regions</title>
            <description>&lt;p&gt;Starting today, Amazon Elastic Compute Cloud (Amazon EC2) C8i and
                C8i-flex instances are available in the Asia Pacific (Sydney), and Europe
                (Frankfurt) regions. These instances are powered by custom Intel Xeon 6 processors,
                available only on AWS, delivering the highest performance and fastest memory
                bandwidth among comparable Intel processors in the cloud. These C8i and C8i-flex
                instances offer up to 15% better price-performance, and 2.5x more memory bandwidth
                compared to previous generation Intel-based instances. They deliver up to 20% higher
                performance than C7i and C7i-flex instances, with even higher gains for specific
                workloads. The C8i and C8i-flex are up to 60% faster for NGINX web applications, up
                to 40% faster for AI deep learning recommendation models, and 35% faster for
                Memcached stores compared to C7i and C7i-flex.&lt;br&gt; &lt;br&gt; C8i-flex are the
                easiest way to get price performance benefits for a majority of compute intensive
                workloads like web and application servers, databases, caches, Apache Kafka,
                Elasticsearch, and enterprise applications. They offer the most common sizes, from
                large to 16xlarge, and are a great first choice for applications that don't fully
                utilize all compute resources.&lt;br&gt; &lt;br&gt; C8i instances are a great choice
                for all memory-intensive workloads, especially for workloads that need the largest
                instance sizes or continuous high CPU usage. C8i instances offer 13 sizes including
                2 bare metal sizes and the new 96xlarge size for the largest applications.&lt;br&gt;
                &lt;br&gt; To get started, sign in to the &lt;a
                href="https://aws.amazon.com/console/" target="_blank"&gt;AWS Management
                Console&lt;/a&gt;. Customers can purchase these instances via Savings Plans,
                On-Demand instances, and Spot instances. For more information about the new &lt;a
                href="https://aws.amazon.com/ec2/instance-types/c8i/" target="_blank"&gt;C8i and
                C8i-flex&lt;/a&gt; instances visit the &lt;a
                href="https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/aws/introducing-new-compute-optimized-amazon-ec2-c8i-and-c8i-flex-instances/"
                target="_blank"&gt;AWS News blog&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
            <pubDate>Thu, 22 Jan 2026 20:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <category>general:products/amazon-ec2,marketing:marchitecture/compute</category>
            <author>aws@amazon.com</author>
            <link>
                https://aws.amazon.com/about-aws/whats-new/2026/01/amazon-ec2-c8i-c8i-flex-instances-asia-pacific-sydney-europe-london-regions</link>
        </item>
        <item>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">bdf655cb1f543c8101b613cbb7c84d4207ae9477</guid>
            <title>AWS Config launches 13 new managed rules</title>
            <description>&lt;p&gt;AWS Config announces launch of an additional 13 managed Config
                rules for various use cases such as security, durability, and operations. You can
                now search, discover, enable and manage these additional rules directly from AWS
                Config and govern more use cases for your AWS environment.&lt;br&gt; &lt;br&gt; With
                this launch, you can now enable these controls across your account or across your
                organization. For example, you can assess your security posture across Amazon
                Cognito User pools, Amazon EBS Snapshots, AWS Cloudformation Stacks and more.
                Additionally, you can leverage Conformance Packs to group these new controls and
                deploy across an account or across organization, streamlining your multi-account
                governance.&lt;br&gt; &lt;br&gt; For the full list of recently released rules, visit
                the&amp;nbsp;&lt;a
                href="https://docs.aws.amazon.com/config/latest/developerguide/DocumentHistory.html"&gt;AWS
                Config developer guide&lt;/a&gt;. For description of each rule and the AWS Regions
                in which it is available, please refer our&amp;nbsp;&lt;a
                href="https://docs.aws.amazon.com/config/latest/developerguide/managed-rules-by-aws-config.html"&gt;Config
                managed rules documentation&lt;/a&gt;. To start using Config rules, please refer
                our&amp;nbsp;&lt;a
                href="https://docs.aws.amazon.com/config/latest/developerguide/evaluate-config_add-rules.html"&gt;documentation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;br&gt;
                &lt;br&gt; New Rules Launched:&lt;br&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
                &lt;ol&gt;
                &lt;li&gt;AURORA_GLOBAL_DATABASE_ENCRYPTION_AT_REST&lt;/li&gt;
                &lt;li&gt;CLOUDFORMATION_STACK_SERVICE_ROLE_CHECK&lt;/li&gt;
                &lt;li&gt;CLOUDFORMATION_TERMINATION_PROTECTION_CHECK&lt;/li&gt;
                &lt;li&gt;CLOUDFRONT_DISTRIBUTION_KEY_GROUP_ENABLED&lt;/li&gt;
                &lt;li&gt;COGNITO_USER_POOL_DELETE_PROTECTION_ENABLED&lt;/li&gt;
                &lt;li&gt;COGNITO_USER_POOL_MFA_ENABLED&lt;/li&gt;
                &lt;li&gt;COGNITO_USERPOOL_CUST_AUTH_THREAT_FULL_CHECK&lt;/li&gt;
                &lt;li&gt;EBS_SNAPSHOT_BLOCK_PUBLIC_ACCESS&lt;/li&gt;
                &lt;li&gt;ECS_CAPACITY_PROVIDER_TERMINATION_CHECK&lt;/li&gt;
                &lt;li&gt;ECS_TASK_DEFINITION_EFS_ENCRYPTION_ENABLED&lt;/li&gt;
                &lt;li&gt;ECS_TASK_DEFINITION_LINUX_USER_NON_ROOT&lt;/li&gt;
                &lt;li&gt;ECS_TASK_DEFINITION_WINDOWS_USER_NON_ADMIN&lt;/li&gt;
                &lt;li&gt;SES_SENDING_TLS_REQUIRED&lt;/li&gt;
                &lt;/ol&gt;</description>
            <pubDate>Thu, 22 Jan 2026 18:06:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <category>
                general:products/aws-config,general:products/aws-govcloud-us,marketing:marchitecture/management-and-governance</category>
            <author>aws@amazon.com</author>
            <link>https://aws.amazon.com/about-aws/whats-new/2026/01/aws-config-launches-new-rules/</link>
        </item>
        <item>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">41e7afe66ec38d5ce932d0c77b2d035098d60cda</guid>
            <title>Amazon Neptune Analytics is now available in 7 additional regions</title>
            <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a
                href="https://docs.aws.amazon.com/neptune-analytics/latest/userguide/what-is-neptune-analytics.html"
                target="_blank"&gt;Amazon Neptune Analytics&lt;/a&gt; is now available in US West
                (N. California), Asia Pacific (Seoul), Asia Pacific (Osaka), Asia Pacific (Hong
                Kong), Europe (Stockholm), Europe (Paris), and South America (São Paulo) regions.
                You can now create and manage Neptune Analytics graphs in these new regions and run
                advanced graph analytics.&lt;br&gt; &lt;br&gt; Amazon Neptune is a serverless graph
                database for connected data, improves the accuracy of AI applications, and lowers
                operational burden and costs. Neptune instantly scales graph workloads removing the
                need to manage capacity. By modeling data as a graph, Neptune captures context that
                improves accuracy and explainability of generative AI applications. To make AI
                application development easier, Neptune offers fully managed GraphRAG with Amazon
                Bedrock Knowledge Bases, and integrations with Strands AI Agents SDK and popular
                agentic memory tools. It also easily analyzes tens of billions of relationships
                across structured and unstructured data within seconds delivering strategic
                insights. Neptune is the only database and analytics engine that gives you the power
                of connected data with the enterprise capabilities and value of AWS.&lt;br&gt;
                &lt;br&gt; To get started, you can create a new Neptune Analytics graphs using the
                &lt;a
                href="https://ap-south-1.console.aws.amazon.com/neptune/home?region=ap-south-1#analytics-graphs:"
                target="_blank"&gt;AWS Management Console&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a
                href="https://docs.aws.amazon.com/cli/latest/reference/neptune-graph/"
                target="_blank"&gt;or AWS CLI&lt;/a&gt;. For more information on pricing and region
                availability, refer to the &lt;a href="https://aws.amazon.com/neptune/pricing/"
                target="_blank"&gt;Neptune pricing page&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a
                href="https://aws.amazon.com/about-aws/global-infrastructure/regional-product-services/"
                target="_blank"&gt;AWS Region Table&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
            <pubDate>Thu, 22 Jan 2026 18:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <category>
                marketing:marchitecture/analytics,general:products/amazon-neptune,marketing:marchitecture/databases</category>
            <author>aws@amazon.com</author>
            <link>
                https://aws.amazon.com/about-aws/whats-new/2026/01/amazon-neptune-analytics-generally-available-additional-regions</link>
        </item>
        <item>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">f39d9be8d60d40d5c53111cbee372ed2c72f992f</guid>
            <title>Amazon Bedrock AgentCore Browser now supports custom browser extensions</title>
            <description>&lt;p&gt;Amazon Bedrock AgentCore Browser now supports custom Chrome
                browser extensions, enabling automation for complex workflows that standard browser
                automation cannot handle alone. This enhancement builds upon AgentCore’s existing
                secure browser features, allowing users to upload Chrome-compatible extensions to S3
                and automatically install them during browser sessions. The feature serves
                enterprise developers, automation engineers, and organizations&amp;nbsp;across
                industries requiring specialized browser functionality within a secure
                environment.&lt;/p&gt;
                &lt;p&gt;This new feature&amp;nbsp;enables powerful use cases including custom
                authentication flows, automated testing, and improved web navigation with
                performance optimization through ad blocking. Organizations gain the ability to
                integrate third-party tools that operate as browser extensions, eliminating manual
                processes while maintaining security within the AgentCore Browser
                environment.&lt;br&gt; &lt;br&gt; This feature is available in all nine &lt;a
                href="https://docs.aws.amazon.com/bedrock-agentcore/latest/devguide/agentcore-regions.html"
                target="_blank"&gt;AWS Regions&lt;/a&gt; where Amazon Bedrock AgentCore Browser is
                available: US East (N. Virginia), US East (Ohio), US West (Oregon), Asia Pacific
                (Mumbai), Asia Pacific (Singapore), Asia Pacific (Sydney), Asia Pacific (Tokyo),
                Europe (Frankfurt), and Europe (Ireland).&lt;br&gt; &lt;br&gt; To learn more about
                implementing custom browser extensions in Amazon Bedrock AgentCore, visit the&lt;a
                href="https://docs.aws.amazon.com/bedrock-agentcore/latest/devguide/browser-extensions.html"
                target="_blank"&gt; Browser documentation.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
            <pubDate>Thu, 22 Jan 2026 17:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <category>
                general:products/amazon-bedrock,marketing:marchitecture/artificial-intelligence</category>
            <author>aws@amazon.com</author>
            <link>
                https://aws.amazon.com/about-aws/whats-new/2026/01/amazon-bedrock-agentcore-browser-custom-extensions</link>
        </item>
        <item>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">8d5697851b02a36771a9f4b773215c8089d8cab5</guid>
            <title>AWS expands Resource Control Policies support for Cognito and CloudWatch Logs </title>
            <description>&lt;p&gt;AWS Resource Control Policies (RCPs) now provide support for &lt;a
                href="https://aws.amazon.com/pm/cognito/?trk=de90528c-2450-48d7-9981-bc556d44c9ab&amp;amp;sc_channel=ps&amp;amp;trk=de90528c-2450-48d7-9981-bc556d44c9ab&amp;amp;sc_channel=ps&amp;amp;ef_id=EAIaIQobChMI1oPdpd-JkgMVEh-tBh0iWzpHEAAYASAAEgLl7_D_BwE:G:s&amp;amp;s_kwcid=AL!4422!3!652240143559!e!!g!!cognito!19878797452!155825919588&amp;amp;gad_campaignid=19878797452&amp;amp;gbraid=0AAAAADjHtp-6asfTXR8BCPoEoERBRak--&amp;amp;gclid=EAIaIQobChMI1oPdpd-JkgMVEh-tBh0iWzpHEAAYASAAEgLl7_D_BwE"
                target="_blank"&gt;Amazon Cognito&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a
                href="https://aws.amazon.com/cloudwatch/?refid=de90528c-2450-48d7-9981-bc556d44c9ab"
                target="_blank"&gt;Amazon CloudWatch Logs&lt;/a&gt;. Resource&lt;u&gt;
                &lt;/u&gt;control policies (RCPs) are a type of organization policy that you can use
                to manage permissions in your organization. RCPs offer central control over the
                maximum available permissions for resources in your organization.&lt;br&gt;
                &lt;br&gt; With this expansion, you can now use RCPs to manage permissions for
                Amazon Cognito and Amazon CloudWatch Logs resources. For example, you can create
                policies that prevent identities outside your organization from accessing these
                resources, helping you build a &lt;a
                href="https://aws.amazon.com/identity/data-perimeters-on-aws/"
                target="_blank"&gt;data perimeter&lt;/a&gt; and enforce baseline security standards
                across your AWS environment.&lt;br&gt; &lt;br&gt; RCPs are available in all AWS
                commercial Regions and AWS GovCloud (US) Regions. To learn more about RCPs and view
                the full list of supported AWS services, visit the &lt;a
                href="https://docs.aws.amazon.com/organizations/latest/userguide/orgs_manage_policies_rcps.html"
                target="_blank"&gt;Resource control policies (RCPs) documentation&lt;/a&gt; in the
                AWS Organizations User Guide.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
            <pubDate>Thu, 22 Jan 2026 17:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <category>
                general:products/amazon-cognito,general:products/amazon-cloudwatch-logs,general:products/aws-govcloud-us,marketing:marchitecture/security-identity-and-compliance</category>
            <author>aws@amazon.com</author>
            <link>
                https://aws.amazon.com/about-aws/whats-new/2026/01/aws-expands-resource-control-policies</link>
        </item>
        <item>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">32fe7128f0f1fb25c654da4c5ccf821ba9acf267</guid>
            <title>Microsoft Office, Visio and Project 2024 Apps now on Amazon WorkSpaces</title>
            <description>&lt;p&gt;Today,&amp;nbsp;Amazon WorkSpaces Personal&amp;nbsp;and Core
                announce the availability of new Microsoft productivity applications for WorkSpaces
                instances, including Microsoft Office LTSC Professional Plus 2024, Microsoft Office
                LTSC Standard 2024, Microsoft Visio LTSC Professional 2024, Microsoft Visio LTSC
                Standard 2024, Microsoft Project Professional 2024 and Microsoft Project Standard
                2024.&lt;br&gt; &lt;br&gt; Microsoft&amp;nbsp;Office 2024, Visio 2024 and Project
                2024 applications are now part of Amazon WorkSpaces’ managed applications catalog
                and&amp;nbsp;can be added to eligible&amp;nbsp;new or existing WorkSpaces using your
                existing Manage application workflow. This helps you standardize on a modern,
                secure, productivity-focused desktop experience without changing your current
                bundles.&lt;/p&gt;
                &lt;p&gt;These applications are available in all AWS Regions that support Amazon
                WorkSpaces Personal and Core. You will be charged the applications you choose for
                your WorkSpaces instances. For more details on pricing, refer to &lt;a
                href="https://aws.amazon.com/workspaces/desktop-as-a-service/pricing/"
                target="_blank"&gt;Amazon WorkSpaces Pricing&lt;/a&gt;. To get started, refer to
                &lt;a
                href="https://docs.aws.amazon.com/workspaces/latest/adminguide/administer-workspaces.html"
                target="_blank"&gt;Administer your WorkSpaces&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a
                href="https://docs.aws.amazon.com/workspaces/latest/adminguide/manage-applications.html"
                target="_blank"&gt;Manage applications&lt;/a&gt; for Amazon WorkSpaces.&lt;/p&gt;
                &lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
                &lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
                &lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
                &lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
                &lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
            <pubDate>Thu, 22 Jan 2026 16:54:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <category>
                marketing:marchitecture/management-tools,marketing:marchitecture/developer-tools,general:products/amazon-workspaces,marketing:marchitecture/applications</category>
            <author>aws@amazon.com</author>
            <link>
                https://aws.amazon.com/about-aws/whats-new/2026/01/microsoft-office-visio-project-2024-amazon-workspaces/</link>
        </item>
        <item>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">12003829a967844acb97e6516f31108b5ea175b1</guid>
            <title>Now available: 48xlarge and metal-48xl sizes for EBS optimized Amazon EC2
                instances</title>
            <description>&lt;p&gt;Today, AWS announces the general availability of the Amazon
                Elastic Block Storage (Amazon EBS) optimized Amazon Elastic Compute Cloud (Amazon
                EC2) C8gb, M8gb, and R8gb instances in 48xlarge sizes. We are also offering C8gb and
                R8gb in metal-48xl sizes. These instances are powered by AWS Graviton4 processors to
                deliver up to 30% better compute performance than AWS Graviton3 processors. At up to
                300 Gbps of EBS bandwidth, these instances offer the highest EBS performance among
                non-accelerated compute EC2 instances. Take advantage of the higher block storage
                performance offered by these new EBS optimized EC2 instances to scale the
                performance and throughput of a wide variety of workloads.&lt;/p&gt;
                &lt;p&gt;For increased scalability, these instances offer sizes up to 48xlarge,
                including two metal sizes (C8gb and R8gb only), 3 varieties of memory to vCPUs
                ratios, up to 300 Gbps of EBS bandwidth, up to 400 Gbps of networking bandwidth.
                Offering up to 1440K IOPS, these instances have the highest Amazon EBS IOPS
                performance in Amazon EC2. These new instances support Elastic Fabric Adapter (EFA)
                networking, which enables lower latency and improved cluster performance for
                workloads deployed on tightly coupled clusters.&lt;/p&gt;
                &lt;p&gt;The new instance sizes are available in US East (N. Virginia) and US West
                (Oregon) regions. Metal sizes are only available in US East (N. Virginia)
                region.&lt;/p&gt;
                &lt;p&gt;To learn more, see Amazon &lt;a
                href="https://aws.amazon.com/ec2/instance-types/c8g/"&gt;C8gb&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a
                href="https://aws.amazon.com/ec2/instance-types/m8g/"&gt;M8gb&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a
                href="https://aws.amazon.com/ec2/instance-types/r8g"&gt;R8gb&lt;/a&gt; Instances. To
                begin your Graviton journey, visit the &lt;a
                href="https://aws.amazon.com/ec2/graviton/level-up-with-graviton/"&gt;Level up your
                compute with AWS Graviton page&lt;/a&gt;. To get started, see &lt;a
                href="https://console.aws.amazon.com/"&gt;AWS Management Console&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a
                href="https://aws.amazon.com/cli/"&gt;AWS Command Line Interface (AWS
                CLI)&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a
                href="https://docs.aws.amazon.com/AWSJavaScriptSDK/latest/AWS/EC2.html"&gt;AWS
                SDKs&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
            <pubDate>Thu, 22 Jan 2026 16:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <category>general:products/amazon-ec2,marketing:marchitecture/compute</category>
            <author>aws@amazon.com</author>
            <link>
                https://aws.amazon.com/about-aws/whats-new/2026/01/graviton4-ebs-optimized-larger-sizes</link>
        </item>
        <item>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">6790c4595f541d6ad5c227253e4d3d7beb5a26ed</guid>
            <title>Announcing availability of AWS Outposts racks in Rwanda</title>
            <description>&lt;p&gt;AWS Outposts racks can now be shipped and installed at your data
                center and on-premises locations in Rwanda.&lt;br&gt; &lt;br&gt; AWS Outposts racks
                extend AWS infrastructure, AWS services, APIs, and tools to virtually any
                on-premises data center or colocation space for a truly consistent hybrid
                experience. Outposts racks allow customers to run workloads that need low latency
                access to on-premises systems locally while connecting back to a home Region for
                application management. Customers can also use Outposts racks to manage and process
                data that needs to remain on-premises to meet data residency requirements.&lt;br&gt;
                &lt;br&gt; To learn more about Outposts racks, read the &lt;a
                href="https://aws.amazon.com/outposts/rack/" target="_blank"&gt;product
                overview&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://docs.aws.amazon.com/outposts/index.html"
                target="_blank"&gt;user guide&lt;/a&gt;. For the most updated list of countries and
                territories and the AWS Regions where Outposts racks are supported, check out the
                &lt;a href="https://aws.amazon.com/outposts/rack/faqs/"
                target="_blank"&gt;&lt;u&gt;Outposts rack FAQs page&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
            <pubDate>Thu, 22 Jan 2026 16:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <category>marketing:marchitecture/compute,general:products/aws-outposts</category>
            <author>aws@amazon.com</author>
            <link>
                https://aws.amazon.comabout-aws/whats-new/2026/01/availability-aws-outposts-racks-rwanda</link>
        </item>
        <item>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">d0f9330d9b3296931f18f8b84c34a8fbb44783ca</guid>
            <title>Amazon MQ now supports Java Messaging Service (JMS) specification for RabbitMQ
                brokers</title>
            <description>&lt;p&gt;Amazon MQ now supports the ability for RabbitMQ 4 brokers to
                connect to JMS applications through the RabbitMQ JMS Topic Exchange plugin and &lt;a
                href="https://www.rabbitmq.com/client-libraries/jms-client" target="_blank"&gt;JMS
                client&lt;/a&gt;. The JMS topic exchange plugin is enabled by default on all
                RabbitMQ 4 brokers, allowing you to use the JMS client to run your JMS 1.1, JMS 2.0,
                and JMS 3.1 applications on RabbitMQ. You can also use the RabbitMQ JMS client to
                send JMS messages to an AMQP exchange and consume messages from an AMQP queue to
                interoperate or migrate JMS workloads to AMQP workloads.&lt;br&gt; &lt;br&gt; To
                start using your JMS applications on RabbitMQ, simply select RabbitMQ 4.2 when
                creating a new broker using the M7g instance type through the AWS Management
                console, AWS CLI, or AWS SDKs, and then use the RabbitMQ JMS client to connect your
                applications. To learn more about the plugin, see the &lt;a
                href="https://docs.aws.amazon.com/amazon-mq/latest/developer-guide/amazon-mq-release-notes.html"
                target="_blank"&gt;Amazon MQ release notes&lt;/a&gt; and the Amazon MQ &lt;a
                href="https://docs.aws.amazon.com/amazon-mq/latest/developer-guide/working-with-rabbitmq.html"
                target="_blank"&gt;developer guide&lt;/a&gt;. This plugin is available in all &lt;a
                href="https://aws.amazon.com/about-aws/global-infrastructure/regional-product-services/"
                target="_blank"&gt;regions&lt;/a&gt; where Amazon MQ RabbitMQ 4 instances are
                available today.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
            <pubDate>Thu, 22 Jan 2026 13:40:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <category>
                marketing:marchitecture/messaging,general:products/amazon-mq,marketing:marchitecture/analytics,marketing:marchitecture/developer-tools</category>
            <author>aws@amazon.com</author>
            <link>https://aws.amazon.com/about-aws/whats-new/2026/01/amazon-mq-jms-spec-rabbitmq/</link>
        </item>
        <item>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">06722f4397a93405a28e82d29e0738fcf8ce9274</guid>
            <title>AWS Security Agent now supports GitHub Enterprise Cloud</title>
            <description>&lt;p&gt;AWS Security Agent now supports GitHub Enterprise Cloud, enabling
                customers to connect their GitHub Enterprise Organization and leverage AI-powered
                security capabilities across their private repositories. With this expansion,
                development teams can integrate security analysis directly into their GitHub
                workflows.&lt;br&gt; &lt;br&gt; Customers can now connect their GitHub Enterprise
                Organization to AWS Security Agent by installing the AWS Security Agent GitHub app
                with the required permissions. Once connected, the agent provides three key
                capabilities for private repositories:&lt;/p&gt;
                &lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Automated Code Reviews&lt;/b&gt;: AWS Security Agent performs
                comprehensive security reviews on new pull requests, identifying vulnerabilities and
                compliance with internal security requirements before code is merged.&lt;/p&gt;
                &lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Penetration Testing Integration&lt;/b&gt;: Leverage your GitHub
                Enterprise code repositories during penetration testing activities, allowing the
                agent to analyze your codebase for potential security weaknesses and attack
                vectors.&lt;/p&gt;
                &lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Automated Code Remediation&lt;/b&gt;: When security issues are
                identified during penetration testing, customers can choose to have AWS Security
                Agent automatically submit pull requests with recommended fixes, accelerating
                remediation workflows.&lt;/p&gt;
                &lt;p&gt;This capability is available in the US East (N. Virginia) region where AWS
                Security Agent operates. To get started, connect your GitHub Enterprise Organization
                to AWS Security Agent through the &lt;a
                href="https://console.aws.amazon.com/security-agent"&gt;AWS Security Agent
                console&lt;/a&gt;.&amp;nbsp;To learn more about AWS Security Agent, visit
                the&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="https://aws.amazon.com/security-agent"&gt;product
                page&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;br&gt; &lt;br&gt; &lt;/p&gt;</description>
            <pubDate>Thu, 22 Jan 2026 09:01:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <category>marketing:marchitecture/security-identity-and-compliance</category>
            <author>aws@amazon.com</author>
            <link>https://aws.amazon.com/about-aws/whats-new/2026/01/aws-security-agent-ghe-support</link>
        </item>
        <item>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">b56fa6f0685f8e88567c15fea9fdcce4574590cc</guid>
            <title>Amazon SageMaker HyperPod introduces enhanced lifecycle scripts debugging</title>
            <description>&lt;p&gt;Amazon SageMaker HyperPod now provides enhanced troubleshooting
                capabilities for lifecycle scripts, making it easier to identify and resolve issues
                during cluster node provisioning. SageMaker HyperPod helps you provision resilient
                clusters for running AI/ML workloads and developing state-of-the-art models such as
                large language models (LLMs), diffusion models, and foundation models
                (FMs).&lt;br&gt; &lt;br&gt; When lifecycle scripts encounter issues during cluster
                creation or node operations, you now receive detailed error messages that include
                the specific CloudWatch log group and log stream names where you can find execution
                logs for lifecycle scripts. You can view these error messages by running the
                DescribeCluster API or by viewing the cluster details page in the SageMaker console.
                The console also provides a "View lifecycle script logs"&amp;nbsp;button that
                navigates directly to the relevant CloudWatch log stream, making it easier to locate
                logs. Additionally, CloudWatch logs for lifecycle scripts now include specific
                markers to help you track lifecycle script execution progress, including indicators
                for when the lifecycle script log begins, when scripts are being downloaded, when
                downloads complete, and when scripts succeed or fail. These markers help you quickly
                identify where issues occurred during the provisioning process. These enhancements
                reduce the time required to diagnose and fix lifecycle script failures, helping you
                get your HyperPod clusters up and running faster.&lt;br&gt; &lt;br&gt; This feature
                is available in all AWS Regions where Amazon SageMaker HyperPod is supported. To
                learn more, see&amp;nbsp;&lt;a
                href="https://docs.aws.amazon.com/sagemaker/latest/dg/sagemaker-hyperpod-cluster-management-slurm.html"
                target="_blank"&gt;SageMaker HyperPod cluster management&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;in the
                Amazon SageMaker Developer Guide.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
            <pubDate>Wed, 21 Jan 2026 19:15:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <category>
                marketing:marchitecture/compute,general:products/amazon-sagemaker,marketing:marchitecture/artificial-intelligence</category>
            <author>aws@amazon.com</author>
            <link>
                https://aws.amazon.com/about-aws/whats-new/2026/01/amazon-sagemaker-hyperpod-lcs-enhanced-debug/</link>
        </item>
        <item>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">4eff3f6b9dd3dabbd9ae42a28fca8e95ee0f7ca5</guid>
            <title>AWS Clean Rooms adds support for join and partition hints in SQL</title>
            <description>&lt;p&gt;AWS Clean Rooms announces support for join and partition hints for
                SQL queries, enabling optimization of join strategies and data partitioning for
                improved query performance and reduced costs. This launch enables you to apply SQL
                hints to your queries using comment-style syntax in pre-approved analysis templates
                as well as ad hoc SQL queries. You can now optimize large table joins using a
                broadcast join hint and you can improve data distribution with partition hints for
                better parallel processing. For example, a measurement company analyzing how many
                households viewed a live sports event uses a broadcast join hint on their lookup
                table to improve query performance and reduce costs.&lt;br&gt; &lt;br&gt; With AWS
                Clean Rooms, customers can create a secure data clean room in minutes and
                collaborate with any company on AWS or Snowflake to generate unique insights about
                advertising campaigns, investment decisions, and research and development. For more
                information about the AWS Regions where AWS Clean Rooms is available, see the &lt;a
                href="https://docs.aws.amazon.com/general/latest/gr/clean-rooms.html#clean-rooms_region"
                target="_blank"&gt;AWS Regions&lt;/a&gt; table. To learn more about collaborating
                with AWS Clean Rooms, visit &lt;a href="https://aws.amazon.com/clean-rooms/"
                target="_blank"&gt;AWS Clean Rooms&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
            <pubDate>Wed, 21 Jan 2026 18:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <category>marketing:marchitecture/analytics,general:products/aws-clean-rooms</category>
            <author>aws@amazon.com</author>
            <link>
                https://aws.amazon.com/about-aws/whats-new/2026/01/aws-clean-rooms-join-partition-hints-sql/</link>
        </item>
        <item>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">566b38526c3aab155eb1f7a3510680d2fafcceb2</guid>
            <title>Amazon Connect can now automatically select random samples of agent contacts for
                evaluation</title>
            <description>&lt;p&gt;Amazon Connect can now provide managers with random samples of
                agent contacts for evaluation, so they can provide fair coaching feedback to agents.
                Managers can specify how many contacts they need to review per agent, as per union
                agreements, regulations, or internal guidelines. They then receive the required
                number of contacts randomly selected from the specified timeframe, for example, 3
                contacts per agent from the last week. Additionally, managers can use new filters to
                ensure that the selected contacts are suitable for evaluation, such as those with
                audio or screen recordings, transcripts, and exclude previously evaluated
                contacts.&lt;br&gt; &lt;br&gt; This feature is available in all regions where &lt;a
                href="https://docs.aws.amazon.com/connect/latest/adminguide/regions.html#amazonconnect_region"&gt;Amazon
                Connect&lt;/a&gt; is offered. To learn more, please visit our &lt;a
                href="https://docs.aws.amazon.com/connect/latest/adminguide/random-sampling-of-contacts-for-evaluation.html"&gt;documentation&lt;/a&gt;
                and our &lt;a href="https://aws.amazon.com/connect/"&gt;webpage&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
            <pubDate>Wed, 21 Jan 2026 18:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <category>
                general:products/amazon-connect,marketing:marchitecture/contact-center,marketing:marchitecture/applications</category>
            <author>aws@amazon.com</author>
            <link>
                https://aws.amazon.com/about-aws/whats-new/2026/01/amazon-connect-automatically-select-random-contacts-evaluation/</link>
        </item>
        <item>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">e3f35cc95e0bc18d2376361a44415ddc1fb826d2</guid>
            <title>Amazon EMR Serverless now supports AWS KMS customer managed keys for encrypting
                local disks</title>
            <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://aws.amazon.com/emr/serverless/"&gt;Amazon EMR
                Serverless&lt;/a&gt; now supports encrypting local disks with AWS Key Management
                Service (KMS) customer managed keys (CMKs). You can now meet strict regulatory and
                compliance requirements with additional encryption options beyond default AWS-owned
                keys, giving you greater control over your encryption strategy.&lt;br&gt; &lt;br&gt;
                Amazon EMR Serverless is a deployment option in Amazon EMR that makes it simple for
                data engineers and data scientists to run open-source big data analytics frameworks
                without configuring, managing, and scaling clusters or servers. Local disks on EMR
                Serverless workers are encrypted by default using AWS-owned keys. With this launch,
                customers who have strict regulatory and compliance needs can encrypt local disks
                with AWS KMS customer managed keys (CMKs) in the same account or from another
                account. This integration is supported on new or existing EMR Serverless
                applications and on all supported EMR release versions. You can specify the AWS KMS
                customer managed key at the application level where it applies to all workloads
                submitted on the application or you can specify the AWS KMS customer managed key for
                a specific job run or interactive session.&lt;br&gt; &lt;br&gt; This feature is
                available in all supported EMR Releases and in all AWS Regions where Amazon EMR
                Serverless is available including AWS GovCloud (US) and China regions. To learn
                more, see &lt;a
                href="https://docs.aws.amazon.com/emr/latest/EMR-Serverless-UserGuide/disk-encryption-cmk.html"&gt;Local
                Disk Encryption with AWS KMS CMK&lt;/a&gt; in the Amazon EMR Serverless User
                Guide.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
            <pubDate>Wed, 21 Jan 2026 17:37:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <category>marketing:marchitecture/analytics,general:products/amazon-emr</category>
            <author>aws@amazon.com</author>
            <link>
                https://aws.amazon.com/about-aws/whats-new/2026/01/amazon-emr-serverless-aws-kms-customer-managed</link>
        </item>
        <item>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">a71341ba7cba7419f694d2d99ae4994c347145f2</guid>
            <title>Amazon Bedrock Reserved Tier available now for Claude Sonnet 4.5 in AWS GovCloud
                (US-West)</title>
            <description>&lt;p&gt;Today, Amazon Bedrock introduces the expansion of the Reserved
                service tier designed for workloads requiring predictable performance and guaranteed
                tokens-per-minute capacity. The Reserved tier provides the ability to reserve
                prioritized compute capacity, keeping service levels predictable for your mission
                critical applications. It also includes the flexibility to allocate different input
                and output tokens-per-minute capacities to match the exact requirements of your
                workload and control cost. This is particularly valuable because many workloads have
                asymmetric token usage patterns. For instance, summarization tasks consume many
                input tokens but generate fewer output tokens, while content generation applications
                require less input and more output capacity. When your application needs more
                tokens-per-minute capacity than what you reserved , the service automatically
                overflows to the pay-as-you-go Standard tier, ensuring uninterrupted operations. The
                Reserved tier is available today for Anthropic Claude Sonnet 4.5 in AWS GovCloud
                (US-West). Customers can reserve capacity for 1 month or 3 month duration. Customers
                pay a fixed price per 1K tokens-per-minute and are billed monthly. Amazon Bedrock
                Reserved Tier is available for customers in AWS GovCloud (US-West) via &lt;a
                href="https://docs.aws.amazon.com/bedrock/latest/userguide/inference-profiles-support.html"
                target="_blank"&gt;GOV-CRIS cross-region profile&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;br&gt; &lt;br&gt;
                With the expansion of the Reserved service tier, Amazon Bedrock continues to provide
                more choice to customers, helping them develop, scale, and deploy applications and
                agents that improve productivity and customer experiences while balancing
                performance and cost requirements.&lt;br&gt; &lt;br&gt; For more information about
                the AWS Regions where Amazon Bedrock Reserved tier is available, refer to the&lt;a
                href="https://docs.aws.amazon.com/bedrock/latest/userguide/service-tiers-inference.html"
                target="_blank"&gt; Documentation&lt;/a&gt;. To get access to the Reserved tier,
                please contact your AWS account team.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
            <pubDate>Wed, 21 Jan 2026 17:02:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <category>
                general:products/amazon-bedrock,general:products/aws-govcloud-us,marketing:marchitecture/artificial-intelligence</category>
            <author>aws@amazon.com</author>
            <link>
                https://aws.amazon.com/about-aws/whats-new/2026/01/amazon-bedrock-reserved-tier-for-claude-sonnet-in-govcloud/</link>
        </item>
        <item>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">6d8895a35ceeb85149cbc8b314521c3bdd17089a</guid>
            <title>Amazon EC2 C8gn instances are now available in additional regions</title>
            <description>&lt;p&gt;Starting today, Amazon Elastic Compute Cloud (Amazon EC2) C8gn
                instances, powered by the latest-generation AWS Graviton4 processors, are available
                in the AWS Region&amp;nbsp;Asia Pacific (Mumbai), Africa (Cape Town), Europe
                (Ireland, London), Canada West (Calgary). The new instances provide up to 30% better
                compute performance than Graviton3-based Amazon EC2 C7gn instances. Amazon EC2 C8gn
                instances feature the latest 6th generation AWS Nitro Cards, and offer up to 600
                Gbps network bandwidth, the highest network bandwidth among network optimized EC2
                instances.&amp;nbsp;&lt;br&gt; &amp;nbsp;&lt;br&gt; Take advantage of the enhanced
                networking capabilities of C8gn to scale performance and throughput, while
                optimizing the cost of running network-intensive workloads such as network virtual
                appliances, data analytics, CPU-based artificial&amp;nbsp;intelligence&amp;nbsp;and
                machine learning&amp;nbsp;(AI/ML) inference.&amp;nbsp;&lt;br&gt;
                &amp;nbsp;&lt;br&gt; For increased scalability, C8gn instances offer instance sizes
                up to 48xlarge, up to 384 GiB of memory, and up to 60 Gbps of bandwidth to Amazon
                Elastic Block Store (EBS). C8gn instances support Elastic Fabric Adapter (EFA)
                networking on the 16xlarge, 24xlarge, 48xlarge, metal-24xl, and metal-48xl sizes,
                which enables lower latency and improved cluster performance for workloads deployed
                on tightly coupled clusters.&amp;nbsp;&lt;br&gt; &amp;nbsp;&lt;br&gt; C8gn instances
                are available in the following AWS Regions: US East (N. Virginia, Ohio), US West
                (Oregon, N.California), Europe (Frankfurt, Stockholm, Ireland, London), Asia Pacific
                (Singapore, Malaysia, Sydney, Thailand, Mumbai), Middle East (UAE), Africa (Cape
                Town), Canada West (Calgary).&amp;nbsp;&lt;br&gt; &amp;nbsp;&lt;br&gt; To learn
                more, see&amp;nbsp;&lt;a
                href="https://aws.amazon.com/ec2/instance-types/c8g/"&gt;Amazon C8gn
                Instances&lt;/a&gt;. To begin your Graviton journey, visit the&amp;nbsp;&lt;a
                href="https://aws.amazon.com/ec2/graviton/level-up-with-graviton/"&gt;Level up your
                compute with AWS Graviton page&lt;/a&gt;. To get started, see&amp;nbsp;&lt;a
                href="https://console.aws.amazon.com/"&gt;AWS Management
                Console&lt;/a&gt;,&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="https://aws.amazon.com/cli/"&gt;AWS Command
                Line Interface (AWS CLI)&lt;/a&gt;, and&amp;nbsp;&lt;a
                href="https://docs.aws.amazon.com/AWSJavaScriptSDK/latest/AWS/EC2.html"&gt;AWS
                SDKs&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
            <pubDate>Wed, 21 Jan 2026 17:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <category>general:products/amazon-ec2,marketing:marchitecture/compute</category>
            <author>aws@amazon.com</author>
            <link>
                https://aws.amazon.com/about-aws/whats-new/2026/01/amazon-ec2-c8gn-instances-additional-regions</link>
        </item>
        <item>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">51c4ec0eb5ef0e5614be5d873b3e071889d51d02</guid>
            <title>AWS introduces additional policy details to access denied error messages</title>
            <description>&lt;p&gt;AWS now includes the&amp;nbsp;&lt;a
                href="https://aws.amazon.com/iam/"&gt;AWS Identity and Access Management
                (IAM)&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;and &lt;a
                href="https://docs.aws.amazon.com/organizations/"&gt;AWS
                Organizations&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;policy’s Amazon Resource Name (ARN) in access
                denied error messages in same account and same organization scenarios. This allows
                you to quickly identify the exact policy responsible for the denied access and take
                action to troubleshoot the issue.&lt;br&gt; &lt;br&gt; Before this launch, customers
                had to identify the root cause of access denied errors based only on the policy type
                in the error message. This launch expedites troubleshooting when you have multiple
                policies of the same type, as you can directly see which policy to address for
                explicit deny cases. The error message now includes the policy ARN for Service
                Control Policies (SCP), Resource Control Policies (RCP), identity-based policies,
                session policies, and permission boundaries.&lt;br&gt; &lt;br&gt; This additional
                context will gradually become available across AWS services in all AWS regions. To
                learn more, refer to&amp;nbsp;&lt;a
                href="https://docs.aws.amazon.com/IAM/latest/UserGuide/troubleshoot_access-denied.html"&gt;IAM
                documentation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
            <pubDate>Wed, 21 Jan 2026 16:17:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <category>
                marketing:marchitecture/security-identity-and-compliance,general:products/aws-iam,general:products/aws-organizations</category>
            <author>aws@amazon.com</author>
            <link>
                https://aws.amazon.com/about-aws/whats-new/2026/01/additional-policy-details-access-denied-error/</link>
        </item>
        <item>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">f5aa902a2c42cb4fcfb46de2c1e59617ca483bf9</guid>
            <title>Instance Scheduler on AWS adds enhanced scaling, reliability, and event-driven
                automation</title>
            <description>&lt;p&gt;Today AWS announced enhanced scheduling orchestration to track AWS
                tagging events, self-service troubleshooting via informational resource tags, an
                optional EC2 insufficient-capacity retry flow using alternate instance types, and
                automatic creation of a dedicated EventBridge bus for scheduling events for Instance
                Scheduler (IS) on AWS. IS’s orchestration and fan-out mechanisms have been
                re-architected to enable customers to track AWS tagging events, allowing the product
                to more intelligently sequence and distribute scheduling operations - improving
                scaling performance and addressing cost-scaling concerns. The product now enables
                distributed cloud engineer personas to perform self-service troubleshooting in their
                spoke accounts through informational tags applied to their resources without relying
                on a central cloud administrator. In addition, an optional Insufficient Capacity
                Error Retry flow has been added to automatically retry failed start actions using
                alternate instance types when EC2 encounters insufficient capacity errors, ensuring
                workloads start reliably even in constrained Availability Zones or regions. Lastly,
                Instance Scheduler on AWS now automatically creates a dedicated EventBus for
                scheduling-related events, streamlining integrations and automation
                workflows.&lt;/p&gt;
                &lt;p&gt;This update improves Instance Scheduler’s scalability, reduces operational
                overhead, and increases workload reliability across complex customer environments.
                You can accelerate issue resolution and boost operational efficiency by empowering
                distributed cloud engineers to troubleshoot independently. You can enhance overall
                workload resilience by improving handling of EC2 capacity shortages and simplify
                integrations by streamlining event routing through the new EventBus to support more
                extensible automation workflows.&lt;/p&gt;
                &lt;p&gt;To learn more about Instance Scheduler, visit the &lt;a
                href="https://aws.amazon.com/solutions/implementations/instance-scheduler-on-aws/"&gt;Product
                Page &lt;/a&gt;or contact your AWS account team.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
            <pubDate>Wed, 21 Jan 2026 15:48:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <category>general:products</category>
            <author>aws@amazon.com</author>
            <link>
                https://aws.amazon.com/about-aws/whats-new/2026/01/instance-scheduler-adds-enhanced-scaling/</link>
        </item>
        <item>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">e64e30610d9ab16bc2941817f76e4ab333e04570</guid>
            <title>Announcing availability of second-generation AWS Outposts racks in 20 more
                countries</title>
            <description>&lt;p&gt;Second-generation AWS Outposts racks can now be shipped and
                installed at your data center and on-premises locations in Argentina, Bangladesh,
                Colombia, Dominican Republic, Ecuador, India, Kazakhstan, Mexico, Morocco, Nigeria,
                Oman, Panama, Qatar, Senegal, Serbia, South Africa, Republic of Korea, Taiwan,
                Thailand, and Uruguay.&lt;br&gt; &lt;br&gt; Outposts racks extend AWS
                infrastructure, AWS services, APIs, and tools to virtually any on-premises data
                center or colocation space for a truly consistent hybrid experience. Outposts racks
                are ideal for workloads requiring low-latency access to on-premises systems, local
                data processing, data residency compliance, and migration of applications with local
                system dependencies. Second-generation Outposts racks support the latest generation
                of x86-powered Amazon Elastic Compute Cloud (Amazon EC2) instances, starting with
                C7i, M7i, and R7i instances. These instances provide up to 40% better performance
                compared to C5, M5, and R5 instances on first-generation Outposts racks.
                Second-generation Outposts racks also offer simplified network scaling and
                configuration, and support a new category of accelerated networking Amazon EC2
                instances optimized for ultra-low latency and high throughput needs.&lt;br&gt;
                &lt;br&gt; With the availability of second-generation Outposts racks in the above
                countries, you can run AWS services locally in your on-premises facilities to
                maintain data residency within your country, while connecting to a supported AWS
                Region for management and operations.&lt;br&gt; &lt;br&gt; To learn more about
                second-generation Outposts racks, read &lt;a
                href="https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/aws/announcing-second-generation-aws-outposts-racks-with-breakthrough-performance-and-scalability-on-premises/"&gt;this
                blog post&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a
                href="https://docs.aws.amazon.com/outposts/latest/network-userguide/what-is-outposts.html"&gt;user
                guide&lt;/a&gt;. For the most updated list of countries and territories and the AWS
                Regions where second-generation Outposts racks are supported, check out the &lt;a
                href="https://aws.amazon.com/outposts/rack/faqs/"&gt;Outposts rack FAQs
                page&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
            <pubDate>Wed, 21 Jan 2026 15:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <category>
                marketing:marchitecture/compute,marketing:marchitecture/storage,general:products/aws-outposts,marketing:marchitecture/networking</category>
            <author>aws@amazon.com</author>
            <link>
                https://aws.amazon.com/about-aws/whats-new/2026/01/availability-second-generation-aws-outposts-racks-more-countries</link>
        </item>
        <item>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">c17fe6e42dcf2aed52c2ececce233ed94367f36d</guid>
            <title>AWS Transfer Family Terraform module now supports web apps</title>
            <description>&lt;p&gt;You can now use the&amp;nbsp;&lt;a
                href="https://github.com/aws-ia/terraform-aws-transfer-family"
                target="_blank"&gt;AWS Transfer Family Terraform module&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;to deploy
                Transfer Family web apps, which enable end users to transfer files to and from
                Amazon S3 over a web interface. This release streamlines centralized provisioning of
                web apps with federated authentication and user access controls, enabling
                consistent, repeatable deployments through infrastructure as code.&lt;br&gt;
                &lt;br&gt; With Transfer Family web apps, you can provide your workforce with a
                fully managed, branded web portal to browse, upload, and download data in S3. In a
                single deployment, this module allows you to programmatically provision your web
                apps that authenticate users through AWS IAM Identity Center using your existing
                identity provider and Amazon S3 Access Grants for fine-grained user permissions. An
                included&amp;nbsp;&lt;a
                href="https://github.com/aws-ia/terraform-aws-transfer-family/tree/v0.5.0/examples/sample-web-app"
                target="_blank"&gt;end-to-end example&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;shows you how to assign and
                optionally create IAM Identity Center users and groups, configure S3 Access Grants,
                set up the web app, and enable security auditing through Amazon
                CloudTrail.&lt;br&gt; &lt;br&gt; You can get started by downloading the new module
                from the&amp;nbsp;&lt;a
                href="https://registry.terraform.io/modules/aws-ia/transfer-family/aws/latest/submodules/transfer-web-app"
                target="_blank"&gt;Terraform Registry&lt;/a&gt;. To learn more about Transfer Family
                web apps, visit the&amp;nbsp;&lt;a
                href="https://docs.aws.amazon.com/transfer/latest/userguide/web-app.html"
                target="_blank"&gt;user guide&lt;/a&gt;. To see all the regions where Transfer
                Family web apps is available, visit the&amp;nbsp;&lt;a
                href="https://docs.aws.amazon.com/transfer/latest/userguide/web-app.html#webapp-regions"
                target="_blank"&gt;AWS Region table&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
            <pubDate>Wed, 21 Jan 2026 13:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <category>
                marketing:marchitecture/migration,general:products/aws-transfer-family,marketing:marchitecture/storage</category>
            <author>aws@amazon.com</author>
            <link>
                https://aws.amazon.com/about-aws/whats-new/2026/01/aws-transfer-family-terraform-webapps</link>
        </item>
        <item>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">6607a831e7967ae4e0de1a05dcef76283ec1fbee</guid>
            <title>Amazon RDS for SQL Server enhances differential and transaction log restores
                support</title>
            <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://aws.amazon.com/rds/sqlserver/"
                target="_blank"&gt;Amazon Relational Database Service (Amazon RDS) for SQL
                Server&lt;/a&gt; now supports differential and transaction log restores for
                instances configured with Multi-AZ and instances with read replicas in the same
                region. The native SQL Server backup and restore feature provides essential
                protection for critical data in your SQL Server databases, and it allows you to
                migrate your databases between different environments, such as from on-premises to
                Amazon RDS for SQL Server.&amp;nbsp;Differential backups capture all data changes
                since the most recent full backup, while transaction log backups record every
                transaction in the database. When combined with full backups, these restore options
                help you create a comprehensive disaster recovery strategy that minimizes data
                loss.&lt;/p&gt;
                &lt;p&gt;Previously, to use native SQL Server differential and transaction log
                restores, you had to remove Multi-AZ and read replicas to convert your instance to
                Single-AZ mode, restore the databases, and then reconfigure Multi-AZ and read
                replicas. Now you can reduce restore time by performing differential and transaction
                log restores directly on Multi-AZ instances and instances with read replicas,
                without converting them to Single-AZ first. This enhancement maintains high
                availability through Multi-AZ and allows read replicas to continue serving read
                workloads in the same Region during the restore process.&lt;/p&gt;
                &lt;p&gt;For more information about using differential and transaction log restores,
                see the &lt;a
                href="https://docs.aws.amazon.com/AmazonRDS/latest/UserGuide/SQLServer.Procedural.Importing.html"
                target="_blank"&gt;Amazon RDS for SQL Server User Guide&lt;/a&gt;. This feature is
                available in all AWS Regions where Amazon RDS for SQL Server is available.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
            <pubDate>Wed, 21 Jan 2026 08:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <category>
                marketing:marchitecture/databases,general:products/aws-govcloud-us,general:products/amazon-rds-for-sql-server</category>
            <author>aws@amazon.com</author>
            <link>
                https://aws.amazon.com/about-aws/whats-new/2026/01/amazon-rds-sql-server-diff-and-log-restores-for-maz-and-rr/</link>
        </item>
        <item>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">5eb0f1307e9ae3be8cf1ad6f539804581951af9c</guid>
            <title>Amazon ECR now supports cross-repository layer sharing to optimize storage and
                improve push performance</title>
            <description>
                &lt;p&gt;Amazon Elastic Container Registry (ECR) now enables you to share
                common image layers across repositories within a registry through a capability
                called blob mounting. This feature is especially valuable if you manage multiple
                microservices or applications built from common base images. With blob mounting, you
                can achieve faster image pushes by reusing existing layers instead of re-uploading
                identical content, and reduce storage costs by storing common layers once and
                referencing them across repositories.&lt;br&gt; &lt;br&gt; Getting started is
                simple, enable the registry-level setting through the ECR console or AWS CLI. Once
                enabled, ECR automatically handles layer sharing when you push images.&lt;br&gt;
                &lt;br&gt; Blob mounting is available in all AWS commercial and AWS GovCloud (US)
                Regions. To learn more about blob mounting, please visit our&amp;nbsp;&lt;a
                href="https://docs.aws.amazon.com/AmazonECR/latest/userguide/registry-settings.html"&gt;documentation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
            <pubDate>Tue, 20 Jan 2026 21:31:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <category>
                marketing:marchitecture/containers,general:products/aws-govcloud-us,general:products/amazon-ecr</category>
            <author>aws@amazon.com</author>
            <link>
                https://aws.amazon.com/about-aws/whats-new/2026/01/amazon-ecr-cross-repository-layer-sharing/</link>
        </item>
        <item>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">516bcaaff39000ee72fdbe31f346ea668963cbe2</guid>
            <title>SageMaker Unified Studio adds cross-Region subscriptions support for IDC based
                domains</title>
            <description>&lt;p&gt;Amazon SageMaker Unified Studio now supports cross-Region
                subscriptions for comprehensive and flexible data access and governance. With
                cross-Region support, you can subscribe to AWS Glue tables and views, as well as
                Amazon Redshift tables and views published in a different AWS Region than your
                project. This capability helps break down data silos and enable better collaboration
                across your organization by allowing teams to access curated data assets from any
                AWS Region without manual replication.&lt;br&gt; &lt;br&gt; To get started with
                cross-Region subscriptions, log into SageMaker Unified Studio, or use the Amazon
                DataZone API, SDK, or AWS CLI. Cross-Region subscriptions support is available in
                all&amp;nbsp;&lt;a
                href="https://docs.aws.amazon.com/sagemaker-unified-studio/latest/adminguide/supported-regions.html"&gt;AWS
                Regions where SageMaker Unified Studio&lt;/a&gt; is supported. To learn more, see
                the SageMaker Unified Studio &lt;a
                href="https://docs.aws.amazon.com/sagemaker-unified-studio/latest/userguide/grant-access-to-unmanaged-asset.html"&gt;user
                guide&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
            <pubDate>Tue, 20 Jan 2026 20:59:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <category>marketing:marchitecture/analytics,general:products/amazon-sagemaker-studio</category>
            <author>aws@amazon.com</author>
            <link>
                https://aws.amazon.com/about-aws/whats-new/2026/01/sagemaker-unified-studio-adds-cross-region-iam/</link>
        </item>
        <item>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">674e71f8739b70c86e1e3cb6f731f99ca4a0ee4f</guid>
            <title>AWS expands managed integrations for AWS IoT Device Management service coverage
                to the Middle East (UAE) region</title>
            <description>&lt;p&gt;AWS IoT Device Management now offers the managed integrations
                feature in the Middle East (UAE) region. Organizations operating in this region can
                now better serve their local customers, helping them build unified Internet of
                Things (IoT) solutions that can easily onboard and manage diverse IoT devices
                through a single interface, regardless of connection type - direct, hub-based, or
                third-party cloud-based.&lt;br&gt; &lt;br&gt; Managed integrations provides
                developers with a unified interface and device SDKs supporting ZigBee, Z-Wave,
                Matter and Wi-Fi protocols. The feature includes partner built cloud-to-cloud
                connectors and 80+ device data model templates based on AWS's implementation of the
                Matter data model standard. These capabilities allow developers to rapidly integrate
                devices into end user applications, such as home security, energy management, and
                elderly care monitoring.&lt;br&gt; &lt;br&gt; The managed integrations feature is
                available in Canada (Central), Europe (Ireland) and Middle East (UAE) regions. To
                learn more, refer to the &lt;a
                href="https://docs.aws.amazon.com/iot-mi/latest/devguide/what-is-managedintegrations.html"&gt;developer
                guide&lt;/a&gt; and get started on the &lt;a
                href="https://console.aws.amazon.com/iot/home"&gt;AWS IoT
                console&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
            <pubDate>Tue, 20 Jan 2026 17:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <category>
                general:products/aws-iot-device-management,marketing:marchitecture/internet-of-things</category>
            <author>aws@amazon.com</author>
            <link>
                https://aws.amazon.com/about-aws/whats-new/2026/01/managed-integrations-iot-device-coverage-uae/</link>
        </item>
        <item>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">67461772c05b46c594ef7f6f3389e7fdcb88fd5c</guid>
            <title>AWS Glue is now available in Asia Pacific (New Zealand) Region</title>
            <description>&lt;p&gt;AWS Glue is now available in the Asia Pacific (New Zealand)
                Region, enabling customers to build and run their ETL workloads closer to their data
                sources in this region.&lt;br&gt; &lt;br&gt; AWS Glue is a serverless data
                integration service that makes it simple to discover, prepare, and combine data for
                analytics, machine learning, and application development. AWS Glue provides both
                visual and code-based interfaces to make data integration simpler so you can analyze
                your data and put it to use in minutes instead of months.&lt;br&gt; &lt;br&gt; To
                learn more, visit the AWS Glue &lt;a href="https://aws.amazon.com/glue/"&gt;product
                page&lt;/a&gt; and our &lt;a
                href="https://docs.aws.amazon.com/glue/"&gt;documentation&lt;/a&gt;.&amp;nbsp;For
                AWS Glue Region availability, please see the&amp;nbsp;&lt;a
                href="https://aws.amazon.com/about-aws/global-infrastructure/regional-product-services/"&gt;AWS
                Region table&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
            <pubDate>Tue, 20 Jan 2026 17:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <category>marketing:marchitecture/analytics,general:products/aws-glue</category>
            <author>aws@amazon.com</author>
            <link>
                https://aws.amazon.com/about-aws/whats-new/2026/01/aws-glue-available-new-zealand-region</link>
        </item>
        <item>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">c97d51ca9fac14e7f7c888a4692da91b2206bc29</guid>
            <title>Amazon Quick Suite launches expanded size, faster ingestion, and richer data type
                support for SPICE datasets</title>
            <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://aws.amazon.com/quicksight/"
                target="_blank"&gt;Amazon Quick Suite&lt;/a&gt; SPICE engine is now supporting
                higher scale, faster ingestion, and broader data types to power advanced analytics
                and AI-driven workloads. With this launch, customers can load up to 2TB of data per
                dataset, doubling the previous 1TB limit, when using the new data preparation
                experience. Despite the increased dataset size, SPICE continues to deliver strong
                performance, with ingestion further optimized to enable even faster data loading and
                refresh to reduce time to insight. We’ve also expanded SPICE’s data type support by
                increasing string length limits from 2K to 64K Unicode characters and extending the
                supported timestamp range from year 1400 back to year 0001. As Quick Suite customers
                bring richer, more complex, and increasingly AI-driven workloads into SPICE, these
                enhancements enable broader data coverage, faster data onboarding, and more powerful
                analytics, without compromising performance. To learn more, visit &lt;a
                href="https://docs.aws.amazon.com/quicksuite/latest/userguide/data-source-limits.html#spice-limits"
                target="_blank"&gt;our documentation.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br&gt; &lt;br&gt; The new SPICE
                dataset size limitation is now available in Amazon Quick Sight Enterprise Editions
                across all &lt;a
                href="https://docs.aws.amazon.com/quicksight/latest/user/regions-qs.html"
                target="_blank"&gt;supported Amazon Quick Sight
                regions&lt;/a&gt;.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
            <pubDate>Tue, 20 Jan 2026 16:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <category>
                general:products/aws-govcloud-us,general:products/amazon-quicksight,marketing:marchitecture/analytics</category>
            <author>aws@amazon.com</author>
            <link>
                https://aws.amazon.com/about-aws/whats-new/2026/01/amazon-quick-suite-launches-expanded-spice</link>
        </item>
        <item>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">67a064a4499c6b7988dbd53323ddc08ff7e186a9</guid>
            <title>Amazon RDS for Oracle extends support for bare metal instances to Standard
                Edition 2</title>
            <description>&lt;p&gt;Amazon RDS for Oracle now supports bare metal instances with Bring
                Your Own License (BYOL) license for Oracle Standard Edition 2. You can use M7i, R7i,
                X2iedn, X2idn, X2iezn, M6i, M6id, M6in, R6i, R6id, and R6in bare metal instances at
                25% lower price compared to equivalent virtualized instances.&lt;br&gt; &lt;br&gt;
                With bare metal instances, you may be able to reduce your commercial database
                license and support costs by using bare metal instances since they provide full
                visibility into the number of CPU cores and sockets of the underlying server. Most
                bare metal instances have 2 sockets while db.m7i.metal-24xl and db.r7i.metal-24xl
                instances each have a single socket. Consult your legal or licensing partner to
                determine if you can use bare metal instances with Oracle Standard Edition 2 and if
                you can reduce license and support costs.&lt;br&gt; &lt;br&gt; Bare metal instances
                are available with Bring Your Own License (BYOL) license for Oracle Enterprise
                Edition Standard Edition 2. Refer to &lt;a
                href="https://aws.amazon.com/rds/oracle/pricing/" target="_blank"&gt;Amazon RDS for
                Oracle Pricing&lt;/a&gt; for available instance configurations, pricing, and region
                availability.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
            <pubDate>Tue, 20 Jan 2026 16:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <category>
                marketing:marchitecture/databases,general:products/amazon-rds-for-oracle,general:products/aws-govcloud-us</category>
            <author>aws@amazon.com</author>
            <link>
                https://aws.amazon.com/about-aws/whats-new/2026/01/amazon-rds-oracle-support-bare-metal-instances-standard-edition-2</link>
        </item>
        <item>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">0bd66d3dd4a970354a45e2e43291582eb0d2ad0f</guid>
            <title>Amazon EC2 G7e instances are now generally available</title>
            <description>&lt;p&gt;Today, Amazon announces the general availability of Amazon Elastic
                Compute Cloud (Amazon EC2) G7e instances, accelerated by NVIDIA RTX PRO 6000
                Blackwell Server Edition GPUs.&amp;nbsp;G7e instances offer up to 2.3x inference
                performance compared to G6e.&lt;/p&gt;
                &lt;p&gt;Customers can use G7e instances to deploy large language models (LLMs),
                agentic AI models, multimodal generative AI models, and physical AI models. G7e
                instances offer the highest performance for spatial computing workloads as well as
                workloads that require both graphics and AI processing capabilities.&amp;nbsp;G7e
                instances feature up to 8 NVIDIA RTX PRO 6000 Blackwell Server Edition GPUs, with 96
                GB of memory per GPU, and 5th Generation Intel Xeon processors. They support up to
                192 virtual CPUs (vCPUs) and up to 1600 Gbps of Elastic Fabric Adapter networking
                bandwidth. G7e instances support NVIDIA GPUDirect Peer to Peer (P2P) that boosts
                performance for multi-GPU workloads. Multi-GPU G7e instances also support NVIDIA
                GPUDirect Remote Direct Memory Access (RDMA) with EFAv4 in EC2 UltraClusters,
                reducing latency for small-scale multi-node workloads.&lt;/p&gt;
                &lt;p&gt;You can use G7e instances for Amazon EC2 in the following AWS Regions: US
                East (N. Virginia) and US East (Ohio). You can purchase G7e instances as On-Demand
                Instances, Spot Instances, or as part of Savings Plans.&lt;/p&gt;
                &lt;p&gt;To get started, visit the&amp;nbsp;&lt;a
                href="https://console.aws.amazon.com/" target="_blank"&gt;AWS Management
                Console&lt;/a&gt;,&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="https://aws.amazon.com/cli/"
                target="_blank"&gt;AWS Command Line Interface&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;(CLI), and AWS
                SDKs. To learn more, visit&amp;nbsp;&lt;a
                href="https://aws.amazon.com/ec2/instance-types/g7e/" target="_blank"&gt;G7e
                instances&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
            <pubDate>Tue, 20 Jan 2026 15:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <category>general:products/amazon-ec2,marketing:marchitecture/compute</category>
            <author>aws@amazon.com</author>
            <link>
                https://aws.amazon.com/about-aws/whats-new/2026/01/amazon-g7e-instances-generally-available</link>
        </item>
        <item>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">c5dd0b5d6b68f64ca55770edbd06556f106599ce</guid>
            <title>Amazon Corretto January 2026 Quarterly Updates</title>
            <description>&lt;p&gt;On January 20, 2026 Amazon announced quarterly security and
                critical updates for Amazon Corretto Long-Term Supported (LTS) versions of OpenJDK.
                Corretto 25.0.2, 21.0.10, 17.0.18, 11.0.30, and 8u482 are now available for &lt;a
                href="https://aws.amazon.com/corretto/" target="_blank"&gt;download&lt;/a&gt;.
                Amazon Corretto is a no-cost, multi-platform, production-ready distribution of
                OpenJDK.&lt;br&gt; &lt;br&gt; Click on the Corretto &lt;a
                href="https://aws.amazon.com/corretto" target="_blank"&gt;home page&lt;/a&gt; to
                download Corretto 25, Corretto 21, Corretto 17, Corretto 11, or Corretto 8. You can
                also get the updates on your Linux system by configuring a &lt;a
                href="https://docs.aws.amazon.com/corretto/latest/corretto-25-ug/generic-linux-install.html"
                target="_blank"&gt;Corretto Apt, Yum, or Apk repo&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;br&gt; &lt;br&gt;
                Feedback is &lt;a href="https://github.com/corretto"
                target="_blank"&gt;welcomed&lt;/a&gt;!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
            <pubDate>Tue, 20 Jan 2026 15:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <category>
                general:products/aws-govcloud-us,general:products/amazon-corretto,marketing:marchitecture/developer-tools</category>
            <author>aws@amazon.com</author>
            <link>
                https://aws.amazon.com/about-aws/whats-new/2026/01/amazon-corretto-january-2026-quarterly-updates</link>
        </item>
        <item>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">3c8d508152c93cbe63b362894688e0e41cb15399</guid>
            <title>Amazon Quick Sight expands dashboard customization in tables and pivot tables</title>
            <description>&lt;p&gt;Building on our recent launch of &lt;a
                href="https://aws.amazon.com/about-aws/whats-new/2025/11/amazon-quick-sight-dashboard-tables-pivot-tables/"
                target="_blank"&gt;customizable tables and pivot tables&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a
                href="https://aws.amazon.com/quicksuite/quicksight/" target="_blank"&gt;Amazon Quick
                Sight &lt;/a&gt;now enables readers to add or remove fields, change aggregations,
                and modify formatting directly in dashboards—all without requiring updates from
                dashboard authors.&lt;br&gt; &lt;br&gt; These enhanced capabilities empower readers
                with even greater flexibility to tailor their data views for specific analytical
                needs. For example, sales managers can add revenue breakdowns by product category to
                identify growth opportunities, while finance teams can change aggregations from sum
                to average to better understand spending patterns across departments.&lt;br&gt;
                &lt;br&gt; These new customization features are now available in Amazon Quick Sight
                Enterprise Edition across all &lt;a
                href="https://docs.aws.amazon.com/quicksight/latest/user/regions-qs.html"
                target="_blank"&gt;supported Amazon Quick Sight regions&lt;/a&gt;. To get started
                with these new customization features, see our &lt;a
                href="https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/business-intelligence/amazon-quick-sight-expands-dashboard-customization-in-tables-and-pivot-tables/"
                target="_blank"&gt;blog post.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
            <pubDate>Tue, 20 Jan 2026 15:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <category>
                general:products/amazon-quicksight,general:products/aws-govcloud-us,marketing:marchitecture/analytics</category>
            <author>aws@amazon.com</author>
            <link>
                https://aws.amazon.com/about-aws/whats-new/2026/01/amazon-quicksight-expands-dashboard-customization-tables-pivot-tables</link>
        </item>
        <item>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">71254182279decc782c8641a3af4fbafbbc782bf</guid>
            <title>Amazon Aurora and RDS for PostgreSQL, MySQL and MariaDB now support r8g, r7g, and
                r7i database instances in additional AWS Regions</title>
            <description>&lt;p&gt;AWS Graviton4-based R8g database instances are now generally
                available for Amazon Aurora (MySQL and PostgreSQL compatibility) and Amazon RDS for
                PostgreSQL, MySQL, and MariaDB in additional Asia Pacific regions (Hong Kong, Osaka,
                and Jakarta). R8G instances are now supported for Amazon Aurora with MySQL
                compatibility and Amazon RDS for PostgreSQL, MySQL, and MariaDB in Asia Pacific
                (Seoul and Singapore), and Canada (Central) regions, expanding on the previous
                launch of R8g support for Amazon Aurora with PostgreSQL compatibility in these three
                regions. Additionally, Amazon Aurora with MySQL and PostgreSQL compatibility now
                also supports R7i database instances in Asia Pacific (Hyderabad) and R7g database
                instances in Africa (Cape Town).&lt;br&gt; &lt;br&gt; AWS Graviton4-based instances
                provide up to 40% performance improvement and up to 29% price/performance
                improvement for on-demand pricing over Graviton3-based instances of equivalent sizes
                on Amazon Aurora and Amazon RDS databases, depending on database engine, version,
                and workload. Built on the AWS Nitro System, the new R8g database instances
                introduce 24xlarge and 48xlarge sizes, delivering up to 192 vCPUs, an 8:1 ratio of
                memory to vCPU with the latest DDR5 memory, up to 50Gbps enhanced networking
                bandwidth, and up to 40Gbps of bandwidth to Amazon Elastic Block Store (Amazon
                EBS).&lt;br&gt; &lt;br&gt; You can easily launch R8g, R7g, or R7i database instances
                through the&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="https://console.aws.amazon.com/rds/home"
                target="_blank"&gt;Amazon RDS Management Console&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;or by using
                the&amp;nbsp;&lt;a
                href="https://docs.aws.amazon.com/AmazonRDS/latest/AuroraUserGuide/Aurora.CreateInstance.html"
                target="_blank"&gt;AWS Command Line Interface&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;(CLI). For detailed
                information about specific engine versions that support these database instance
                types, please refer to the&amp;nbsp;&lt;a
                href="https://docs.aws.amazon.com/AmazonRDS/latest/AuroraUserGuide/Concepts.DBInstanceClass.SupportAurora.html"
                target="_blank"&gt;Aurora&amp;nbsp;&lt;/a&gt;and&amp;nbsp;&lt;a
                href="https://docs.aws.amazon.com/AmazonRDS/latest/UserGuide/Concepts.DBInstanceClass.Support.html"
                target="_blank"&gt;RDS&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;documentation.&amp;nbsp;For complete
                information on pricing and regional availability, please refer to the Amazon
                RDS&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="https://aws.amazon.com/rds/pricing/"
                target="_blank"&gt;pricing page&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
            <pubDate>Tue, 20 Jan 2026 15:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <category>
                general:products/amazon-aurora,general:products/amazon-rds,marketing:marchitecture/databases</category>
            <author>aws@amazon.com</author>
            <link>
                https://aws.amazon.comabout-aws/whats-new/2026/01/amazon-aurora-rds-r8g-r7g-r7i-instances-additional-regions/</link>
        </item>
        <item>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">c3e6335f077e9217df2725d052a7aae98024b9cf</guid>
            <title>Amazon RDS Blue/Green Deployments reduces downtime to under five seconds</title>
            <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://aws.amazon.com/rds/" target="_blank"&gt;Amazon
                Relational Database Service (Amazon RDS)&lt;/a&gt; now supports faster Blue/Green
                Deployments switchover, reducing your primary database, or writer node, upgrade
                downtime to typically five seconds or lower for single-Region configurations.
                Blue/Green Deployment creates a staging environment (Green) to test changes while
                keeping production (Blue) safe, enabling seamless switchover that requires no
                application endpoint changes.&lt;br&gt; &lt;br&gt; Your database writer instance
                downtime during switchover varies based on your connection method. For single-Region
                configurations, applications connecting directly to the database endpoint experience
                typically five seconds or lower downtime, while those using the AWS Advanced JDBC
                Driver typically see two seconds or lower due to eliminated DNS propagation delays.
                You can use Amazon RDS Blue/Green Deployments for deploying changes to production,
                such as major version database engine upgrades, maintenance updates, and scaling
                instances.&lt;br&gt; &lt;br&gt; Support for faster RDS Blue/Green Deployments
                switchover for single-Region configurations is available for Amazon Aurora and
                Amazon RDS database engines including PostgreSQL, MySQL, and MariaDB in all AWS
                regions.&lt;br&gt; &lt;br&gt; In a few clicks, update your databases using RDS
                Blue/Green Deployments via the &lt;a href="https://console.aws.amazon.com/rds/home"
                target="_blank"&gt;Amazon RDS Console&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a
                href="https://docs.aws.amazon.com/AmazonRDS/latest/AuroraUserGuide/blue-green-deployments-creating.html#blue-green-deployments-creating-create"
                target="_blank"&gt;Amazon RDS CLI&lt;/a&gt;. Learn more about RDS Blue/Green
                Deployments and the supported engine versions &lt;a
                href="https://docs.aws.amazon.com/AmazonRDS/latest/AuroraUserGuide/blue-green-deployments-overview.html"
                target="_blank"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
            <pubDate>Tue, 20 Jan 2026 15:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <category>
                marketing:marchitecture/databases,general:products/amazon-rds,general:products/aws-govcloud-us</category>
            <author>aws@amazon.com</author>
            <link>
                https://aws.amazon.com/about-aws/whats-new/2026/01/amazon-rds-blue-green-deployments-reduces-downtime</link>
        </item>
        <item>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">aebb7760771723151c816e904ac1ced06613bf75</guid>
            <title>Amazon CloudWatch Database Insights on-demand analysis now available in four
                additional Regions</title>
            <description>&lt;p&gt;Amazon CloudWatch Database Insights expands the availability of
                its on-demand analysis experience to four additional Regions - Asia Pacific (New
                Zealand), Asia Pacific (Taipei), Asia Pacific (Thailand), and Mexico (Central).
                CloudWatch Database Insights is a monitoring and diagnostics solution that helps
                database administrators and developers optimize database performance by providing
                comprehensive visibility into database metrics, query analysis, and resource
                utilization patterns. This feature leverages machine learning models to help
                identify performance bottlenecks during the selected time period, and gives advice
                on what to do next.&lt;br&gt; &lt;br&gt; Previously, database administrators had to
                manually analyze performance data, correlate metrics, and investigate root cause.
                This process is time-consuming and requires deep database expertise. With this
                launch, you can now analyze database performance monitoring data for any time period
                with automated intelligence. The feature automatically compares your selected time
                period against normal baseline performance, identifies anomalies, and provides
                specific remediation advice. Through intuitive visualizations and clear
                explanations, you can quickly identify performance issues and receive step-by-step
                guidance for resolution. This automated analysis and recommendation system reduces
                mean-time-to-diagnosis from hours to minutes.&lt;br&gt; &lt;br&gt; You can get
                started with this feature by enabling the Advanced mode of CloudWatch Database
                Insights on your Amazon Aurora and Amazon RDS databases using the RDS service
                console, AWS APIs, the AWS SDK, or AWS CloudFormation. Please refer
                to&amp;nbsp;&lt;a
                href="https://docs.aws.amazon.com/AmazonRDS/latest/AuroraUserGuide/USER_PerfInsights.Overview.Engines.html#USER_PerfInsights.Overview.PIfeatureEngnRegSupport"
                target="_blank"&gt;Aurora documentation&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;or&amp;nbsp;&lt;a
                href="https://docs.aws.amazon.com/AmazonRDS/latest/UserGuide/USER_PerfInsights.Overview.Engines.html"
                target="_blank"&gt;RDS documentation&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;to get
                started.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
            <pubDate>Tue, 20 Jan 2026 14:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <category>general:products/amazon-rds,marketing:marchitecture/databases</category>
            <author>aws@amazon.com</author>
            <link>
                https://aws.amazon.com/about-aws/whats-new/2026/01/amazon-cloudwatch-database-insights-on-demand-analysis-available-additional-regions</link>
        </item>
        <item>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">98a2b76f72a1909b706f4fec358784e95007577a</guid>
            <title>Amazon EVS now supports VCF and VMware ESX software version selection</title>
            <description>&lt;p&gt;Amazon Elastic VMware Service (Amazon EVS) now supports the
                ability to specify supported combinations of VMware Cloud Foundation
                (VCF)&amp;nbsp;and ESX software versions when setting up your EVS environments and
                hosts.&lt;/p&gt;
                &lt;p&gt;Amazon EVS lets you run VCF natively within your Amazon Virtual Private
                Cloud (VPC), powered by AWS Nitro EC2 bare-metal instances. Amazon EVS automates
                deployment of a complete VCF environment in hours using either an intuitive
                step-by-step configuration workflow on the AWS console or the AWS Command Line
                Interface (CLI). This newest enhancement addresses the critical need for version
                flexibility to help you migrate workloads to AWS faster, reduce operational
                complexity and risk, and meet data center exit deadlines with Amazon EVS.&lt;/p&gt;
                &lt;p&gt;With software versioning support, you can now specify a VCF version when
                creating new environments using the CreateEnvironment API and select an ESX version
                when adding new hosts to existing environments using the CreateEnvironmentHost API.
                You can also query supported version combinations with the new GetVersions
                API.&amp;nbsp;As part of this capability, we're also adding support for new
                environment deployments with VCF 5.2.2.&lt;br&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
                &lt;p&gt;To get started, visit the Amazon EVS&amp;nbsp;&lt;a
                href="https://aws.amazon.com/evs/"&gt;product detail
                page&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;and&amp;nbsp;&lt;a
                href="https://docs.aws.amazon.com/evs/latest/userguide/what-is-evs.html"&gt;user
                guide&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
            <pubDate>Tue, 20 Jan 2026 08:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <category>marketing:marchitecture/migration,marketing:marchitecture/compute</category>
            <author>aws@amazon.com</author>
            <link>
                https://aws.amazon.com/about-aws/whats-new/2026/01/amazon-evs-vcf-vmware-esx-software-version</link>
        </item>
        <item>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">6c8e56fffb466c250e18ef8222db7a89b5a5c2aa</guid>
            <title>Amazon EC2 High Memory U7i instances now available in additional regions</title>
            <description>&lt;p&gt;Amazon EC2 High Memory U7i instances are available in new regions.
                U7i-6tb.112xlarge instances are now available in AWS Asia Pacific (Thailand, Sydney,
                Singapore), Canada (Central), and AWS GovCloud (US-East), u7i-8tb.112xlarge
                instances are now available in AWS South America (Sao Paulo), and
                u7in-16tb.224xlarge instances are now available in AWS GovCloud
                (US-East).&amp;nbsp;U7i instances are part of AWS 7th generation and are powered by
                custom fourth generation Intel Xeon Scalable Processors (Sapphire Rapids). U7i-6tb
                instances offer 6TiB of DDR5 memory, U7in-8tb instances&amp;nbsp;offer 8TiB of DDR5
                memory,&amp;nbsp;and U7in-16tb instances&amp;nbsp;offer&amp;nbsp;16TiB of DDR5
                memory,&amp;nbsp;enabling customers to scale transaction processing throughput in a
                fast-growing data environment.&lt;/p&gt;
                &lt;p&gt;U7i-6tb and U7i-8tb instances offer 448 vCPUs, support up to 100Gbps
                Elastic Block Storage (EBS) for faster data loading and backups, deliver up to
                100Gbps of network bandwidth, and support ENA Express.&amp;nbsp;U7in-16tb instances
                offer 896 vCPUs, support up to 100Gbps Elastic Block Storage (EBS) for faster data
                loading and backups, deliver up to 200Gbps of network bandwidth, and support ENA
                Express.&amp;nbsp;U7i instances are ideal for customers using mission-critical
                in-memory databases like SAP HANA, Oracle, and SQL Server.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
                &lt;p&gt;To learn more about U7i instances, visit the&amp;nbsp;&lt;a
                href="https://aws.amazon.com/ec2/instance-types/u7i/"&gt;High Memory instances
                page&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
            <pubDate>Fri, 16 Jan 2026 22:20:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <category>
                general:products/aws-govcloud-us,marketing:marchitecture/compute,general:products/amazon-ec2</category>
            <author>aws@amazon.com</author>
            <link>
                https://aws.amazon.com/about-aws/whats-new/2026/01/amazon-ec-high-memory-ui-instances-additional-regions/</link>
        </item>
        <item>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">53d570bc88d0672790b44a7701cf48f19db8440b</guid>
            <title>Amazon Bedrock Reserved Tier available now for Claude Opus 4.5 and Haiku 4.5</title>
            <description>&lt;p&gt;Today, Amazon Bedrock announces the expansion of the Reserved
                service tier designed for workloads requiring predictable performance and guaranteed
                tokens-per-minute capacity. The Reserved tier provides the ability to reserve
                prioritized compute capacity, keeping service levels predictable for your mission
                critical applications. It also includes the flexibility to allocate different input
                and output tokens-per-minute capacities to match the exact requirements of your
                workload and control cost. This is particularly valuable because many workloads have
                asymmetric token usage patterns. For instance, summarization tasks consume many
                input tokens but generate fewer output tokens, while content generation applications
                require less input and more output capacity. When your application needs more
                tokens-per-minute capacity than what you reserved , the service automatically
                overflows to the pay-as-you-go Standard tier, ensuring uninterrupted operations. The
                Reserved tier and is available today for Anthropic Claude Opus 4.5 and Claude Haiku
                4.5. Customers can reserve capacity for 1 month or 3 month duration. Customers pay a
                fixed price per 1K tokens-per-minute and are billed monthly.&lt;br&gt; &lt;br&gt;
                With the expansion of the Reserved service tier, Amazon Bedrock continues to provide
                more choice to customers, helping them develop, scale, and deploy applications and
                agents that improve productivity and customer experiences while balancing
                performance and cost requirements.&lt;br&gt; &lt;br&gt; For more information about
                the AWS Regions where Amazon Bedrock Reserved tier is available, refer to the&lt;a
                href="https://docs.aws.amazon.com/bedrock/latest/userguide/service-tiers-inference.html"&gt;
                Documentation&lt;/a&gt;. To get access to the Reserved tier, please contact your AWS
                account team.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
            <pubDate>Fri, 16 Jan 2026 18:30:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <category>
                marketing:marchitecture/artificial-intelligence,general:products/amazon-bedrock</category>
            <author>aws@amazon.com</author>
            <link>
                https://aws.amazon.com/about-aws/whats-new/2026/01/amazon-bedrock-reserved-tier-claude-opus-haiku/</link>
        </item>
        <item>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2fac5f6329257539dfc0067365a13f2044e0e616</guid>
            <title>Amazon MWAA now available in additional Region</title>
            <description>&lt;p&gt;Amazon Managed Workflows for Apache Airflow (MWAA) is now
                available in AWS Region&amp;nbsp;Asia Pacific (Thailand).&lt;br&gt; &lt;br&gt;
                Amazon MWAA is a managed service for Apache Airflow that lets you use the same
                familiar Apache Airflow platform as you do today to orchestrate your workflows and
                enjoy improved scalability, availability, and security without the operational
                burden of having to manage the underlying infrastructure. Learn more about using
                Amazon MWAA on the&amp;nbsp;&lt;a
                href="https://aws.amazon.com/managed-workflows-for-apache-airflow/"&gt;product
                page&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;br&gt; Please visit the&amp;nbsp;&lt;a
                href="https://aws.amazon.com/about-aws/global-infrastructure/regional-product-services/"&gt;AWS
                region table&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;for more information on AWS regions and services. To
                learn more about Amazon MWAA visit the&amp;nbsp;&lt;a
                href="https://docs.aws.amazon.com/mwaa/latest/userguide/what-is-mwaa.html"&gt;Amazon
                MWAA documentation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;br&gt; &lt;br&gt; &lt;i&gt;Apache, Apache Airflow,
                and Airflow are either registered trademarks or trademarks of the Apache Software
                Foundation in the United States and/or other countries.&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
            <pubDate>Fri, 16 Jan 2026 18:01:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <category>marketing:marchitecture/analytics,general:products/amazon-mwaa</category>
            <author>aws@amazon.com</author>
            <link>https://aws.amazon.com/about-aws/whats-new/2026/01/amazon-mwaa-additional-region</link>
        </item>
        <item>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">b50c950fc399393bd1efa1b754f5711fe93dd595</guid>
            <title>AWS Outposts racks support multiple LGW routing domains</title>
            <description>&lt;p&gt;AWS Outposts racks now support multiple local gateway (LGW)
                routing domains, enabling you to create up to 10 isolated routing domains per
                Outpost, each with independent route tables and BGP sessions to your on-premises
                network. This feature provides traffic separation between routing domains and
                enables both customer-owned IP (CoIP) and direct VPC routing (DVR) modes on the same
                Outpost.&lt;br&gt; &lt;br&gt; With multiple LGW routing domains, you can segment
                on-premises network connectivity for different departments or business units sharing
                an Outpost. Each routing domain maintains its own LGW VIF Group, LGW Route Table,
                and VPC associations, preventing traffic from crossing between domains. You can
                configure multiple LGW routing domains through the AWS Management Console or AWS
                CLI.&lt;br&gt; &lt;br&gt; Multiple LGW routing domains is available on
                second-generation Outposts racks at no additional charge. See the &lt;a
                href="https://aws.amazon.com/outposts/rack/faqs/"&gt;FAQs for Outposts
                racks&lt;/a&gt; for the latest list of supported AWS Regions.&lt;br&gt; &lt;br&gt;
                To learn more about implementation details and best practices, check out this &lt;a
                href="https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/compute/simplify-network-segmentation-for-aws-outposts-racks-with-multiple-local-gateway-routing-domains/"&gt;blog
                post&lt;/a&gt; or visit our &lt;a
                href="https://docs.aws.amazon.com/outposts/latest/network-userguide/routing-domains.html"&gt;technical
                documentation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
            <pubDate>Fri, 16 Jan 2026 17:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <category>marketing:marchitecture/migration,marketing:marchitecture/compute</category>
            <author>aws@amazon.com</author>
            <link>
                https://aws.amazon.com/about-aws/whats-new/2026/01/aws-outposts-multiple-lgw-routing-domain</link>
        </item>
        <item>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2bdf321aef8544d5c26f42043caa60745395e46a</guid>
            <title>Second-generation AWS Outposts racks are now supported in additional AWS Regions</title>
            <description>&lt;p&gt;Second-generation AWS Outposts racks are now supported in the
                South America (Sao Paulo) and Europe (Stockholm) Regions. Outposts racks extend AWS
                infrastructure, AWS services, APIs, and tools to virtually any on-premises data
                center or colocation space for a truly consistent hybrid experience.&lt;br&gt;
                &lt;br&gt; Organizations from startups to enterprises and the public sector in and
                outside of Europe and South America can now order their Outposts racks connected to
                these new supported regions, optimizing for their latency and data residency needs.
                Outposts allows customers to run workloads that need low latency access to
                on-premises systems locally while connecting back to their home Region for
                application management. Customers can also use Outposts and AWS services to manage
                and process data that needs to remain on-premises to meet data residency
                requirements. This regional expansion provides additional flexibility in the AWS
                Regions that customers’ Outposts can connect to.&lt;br&gt; &lt;br&gt; To learn more
                about second-generation Outposts racks, read &lt;a
                href="https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/aws/announcing-second-generation-aws-outposts-racks-with-breakthrough-performance-and-scalability-on-premises/"&gt;&lt;u&gt;this
                blog post&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a
                href="https://docs.aws.amazon.com/outposts/latest/network-userguide/what-is-outposts.html"&gt;&lt;u&gt;user
                guide&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt;. For the most updated list of countries and territories
                and the AWS Regions where second-generation Outposts racks are supported, check out
                the &lt;a href="https://aws.amazon.com/outposts/rack/faqs/"&gt;&lt;u&gt;Outposts
                rack FAQs page&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
            <pubDate>Fri, 16 Jan 2026 15:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <category>
                marketing:marchitecture/storage,general:products/aws-outposts,marketing:marchitecture/networking,marketing:marchitecture/compute</category>
            <author>aws@amazon.com</author>
            <link>
                https://aws.amazon.com/about-aws/whats-new/2026/01/second-generation-aws-outposts-racks-additional-aws-regions</link>
        </item>
        <item>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">bf19d8829336e8883483e829505d051ec9f7dddc</guid>
            <title>Amazon S3 Storage Lens is now available in AWS GovCloud (US) Regions</title>
            <description>&lt;p&gt;Amazon S3 Storage Lens provides organization-wide visibility into
                your storage usage and activity. S3 Storage Lens is now available in AWS GovCloud
                (US) Regions, bringing metrics to help you optimize storage costs, identify data
                protection opportunities, and improve application performance.&lt;br&gt; &lt;br&gt;
                S3 Storage Lens provides a single view of object storage usage and activity across
                thousands of accounts in an organization, with drill-downs to generate insights at
                multiple aggregation levels. You can optimize storage costs by identifying prefixes
                with incomplete multipart uploads or buckets accumulating non-current object
                versions. You can identify buckets that don’t follow your data protection best
                practices, such as using S3 Cross-Region Replication to replicate data across AWS
                Regions or S3 Versioning to keep multiple versions of an object. With the newly
                added performance metrics, you can identify application performance constraints—for
                example, using request and object size distribution metrics to detect inefficient
                access patterns or tracking cross-Region data transfer to reduce latency and
                costs.&lt;br&gt; &lt;br&gt; Amazon S3 Storage Lens is available in all AWS Regions.
                S3 Storage Lens is pre-configured to receive free metrics by default for all
                customers and 14 days of historical data. For more detailed visibility with up to 15
                months data retention, you can upgrade to S3 Storage Lens advanced metrics. To learn
                more about S3 Storage Lens metrics, including free and advanced metrics, refer to
                the &lt;a
                href="https://docs.aws.amazon.com/AmazonS3/latest/userguide/storage_lens_metrics_glossary.html"
                target="_blank"&gt;documentation&lt;/a&gt;. For S3 Storage Lens Advanced pricing
                details, visit the &lt;a href="https://aws.amazon.com/s3/pricing/"
                target="_blank"&gt;Amazon S3 pricing page&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
            <pubDate>Fri, 16 Jan 2026 14:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <category>
                general:products/aws-govcloud-us,general:products/amazon-s3,marketing:marchitecture/storage</category>
            <author>aws@amazon.com</author>
            <link>
                https://aws.amazon.com/about-aws/whats-new/2026/01/s3-storage-lens-aws-govcloud-us-regions/</link>
        </item>
        <item>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">8a62879b5a878cfd5924dcfd6946c6a224b99a1d</guid>
            <title>Amazon S3 on Outposts is now available on second-generation AWS Outposts racks</title>
            <description>&lt;p&gt;Amazon S3 on Outposts is now available on second-generation AWS
                Outposts racks for your data residency, low latency, and local data processing use
                cases on-premises. S3 on Outposts on second-generation Outposts racks offers three
                storage tiers: 196 TB, 490 TB, and 786 TB. Choose the storage tier that matches your
                workload, whether for production workloads, backups, or archival
                workloads.&lt;br&gt; &lt;br&gt; With S3 on Outposts, you can store, secure,
                retrieve, and control access to your data using familiar S3 APIs and features. AWS
                Outposts is a fully managed service that extends AWS infrastructure, services, and
                tools to virtually any data center, co-location space, or on-premises facility for a
                consistent hybrid experience.&lt;br&gt; &lt;br&gt; S3 on Outposts on
                second-generation Outposts racks is available in all AWS Regions and
                countries/territories where these &lt;a href="https://aws.amazon.com/outposts/faqs/"
                target="_blank"&gt;racks are available&lt;/a&gt;. To learn more, visit the &lt;a
                href="https://aws.amazon.com/s3/outposts/" target="_blank"&gt;S3 on Outposts
                page&lt;/a&gt; or read our &lt;a
                href="https://docs.aws.amazon.com/AmazonS3/latest/dev/S3onOutposts.html"
                target="_blank"&gt;documentation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
            <pubDate>Thu, 15 Jan 2026 20:23:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <category>
                general:products/aws-outposts,marketing:marchitecture/storage,marketing:marchitecture/compute,general:products/amazon-s3</category>
            <author>aws@amazon.com</author>
            <link>
                https://aws.amazon.com/about-aws/whats-new/2026/01/amazon-s3-second-generation-aws-outposts-racks</link>
        </item>
        <item>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">a068903fec30cae59dbc7718cc3238ef8fff50be</guid>
            <title>AWS Deadline Cloud now supports machine learning training using Foundry Nuke
                CopyCat</title>
            <description>&lt;p&gt;Today, AWS Deadline Cloud announces integration with Foundry Nuke
                CopyCat, allowing you to run machine learning training jobs for visual effects in
                the cloud. AWS Deadline Cloud is a fully managed service that simplifies render
                management for computer-generated 2D/3D graphics and visual effects for films, TV
                shows, commercials, games, and industrial design.&lt;br&gt; &lt;br&gt; CopyCat
                learns visual effects, such as color corrections, beauty finishes, or deblurring,
                from a set of adjusted frames and automatically applies these adjustments across
                entire sequences. Instead of cleaning up frames one by one, you can fix a handful of
                representative frames and CopyCat will automatically apply these changes to the rest
                of your footage, saving you significant amounts of valuable time. With this
                integration, you can now train models by submitting CopyCat training jobs directly
                to your Deadline Cloud render farm. This gives you the ability to scale and run
                multiple training workloads in parallel while freeing up your artist workstations
                for creative work. You can monitor and track training jobs alongside other render
                jobs through the Deadline Cloud interface for one simple view across an entire
                project.&lt;br&gt; &lt;br&gt; AWS Deadline Cloud with Nuke CopyCat integration is
                available in all AWS Regions where AWS Deadline Cloud is supported. To get started,
                visit our &lt;a
                href="https://aws-deadline.github.io/nuke/using-submitter/copycat-submissions/"&gt;CopyCat
                integration user guide.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
            <pubDate>Thu, 15 Jan 2026 19:50:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <category>general:products/aws-deadline-cloud,marketing:marchitecture/media-services</category>
            <author>aws@amazon.com</author>
            <link>
                https://aws.amazon.com/about-aws/whats-new/2026/01/aws-deadline-cloud-machine-learning-training</link>
        </item>
        <item>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">e2afdecd9d55133474c5e073b32fe614bf0d851c</guid>
            <title>AWS Clean Rooms now supports parameters in PySpark analysis templates</title>
            <description>&lt;p&gt;AWS Clean Rooms announces support for parameters in PySpark
                analysis templates, offering increased flexibility for organizations and their
                partners to scale their privacy-enhanced data collaboration use cases. With this
                launch, you can create a single &lt;a
                href="https://docs.aws.amazon.com/clean-rooms/latest/userguide/pyspark-analysis-templates.html"
                target="_blank"&gt;PySpark analysis template&lt;/a&gt; that allows different values
                to be provided by the Clean Rooms collaborator running a job at submission time
                without modifying the template code. With parameters in PySpark analysis templates,
                the code author creates a PySpark template with parameters support, and if approved
                to run, the job runner submits parameter values directly to the PySpark job. For
                example, a measurement company running attribution analysis for advertising
                campaigns can input time windows and geographic regions dynamically to surface
                insights that drive campaign optimizations and media planning accelerating
                time-to-insights.&lt;/p&gt;
                &lt;p&gt;&lt;br&gt; With AWS Clean Rooms, customers can create a secure data clean
                room in minutes and collaborate with any company on AWS or Snowflake to generate
                unique insights about advertising campaigns, investment decisions, and research and
                development. For more information about the AWS Regions where AWS Clean Rooms is
                available, see the &lt;a
                href="https://docs.aws.amazon.com/general/latest/gr/clean-rooms.html#clean-rooms_region"
                target="_blank"&gt;AWS Regions&lt;/a&gt; table. To learn more about collaborating
                with AWS Clean Rooms, visit &lt;a href="https://aws.amazon.com/clean-rooms/"
                target="_blank"&gt;AWS Clean Rooms&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
            <pubDate>Thu, 15 Jan 2026 18:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <category>general:products/aws-clean-rooms,marketing:marchitecture/analytics</category>
            <author>aws@amazon.com</author>
            <link>
                https://aws.amazon.com/about-aws/whats-new/2026/01/aws-clean-rooms-parameters-pyspark-analysis-templates/</link>
        </item>
        <item>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">f897e9439604674eb2c74b71525a459f07128384</guid>
            <title>AWS Databases are now available on v0 by Vercel</title>
            <description>&lt;p&gt;Amazon Aurora PostgreSQL, Amazon Aurora DSQL, and Amazon DynamoDB
                serverless databases are now available on v0 by Vercel, an AI-powered tool that
                transforms your ideas into production-ready, full-stack web applications in minutes.
                With this launch, you can build your ideas as well as create and connect to AWS
                databases from v0 using natural language prompts.&lt;br&gt; &lt;br&gt; To get
                started, simply describe what you want to build in v0. The tool takes care of
                developing the frontend user interface and backend logic, storing your application
                data in the AWS database that best meets your application needs. v0 provides an
                end-to-end setup experience where you can choose and configure database resources
                under a new AWS account or link to an existing account, all without leaving v0
                interface. New AWS accounts from Vercel include access to all three databases and
                $100 USD in credits that can be used with any of the database options for up to six
                months. You can also manage your plan, add payment information, and view usage
                details anytime by visiting the AWS settings portal from the Vercel dashboard. To
                learn more, visit &lt;a href="http://v0.app" target="_blank"&gt;v0&lt;/a&gt; or the
                &lt;a href="https://vercel.com/marketplace/aws" target="_blank"&gt;AWS landing
                page&lt;/a&gt; on the Vercel Marketplace.&lt;br&gt; &lt;br&gt; The serverless
                options for &lt;a href="https://aws.amazon.com/rds/aurora/"
                target="_blank"&gt;Amazon Aurora PostgreSQL&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a
                href="https://aws.amazon.com/rds/aurora/dsql/" target="_blank"&gt;Amazon Aurora
                DSQL&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href="https://aws.amazon.com/dynamodb/?nc2=type_a"
                target="_blank"&gt;Amazon DynamoDB&lt;/a&gt; do not require infrastructure
                management and reduce costs by scaling down to zero automatically when not in use.
                You can create a database in the following &lt;a
                href="https://aws.amazon.com/about-aws/global-infrastructure/regional-product-services/"
                target="_blank"&gt;AWS Regions&lt;/a&gt;: US East (N. Virginia), US East (Ohio), US
                West (Oregon), Europe (Ireland), Europe (Frankfurt), Asia Pacific (Tokyo), and Asia
                Pacific (Mumbai).&lt;br&gt; &lt;br&gt; AWS Databases deliver security, reliability,
                and price performance without the operational overhead, whether you're prototyping
                your next big idea or running production AI and data driven applications. For more
                information, visit the &lt;a href="https://aws.amazon.com/products/databases/"
                target="_blank"&gt;AWS Databases webpage.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
            <pubDate>Thu, 15 Jan 2026 18:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <category>
                marketing:marchitecture/databases,general:products/amazon-dynamodb,general:products/amazon-aurora</category>
            <author>aws@amazon.com</author>
            <link>
                https://aws.amazon.com/about-aws/whats-new/2026/01/aws-databases-available-vercel-v0/</link>
        </item>
        <item>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">b2f0eb5f93257bab300772d7d0eeed4e01b11382</guid>
            <title>Announcing Amazon EC2 Memory optimized X8i instances</title>
            <description>&lt;p&gt;Amazon Web Services (AWS) is announcing the general availability
                of Amazon EC2 X8i instances, next-generation memory optimized instances powered by
                custom Intel Xeon 6 processors available only on AWS. X8i instances are
                SAP-certified and deliver the highest performance and fastest memory bandwidth among
                comparable Intel processors in the cloud. They deliver up to 43% higher performance,
                1.5x more memory capacity (up to 6TB), and 3.4x more memory bandwidth compared to
                previous generation X2i instances.&lt;br&gt; &lt;br&gt; X8i instances are designed
                for memory-intensive workloads like SAP HANA, large databases, data analytics, and
                Electronic Design Automation (EDA). Compared to X2i instances, X8i instances offer
                up to 50% higher SAPS performance, up to 47% faster PostgreSQL performance, 88%
                faster Memcached performance, and 46% faster AI inference performance. X8i instances
                come in 14 sizes, from large to 96xlarge, including two bare metal
                options.&lt;br&gt; &lt;br&gt; X8i instances are available in the following &lt;a
                href="https://aws.amazon.com/about-aws/global-infrastructure/regional-product-services/"&gt;AWS
                Regions&lt;/a&gt;: US East (N. Virginia), US East (Ohio), US West (Oregon), and
                Europe (Frankfurt).&lt;br&gt; &lt;br&gt; To get started, visit the &lt;a
                href="https://aws.amazon.com/console/"&gt;AWS Management Console&lt;/a&gt;. X8i
                instances can be purchased via Savings Plans, On-Demand instances, and Spot
                instances. For more information visit &lt;a
                href="https://aws.amazon.com/ec2/instance-types/x8i/"&gt;X8i instances
                page&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
            <pubDate>Thu, 15 Jan 2026 16:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <category>general:products/amazon-ec2,marketing:marchitecture/compute</category>
            <author>aws@amazon.com</author>
            <link>
                https://aws.amazon.com/about-aws/whats-new/2026/01/aws-amazon-ec2-x8i-generally-available</link>
        </item>
        <item>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">43c21cf9f510aafdc704f5c6396385eb07c285ca</guid>
            <title>Amazon Connect now provides agent scheduling metrics in data lake</title>
            <description>
                &lt;p&gt;Amazon Connect now provides agent scheduling metrics in data lake,
                making it easier for you to generate reports and insights from this data. For
                example, after publishing schedules for next month, you can access interval level
                (15 minutes or 30 minutes) metrics such as forecasted headcount, scheduled
                headcount, and projected service level in Connect analytics data lake. You can view
                aggregated metrics for an entire business unit (forecast group) or broken down by
                specific demand segments (demand groups). You can then visualize this data in Amazon
                Quick Sight or another BI tool of your choice for further analysis, such as
                identifying periods of over or under-staffing. This eliminates the need for manual
                reviews of agent schedules thus improving productivity for schedulers and
                supervisors.&lt;br&gt; &lt;br&gt; This feature is available in all &lt;a
                href="https://docs.aws.amazon.com/connect/latest/adminguide/regions.html#optimization_region"&gt;AWS
                Regions&lt;/a&gt; where Amazon Connect agent scheduling is available. To learn more
                about Amazon Connect agent scheduling, click &lt;a
                href="https://docs.aws.amazon.com/connect/latest/adminguide/forecasting-capacity-planning-scheduling.html"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
            <pubDate>Thu, 15 Jan 2026 16:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <category>
                marketing:marchitecture/contact-center,general:products/aws-govcloud-us,general:products/amazon-connect,marketing:marchitecture/business-productivity</category>
            <author>aws@amazon.com</author>
            <link>
                https://aws.amazon.com/about-aws/whats-new/2026/01/amazon-connect-scheduling-metrics/</link>
        </item>
        <item>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2973e24efca02117e251fe8007ae6e1e22438ffc</guid>
            <title>Amazon RDS now supports the latest CU and GDR updates for Microsoft SQL Server</title>
            <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://aws.amazon.com/rds/sqlserver/"
                target="_blank"&gt;Amazon Relational Database Service (Amazon RDS) for SQL Server
                &lt;/a&gt;now supports the latest General Distribution Release (GDR) updates for
                Microsoft SQL Server. This release includes support for Microsoft SQL Server 2016
                SP3+GDR &lt;a href="https://support.microsoft.com/help/5068401"
                target="_blank"&gt;KB5068401&lt;/a&gt; (RDS version 13.00.6475.1.v1), SQL Server
                2017 CU31+GDR &lt;a href="https://support.microsoft.com/help/5068402"
                target="_blank"&gt;KB5068402&lt;/a&gt; (RDS version 14.00.3515.1.v1), SQL Server
                2019 CU32+GDR &lt;a href="https://support.microsoft.com/help/5068404"
                target="_blank"&gt;KB5068404&lt;/a&gt; (RDS version 15.00.4455.2.v1) and SQL Server
                2022 CU22 &lt;a
                href="https://learn.microsoft.com/en-us/troubleshoot/sql/releases/sqlserver-2022/cumulativeupdate22"
                target="_blank"&gt;KB5068450&lt;/a&gt; (RDS version 16.00.4225.2.v1).&lt;br&gt;
                &lt;br&gt; The GDR updates address vulnerabilities described in CVE-2025-59499. For
                additional information on the improvements and fixes included in these updates, see
                Microsoft documentation for KB5068401, KB5068402, KB5068404, KB5068450. We recommend
                that you upgrade your Amazon RDS for SQL Server instances to apply these updates
                using Amazon RDS Management Console, or by using the AWS SDK or CLI. You can learn
                more about upgrading your database instance in the &lt;a
                href="https://docs.aws.amazon.com/AmazonRDS/latest/UserGuide/USER_UpgradeDBInstance.SQLServer.html"
                target="_blank"&gt;Amazon RDS SQL Server User Guide for upgrading your RDS Microsoft
                SQL Server DB engine&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
            <pubDate>Thu, 15 Jan 2026 15:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <category>
                general:products/amazon-rds,marketing:marchitecture/databases,general:products/aws-govcloud-us</category>
            <author>aws@amazon.com</author>
            <link>
                https://aws.amazon.com/about-aws/whats-new/2026/01/amazon-rds-cu-gdr-updates-microsoft-sql-server</link>
        </item>
        <item>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">6316cc254b3d315f41ddd63ced9b886b19bb3d37</guid>
            <title>AWS Lambda announces cross-account access for DynamoDB Streams</title>
            <description>
                &lt;p&gt;AWS Lambda now supports cross-account access for Amazon DynamoDB
                Streams event-source mappings (ESMs), enabling you to trigger Lambda functions in
                one account from DynamoDB Streams in another account.&lt;br&gt; &lt;br&gt; Customers
                build event-driven applications using Lambda's fully-managed DynamoDB Streams ESMs,
                which poll change events from DynamoDB tables and trigger your Lambda functions.
                Organizations implementing multi-account architectures—whether to centralize event
                processing or share events with partner teams—previously needed to build complex
                data replication solutions to share data across accounts, which added operational
                overhead. With this launch, you can now provide cross-account access to your
                DynamoDB Streams to trigger Lambda functions in another account. By setting a &lt;a
                href="https://docs.aws.amazon.com/amazondynamodb/latest/developerguide/access-control-resource-based.html"&gt;resource-based
                policy&lt;/a&gt; on your DynamoDB stream, you can enable a Lambda function in one
                account to access a DynamoDB stream in another account. This capability allows you
                to simplify your streaming applications across accounts without the overhead of
                replication solutions in each account.&lt;br&gt; &lt;br&gt; This feature is
                generally available in all &lt;a
                href="https://aws.amazon.com/about-aws/global-infrastructure/regional-product-services/"&gt;AWS
                Commercial and AWS GovCloud (US) Regions&lt;/a&gt;. You can enable cross-account
                Lambda triggers by creating resource-based policies for your DynamoDB Streams using
                the AWS Management Console, AWS CLI, AWS SDKs, AWS CloudFormation, or AWS APIs. To
                learn more, read Lambda ESM &lt;a
                href="https://docs.aws.amazon.com/lambda/latest/dg/services-dynamodb-eventsourcemapping.html#services-dynamodb-eventsourcemapping-cross-account"&gt;documentation&lt;/a&gt;.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
            <pubDate>Thu, 15 Jan 2026 15:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <category>
                general:products/aws-govcloud-us,marketing:marchitecture/serverless,general:products/aws-lambda</category>
            <author>aws@amazon.com</author>
            <link>
                https://aws.amazon.com/about-aws/whats-new/2026/01/aws-lambda-cross-account-access-dynamodb-streams</link>
        </item>
        <item>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">f0142142732b1c17bdaceb21564b861eeae519e4</guid>
            <title>Amazon RDS Custom now supports the latest GDR updates for Microsoft SQL Server</title>
            <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://aws.amazon.com/rds/custom/"
                target="_blank"&gt;Amazon Relational Database Service (Amazon RDS) Custom for SQL
                Server&lt;/a&gt; now supports the latest General Distribution Release (GDR) updates
                for Microsoft SQL Server. This release includes support for SQL Server 2019 CU32+GDR
                &lt;a href="https://support.microsoft.com/help/5068404"
                target="_blank"&gt;KB5068404&lt;/a&gt; (RDS version 15.00.4455.2.v1) and SQL Server
                2022 CU21+GDR &lt;a href="https://support.microsoft.com/help/5068406"
                target="_blank"&gt;KB5068406&lt;/a&gt; (RDS version 16.00.4222.2.v1).&lt;br&gt;
                &lt;br&gt; The GDR updates address vulnerabilities described in CVE-2025-59499. For
                additional information on the improvements and fixes included in these updates, see
                Microsoft documentation for KB5068404 and KB5068406. We recommend that you upgrade
                your Amazon RDS Custom for SQL Server instances to apply these updates using Amazon
                RDS Management Console, or by using the AWS SDK or CLI. You can learn more about
                upgrading your database instance in the &lt;a
                href="https://docs.aws.amazon.com/AmazonRDS/latest/UserGuide/custom-upgrading-sqlserver.html"
                target="_blank"&gt;Amazon RDS Custom User Guide&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
            <pubDate>Thu, 15 Jan 2026 15:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <category>general:products/amazon-rds,marketing:marchitecture/databases</category>
            <author>aws@amazon.com</author>
            <link>
                https://aws.amazon.com/about-aws/whats-new/2026/01/amazon-rds-custom-gdr-updates-microsoft-sql-server</link>
        </item>
        <item>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">65cf78f9d44babd10a8b4ea2a3fda343a6f45e90</guid>
            <title>Amazon Redshift Serverless adds queue-based query resource management</title>
            <description>&lt;p&gt;Amazon Redshift Serverless introduces queue-based query resource
                management. You can create dedicated query queues with customized monitoring rules
                for different workloads. This feature provides granular control over resource usage.
                Queues let you set metrics-based predicates and automated responses. For example,
                you can configure rules to automatically abort queries that exceed time limits or
                consume too many resources.&lt;br&gt; &lt;br&gt; Previously, Query Monitoring Rules
                (QMR) were applied only at the Redshift Serverless workgroup level, affecting all
                queries run in this workgroup uniformly. The new queue-based approach lets you
                create queues with distinct monitoring rules. You can assign these queues to
                specific user roles and query groups. Each queue operates independently, with rules
                affecting only the queries within that queue. The available monitoring metrics can
                be found in &lt;a
                href="https://docs.aws.amazon.com/redshift/latest/dg/cm-c-wlm-query-monitoring-rules.html#cm-c-wlm-query-monitoring-metrics-serverless"
                target="_blank"&gt;Query monitoring metrics for Amazon Redshift
                Serverless&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;br&gt; &lt;br&gt; This feature is available in all &lt;a
                href="https://aws.amazon.com/about-aws/global-infrastructure/regional-product-services/"
                target="_blank"&gt;AWS regions&lt;/a&gt; that support Amazon Redshift Serverless.
                You can manage QMR with queues through the AWS Console and Redshift APIs.&lt;br&gt;
                &lt;br&gt; For implementation details, see the &lt;a
                href="https://docs.aws.amazon.com/redshift/latest/mgmt/serverless-workgroup-query-limits.html"
                target="_blank"&gt;documentation&lt;/a&gt; in the Amazon Redshift management
                guide.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
            <pubDate>Thu, 15 Jan 2026 14:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <category>
                marketing:marchitecture/serverless,general:products/amazon-redshift,marketing:marchitecture/analytics</category>
            <author>aws@amazon.com</author>
            <link>
                https://aws.amazon.com/about-aws/whats-new/2026/01/amazon-redshift-serverless-queue-based-query-resource-management</link>
        </item>
        <item>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">ef763717e27b61f7846fa570b3fc0178b472b743</guid>
            <title>Amazon EBS now supports up to four Elastic Volumes modifications in 24 hours</title>
            <description>&lt;p&gt;Amazon Elastic Block Store (EBS) now supports up to four Elastic
                Volumes modifications per volume within a rolling 24-hour window. Elastic Volumes
                modifications allow you to increase the size, change the type, and adjust the
                performance of your EBS volumes. With this update, you can start a new modification
                immediately after the previous one completes, as long as you have initiated fewer
                than four modifications in the past 24 hours.&lt;/p&gt;
                &lt;p&gt;This enhancement improves your operational agility to immediately scale
                storage capacity or adjust performance in response to sudden data growth or
                unanticipated workload spikes. With Elastic Volumes modifications, you can modify
                your volumes without detaching them or restarting your instances, allowing your
                application to continue running with minimal performance impact.&lt;/p&gt;
                &lt;p&gt;This feature is available in all commercial AWS Regions, the AWS GovCloud
                (US) Regions, and the China Regions. This capability is automatically enabled
                without requiring changes to your existing workflows. To learn more,
                see&amp;nbsp;&lt;a
                href="https://docs.aws.amazon.com/ebs/latest/userguide/ebs-modify-volume.html"&gt;Modify
                an Amazon EBS volume using Elastic Volumes operations&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;in the
                Amazon EBS User Guide.&lt;br&gt; &lt;/p&gt;</description>
            <pubDate>Thu, 15 Jan 2026 14:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <category>
                general:products/aws-govcloud-us,marketing:marchitecture/storage,general:products/amazon-elastic-block-store</category>
            <author>aws@amazon.com</author>
            <link>
                https://aws.amazon.com/about-aws/whats-new/2026/01/amazon-ebs-up-to-four-volume-modifications/</link>
        </item>
        <item>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">1dba797a7929cde14d5fede0c5db5e82467dd465</guid>
            <title>AWS Data Exports adds granular operation visibility for Amazon Bedrock model
                usage</title>
            <description>&lt;p&gt;AWS Data Exports now enables customers to distinguish between
                Amazon Bedrock operation types in their cost reports for enhanced cost analysis and
                optimization. This granular operation information is available in Cost and Usage
                Reports (CUR), CUR 2.0, and Data Exports for FOCUS, and is particularly valuable for
                FinOps teams, cost optimization professionals, and organizations using Amazon
                Bedrock that require detailed billing analysis.&lt;br&gt; &lt;br&gt; Customers will
                now see specific operation types such as "InvokeModelInference" and
                "InvokeModelStreamingInference" in their cost reports, replacing generic "Usage"
                labels. These granular operation types appear in the "line_item_operation" column in
                Legacy CUR and CUR 2.0 reports, the "x_Operation" column in FOCUS reports, and AWS
                Cost Explorer API Operation dimension values. This visibility now extends to all
                foundation models on Amazon Bedrock, enabling precise tracking of usage patterns and
                cost optimization opportunities across all model providers.&lt;br&gt; &lt;br&gt; To
                learn more about AWS Billing and Cost Management, visit the &lt;a
                href="https://docs.aws.amazon.com/awsaccountbilling/latest/aboutv2/billing-what-is.html"&gt;AWS
                Billing and Cost Management documentation&lt;/a&gt;, and for AWS Data Exports, visit
                the &lt;a
                href="https://docs.aws.amazon.com/cur/latest/userguide/what-is-data-exports.html"&gt;AWS
                Data Exports documentation&lt;/a&gt;. To get started with Amazon Bedrock, visit the
                &lt;a href="https://aws.amazon.com/bedrock/"&gt;Amazon Bedrock page&lt;/a&gt; and
                see the &lt;a
                href="https://docs.aws.amazon.com/bedrock/latest/userguide/models-regions.html"&gt;Amazon
                Bedrock documentation&lt;/a&gt; for more details.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
            <pubDate>Thu, 15 Jan 2026 08:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <category>marketing:marchitecture/cost-management,general:products/amazon-bedrock</category>
            <author>aws@amazon.com</author>
            <link>
                https://aws.amazon.com/about-aws/whats-new/2026/01/amazon-bedrock-granular-usage-visibility</link>
        </item>
        <item>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">44e6a38fe29e21a926f5b8dc6d25170b6b78bac6</guid>
            <title>Amazon VPC Route Server now available in new regions</title>
            <description>&lt;p&gt;Amazon VPC Route Server is now available in 16 new regions in
                addition to the 14 existing ones.&lt;br&gt; &lt;br&gt; VPC Route Server simplifies
                dynamic routing between virtual appliances in your Amazon VPC. It allows you to
                advertise routing information through Border Gateway Protocol (BGP) from virtual
                appliances and dynamically update the VPC route tables associated with subnets and
                internet gateway.&lt;br&gt; &lt;br&gt; With this launch, Amazon VPC Route Server is
                available in 30 AWS Regions: US East (Virginia), US East (Ohio), US West (Oregon),
                Europe (Ireland), Europe (Frankfurt), Asia Pacific (Tokyo), US West (N. California),
                Canada West (Calgary), Asia Pacific (Malaysia), Europe (Milan), Europe (Paris), Asia
                Pacific (Sydney), Europe (London), Canada (Central), Mexico
                (Central),&amp;nbsp;South America (Sao Paulo),Asia Pacific (Seoul), Europe (Zurich),
                Europe (Stockholm), Middle East (UAE), Israel (Tel Aviv), Asia Pacific (Taipei),
                Asia Pacific (New Zealand), Asia Pacific (Melbourne), Middle East (Bahrain), Asia
                Pacific (Jakarta), Africa (Cape Town), Asia Pacific (Hong Kong), Asia Pacific
                (Osaka) and Asia Pacific (Thailand). To learn more about Amazon VPC Route Server,
                visit this &lt;a
                href="https://docs.aws.amazon.com/vpc/latest/userguide/route-server-how-it-works.html"
                target="_blank"&gt;page&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
            <pubDate>Wed, 14 Jan 2026 18:41:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <category>
                marketing:marchitecture/networking-and-content-delivery,general:products/amazon-virtual-private-cloud,general:products/amazon-vpc</category>
            <author>aws@amazon.com</author>
            <link>
                https://aws.amazon.com/about-aws/whats-new/2026/01/amazon-vpc-route-server-available-new-regions</link>
        </item>
        <item>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">894b7c282c886cc54a3ab42276ed52c49658be86</guid>
            <title>Amazon VPC IPAM policies now support RDS and Application Load Balancers</title>
            <description>&lt;p&gt;Amazon Virtual Private Cloud (VPC) IP Address Manager (IPAM) now
                supports policies for Amazon Relational Database Service (RDS) instances and
                Application Load Balancers (ALB). This feature enables IP administrators to
                centrally configure and enforce IP allocation strategies for these resources,
                improving operational posture and simplifying network and security
                management.&lt;br&gt; &lt;br&gt; Using IPAM policies, IP administrators can
                centrally define public IP allocation rules for AWS resources, such as RDS
                instances, Application Load Balancers and Network Address Translation (NAT) Gateways
                when used in regional availability mode, and Elastic IP addresses. The IP allocation
                policy configured centrally cannot be superseded by individual application teams,
                ensuring compliance at all times. Before this feature, IP administrators had to
                educate database administrators and application developers about IP allocation
                requirements for RDS instances and Application Load Balancers, and rely on them to
                always comply with best practices. Now, you can add IP-based filters for RDS and ALB
                traffic in your networking and security constructs like access control lists, route
                tables, security groups, and firewalls, with confidence that public IPv4 address
                assignments to these resources always come from specific IPAM pools.&lt;br&gt;
                &lt;br&gt; The feature is available in all AWS commercial regions and the AWS
                GovCloud (US) Regions, in both Free Tier and Advanced Tier of VPC IPAM. When used
                with the Advanced Tier of VPC IPAM, customers can set policies across AWS accounts
                and AWS regions. To get started please see the &lt;a
                href="https://docs.aws.amazon.com/vpc/latest/ipam/define-public-ipv4-allocation-strategy-with-ipam-policies.html"
                target="_blank"&gt;IPAM policies documentation page&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;br&gt; &lt;br&gt;
                To learn more about IPAM, view the &lt;a
                href="https://docs.aws.amazon.com/vpc/latest/ipam/what-it-is-ipam.html"
                target="_blank"&gt;IPAM documentation&lt;/a&gt;. For details on pricing, refer to
                the IPAM tab on the &lt;a href="https://www.amazonaws.cn/en/vpc/pricing/"
                target="_blank"&gt;Amazon VPC Pricing Page&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
            <pubDate>Wed, 14 Jan 2026 17:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <category>
                general:products/aws-govcloud-us,marketing:marchitecture/networking-and-content-delivery,general:products/amazon-vpc</category>
            <author>aws@amazon.com</author>
            <link>
                https://aws.amazon.com/about-aws/whats-new/2026/01/amazon-vpc-ipam-policies-rds-alb/</link>
        </item>
        <item>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">b3c78d9d59145881c414215e7423f6b4a80fa5ba</guid>
            <title>Amazon Bedrock introduces API keys to streamline development in GovCloud regions</title>
            <description>&lt;p&gt;API keys for Amazon Bedrock are now available in AWS GovCloud (US)
                regions, expanding a feature that simplifies authentication and accelerates
                generative AI development. Originally launched in commercial AWS regions in July
                2025, API keys for Amazon Bedrock enable developers to quickly generate access
                credentials directly within the Amazon Bedrock console or AWS SDK without needing to
                manually configure IAM principals and policies.&lt;br&gt; &lt;br&gt; With the
                introduction of API keys for Amazon Bedrock, developers can generate short-term and
                long-term API keys directly from the Amazon Bedrock console or API to authenticate
                API calls to Amazon Bedrock models. Short-term API keys are valid for the duration
                of your console session, or up to 12 hours, whichever is shorter. Long-term API keys
                give you the flexibility to define key validity duration and manage the keys from
                the AWS IAM console.&lt;br&gt; &lt;br&gt; Bedrock API key authentication is now
                available in the AWS GovCloud (US) and commercial &lt;a
                href="https://aws.amazon.com/about-aws/global-infrastructure/regional-product-services/?p=ngi&amp;amp;loc=4"&gt;AWS
                Regions&lt;/a&gt; where Amazon Bedrock is available.&lt;br&gt; &lt;br&gt; To learn
                more about API keys in Amazon Bedrock, visit the&lt;a
                href="https://docs.aws.amazon.com/bedrock/latest/userguide/api-keys.html"&gt; API
                Keys documentation&lt;/a&gt; in the &lt;a
                href="https://docs.aws.amazon.com/bedrock/latest/userguide/getting-started.html"&gt;Amazon
                Bedrock user guide&lt;/a&gt;, or check out our &lt;a
                href="https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/machine-learning/accelerate-ai-development-with-amazon-bedrock-api-keys/"&gt;blog&lt;/a&gt;
                for code snippets and implementation examples.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
            <pubDate>Wed, 14 Jan 2026 17:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <category>
                marketing:marchitecture/artificial-intelligence,general:products/amazon-bedrock,general:products/aws-govcloud-us</category>
            <author>aws@amazon.com</author>
            <link>
                https://aws.amazon.com/about-aws/whats-new/2025/12/amazon-bedrock-api-keys-streamline-development-govcloud/</link>
        </item>
        <item>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">d63224ec313803cf29066e4b3db7846bfb191191</guid>
            <title>AWS IoT Device Management launches Wi-Fi Simple Setup for managed integrations</title>
            <description>&lt;p&gt;AWS IoT Device Management now offers Wi-Fi Simple Setup (WSS) for
                managed integrations, enabling developers to implement simplified Wi-Fi provisioning
                in Internet of Things (IoT) solutions. With WSS, developers can now integrate QR
                code scanning functionality that empowers end users to connect their Wi-Fi enabled
                devices using simple bar code scans, reducing device setup time and minimizing the
                need for technical support compared to manual configurations.&lt;br&gt; &lt;br&gt;
                The WSS capability operates through the managed integrations feature of AWS IoT
                Device Management. Managed integrations enables developers to control and manage
                devices across different vendors and connectivity protocols, while WSS helps
                streamline the device onboarding process. Once users securely store their Wi-Fi
                credentials in managed integrations, new device setup becomes nearly automatic.
                Users simply power on their new IoT device and scan its QR code using the solution
                provider's mobile app. The new device discovers and connects to a hidden network
                broadcasted by the IoT hub, which securely transmits the user's pre-stored Wi-Fi
                credentials to complete the onboarding process. This creates a near zero-touch
                experience for end users to securely and conveniently onboard Wi-Fi-connected
                devices into managed integrations-based IoT solutions.&lt;br&gt; &lt;br&gt; The
                managed integrations feature is available in Canada (Central) and Europe (Ireland)
                To learn more, refer to the &lt;a
                href="https://docs.aws.amazon.com/iot-mi/latest/devguide/what-is-managedintegrations.html"&gt;developer
                guide&lt;/a&gt; and get started on the &lt;a
                href="https://console.aws.amazon.com/iot/home"&gt;AWS IoT
                console&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
            <pubDate>Wed, 14 Jan 2026 17:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <category>
                marketing:marchitecture/internet-of-things,general:products/aws-iot-device-management</category>
            <author>aws@amazon.com</author>
            <link>
                https://aws.amazon.com/about-aws/whats-new/2026/01/aws-iot-device-management-wifi-simple-setup/</link>
        </item>
        <item>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">cd7d09cf4d4c8ad0270650765748a0b60fe1822e</guid>
            <title>AWS Transform custom adds AWS PrivateLink support and expands to Europe
                (Frankfurt) Region</title>
            <description>&lt;p&gt;AWS Transform custom now supports AWS PrivateLink and is available
                in a new AWS Region, Europe (Frankfurt), in addition to the US East (N. Virginia)
                Region. AWS Transform custom helps organizations reduce technical debt by automating
                repetitive transformation tasks such as language version upgrades, API migrations,
                and framework updates. The agent is designed for enterprise development teams and
                consulting partners who need to execute consistent, repeatable code transformations
                across large codebases.&lt;br&gt; &lt;br&gt; With AWS Transform custom, teams can
                create custom transformation definitions using natural language, documentation, and
                code samples, or use AWS-managed transformations for common scenarios including
                Java, Python, and Node.js version upgrades. Through continual learning, the service
                improves transformation quality with every execution over time. With AWS PrivateLink
                support, customers can now access AWS Transform custom from their Amazon VPC without
                routing traffic over the public internet, helping meet security and compliance
                requirements.&lt;br&gt; &lt;br&gt; To learn more about AWS Transform custom, visit
                the &lt;a href="https://aws.amazon.com/transform/custom/"
                target="_blank"&gt;&lt;u&gt;product page&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a
                href="https://docs.aws.amazon.com/transform/latest/userguide/custom.html"
                target="_blank"&gt;&lt;u&gt;user guide&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
            <pubDate>Wed, 14 Jan 2026 17:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <category>
                marketing:marchitecture/migration,marketing:marchitecture/developer-tools,marketing:marchitecture/artificial-intelligence</category>
            <author>aws@amazon.com</author>
            <link>
                https://aws.amazon.com/about-aws/whats-new/2026/01/aws-transform-custom-privatelink-europe-frankfurt-region/</link>
        </item>
        <item>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">6b4b6b7417b43c4de8fe4d0577e0bd728c512424</guid>
            <title>Amazon Connect makes it easier to manage recurring overrides for hours of
                operation</title>
            <description>&lt;p&gt;Amazon Connect now makes it easier to manage contact center
                operating hours for recurring events like holidays, maintenance windows, and
                promotional periods, with a visual calendar that provides at-a-glance visibility by
                day, month, or year. You can set up recurring overrides that automatically take
                effect weekly, monthly, or every other Friday, and use them to provide customers
                with personalized experiences, all without having to manually revisit
                configurations. For example, every January 1st you can automatically greet customers
                with "Happy New Year!" and route them to a special holiday message before checking
                if agents are available, then on January 2nd your contact center automatically
                returns to normal operations.&lt;br&gt; &lt;br&gt; These additional hours of
                operation override capabilities are available in all &lt;a
                href="https://docs.aws.amazon.com/connect/latest/adminguide/regions.html#amazonconnect_region"
                target="_blank" title="AWS regions"&gt;AWS regions&lt;/a&gt; where Amazon Connect is
                available and offer public API and AWS CloudFormation support. To learn more, see
                the &lt;a
                href="https://docs.aws.amazon.com/connect/latest/adminguide/set-hours-operation.html"
                target="_blank" title="Amazon Connect Administrator Guide."&gt;Amazon Connect
                Administrator Guide&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a
                href="https://docs.aws.amazon.com/connect/latest/adminguide/use-contact-segment-attributes.html"&gt;.&lt;/a&gt;
                To learn more about Amazon Connect, please visit the &lt;a
                href="https://aws.amazon.com/connect/" target="_blank" title="Amazon Connect
                website."&gt;Amazon Connect website&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
            <pubDate>Wed, 14 Jan 2026 15:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <category>
                general:products/amazon-connect,marketing:marchitecture/business-productivity,general:products/aws-govcloud-us,marketing:marchitecture/applications</category>
            <author>aws@amazon.com</author>
            <link>
                https://aws.amazon.comabout-aws/whats-new/2026/01/amazon-connect-recurring-hour-operation-overrides</link>
        </item>
        <item>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">d472ff751b5ae283fa2214576e55d5a56ee417d9</guid>
            <title>Enhanced Transactions view now available in AWS Billing Console</title>
            <description>&lt;p&gt;AWS announces significant improvements to the Transactions view in
                the AWS Billing and Cost Management Console’s Payments page, delivering faster
                performance, simplified payment reconciliation, and improved data accuracy. The
                enhanced view provides customers with a unified interface to manage all their
                financial transactions, improving visibility and reducing the time spent on payment
                tracking.&lt;br&gt; &lt;br&gt; The enhanced view delivers improved performance, with
                pages loading in mili seconds instead of minutes. Even customers with tens of
                thousands of transactions can now access their complete transaction history without
                timeouts. The enhanced view introduces new capabilities including comprehensive
                balance tracking, clear transaction status indicators, and advanced filtering
                options. Key improvements include consolidated visibility into invoice statuses,
                clear +/- indicators for amounts owed versus funds available, and the ability to
                view records in a single view without performance impact. For organizations using
                &lt;a
                href="https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/aws/new-aws-billing-transfer-for-centrally-managing-aws-billing-and-costs-across-multiple-organizations/"
                target="_blank"&gt;Billing Transfer&lt;/a&gt;, the new "Usage Consolidation Account"
                column makes it easier to track transactions across multiple accounts.&lt;br&gt;
                &lt;br&gt; This feature was made available to all customers on January 12, 2026, in
                all AWS commercial regions.&lt;br&gt; &lt;br&gt; To learn more about managing your
                transactions, visit the &lt;a
                href="https://docs.aws.amazon.com/awsaccountbilling/latest/aboutv2/view-payment-info.html"
                target="_blank"&gt;AWS Billing and Cost Management documentation.&lt;/a&gt; For
                additional information about managing your AWS payments and billing, see the &lt;a
                href="https://docs.aws.amazon.com/awsaccountbilling/latest/aboutv2/billing-what-is.html"
                target="_blank"&gt;AWS Billing Console User Guide&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
            <pubDate>Wed, 14 Jan 2026 15:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <category>general:products/cloud-financial-management</category>
            <author>aws@amazon.com</author>
            <link>
                https://aws.amazon.com/about-aws/whats-new/2026/01/enhanced-transactions-view-aws-billing-console</link>
        </item>
        <item>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">e6bc60b99ce6a5eb05ddb78493a03341ccef2405</guid>
            <title>Amazon Neptune Database now supports R7g and R8g instances in 5 additional
                regions</title>
            <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://aws.amazon.com/neptune/"&gt;Amazon Neptune
                Database&lt;/a&gt; now supports Graviton3-based R7g and Graviton4-based R8g
                instances for Amazon Neptune engine versions 1.4.5 or above, in Asia Pacific (Hong
                Kong), Asia Pacific (Osaka), Asia Pacific (Singapore), Canada (Central) and US West
                (N. California). R7g and R8g instances are priced -16% vs R6g.&lt;br&gt; &lt;br&gt;
                Graviton3-based R7g are the first AWS database instances to feature the latest DDR5
                memory, enabling high-speed access to data in memory. R7g database instances offer
                up to 30Gbps enhanced networking bandwidth and up to 20 Gbps of bandwidth to the
                Amazon Elastic Block Store (Amazon EBS). Graviton4-based R8g instances offer larger
                instance sizes, up to 48xlarge and features an 8:1 ratio of memory to vCPU, and the
                latest DDR5 memory.&amp;nbsp;AWS Graviton4 processors are up to 40% faster for
                databases than AWS Graviton3 processors.&lt;br&gt; &lt;br&gt; You can launch R7g and
                R8g instances for Neptune using the &lt;a
                href="https://console.aws.amazon.com/neptune/"&gt;AWS Management Console&lt;/a&gt;
                or using the &lt;a
                href="https://awscli.amazonaws.com/v2/documentation/api/latest/reference/neptune/index.html"&gt;AWS
                CLI&lt;/a&gt;. Upgrading a Neptune cluster to R7g or R8g instances requires a simple
                instance type modification for Neptune engine versions 1.4.5 or higher. For more
                information on pricing and regional availability, refer to the &lt;a
                href="https://aws.amazon.com/neptune/pricing/"&gt;Amazon Neptune pricing
                page&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
            <pubDate>Tue, 13 Jan 2026 19:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <category>marketing:marchitecture/databases,general:products/amazon-neptune</category>
            <author>aws@amazon.com</author>
            <link>
                https://aws.amazon.com/about-aws/whats-new/2026/01/amazon-neptune-database-r7g-r8g-additional-regions</link>
        </item>
        <item>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">12ef2e978c9cb5bbe6b6f35ef37194f8fafb841d</guid>
            <title>Amazon EC2 X8aedz instances are now available in Asia Pacific (Mumbai, Seoul)
                regions</title>
            <description>&lt;p&gt;Starting today, Amazon Elastic Compute Cloud (Amazon EC2) X8aedz
                instances are available in Asia Pacific (Mumbai) and Asia Pacific (Seoul) regions.
                These instances are powered by 5th Gen AMD EPYC processors (formerly code named
                Turin). These instances offer the highest maximum CPU frequency, 5GHz in the
                cloud.&lt;br&gt; &lt;br&gt; X8aedz instances are built using the latest sixth
                generation &lt;a href="https://aws.amazon.com/ec2/nitro/"&gt;AWS Nitro
                Cards&lt;/a&gt; and are ideal for electronic design automation (EDA) workloads such
                as physical layout and physical verification jobs, and relational databases that
                benefit from high single-threaded processor performance and a large memory
                footprint. The combination of 5 GHz processors and local NVMe storage enables faster
                processing of memory-intensive backend EDA workloads such as floor planning, logic
                placement, clock tree synthesis (CTS), routing, and power/signal integrity
                analysis.&lt;br&gt; &lt;br&gt; X8aedz instances feature a 32:1 ratio of memory to
                vCPU and are available in 8 sizes ranging from 2 to 96 vCPUs with 64 to 3,072 GiB of
                memory, including two bare metal variants, and up to 8 TB of local NVMe SSD
                storage.&lt;br&gt; &lt;br&gt; Customers can purchase X8aedz instances via Savings
                Plans, On-Demand instances, and Spot instances. To get started, sign in to the AWS
                Management Console. For more information visit the Amazon EC2 &lt;a
                href="https://aws.amazon.com/ec2/instance-types/x8aedz"&gt;X8aedz instance
                page&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
            <pubDate>Tue, 13 Jan 2026 17:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <category>marketing:marchitecture/compute,general:products/amazon-ec2</category>
            <author>aws@amazon.com</author>
            <link>
                https://aws.amazon.com/about-aws/whats-new/2026/01/amazon-ec2-x8aedz-instances-asia-pacific-mumbai-seoul-regions</link>
        </item>
        <item>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">c79ba182b4ab439bc670600e7a5b12f8bf6e8fa8</guid>
            <title>Amazon RDS for PostgreSQL announces Extended Support minor 12.22-rds.20251114 and
                11.22-rds.20251114 </title>
            <description>&lt;p&gt;Amazon Relational Database Service (RDS) for PostgreSQL announces
                Amazon RDS Extended Support minor version &amp;nbsp;12.22-rds.20251114 and
                11.22-rds.20251114. We recommend that you upgrade to this version to fix known
                security vulnerabilities and bugs in prior versions of PostgreSQL.&lt;br&gt;
                &lt;br&gt; Amazon RDS Extended Support provides you more time, up to three years, to
                upgrade to a new major version to help you meet your business requirements. During
                Extended Support, Amazon RDS will provide critical security and bug fixes for your
                PostgreSQL databases after the community ends support for a major version. You can
                run your PostgreSQL databases on Amazon RDS with Extended Support for up to three
                years beyond a major version’s end of standard support date. Learn more about
                Extended Support in the &lt;a
                href="https://docs.amazonaws.cn/en_us/AmazonRDS/latest/UserGuide/Welcome.html"
                target="_blank"&gt;Amazon RDS User Guide&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;br&gt; &lt;br&gt; You can
                leverage automatic minor version upgrades to automatically upgrade your databases to
                more recent minor versions during scheduled maintenance windows. Learn more about
                upgrading your database instances, including automatic minor version upgrades, in
                the &lt;a
                href="https://docs.amazonaws.cn/zh_cn/AmazonRDS/latest/UserGuide/CHAP_MySQL.html"
                target="_blank"&gt;Amazon RDS User Guide&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;br&gt; &lt;br&gt; Amazon RDS
                for PostgreSQL makes it easy to set up, operate, and scale PostgreSQL deployments in
                the cloud. Amazon RDS for PostgreSQL is available in all commercial and gov cloud
                region. See &lt;a href="https://www.amazonaws.cn/en/rds/pricing/"
                target="_blank"&gt;Amazon RDS for PostgreSQL&lt;/a&gt; for pricing details. Create
                or update a fully managed Amazon RDS database in the &lt;a
                href="https://console.amazonaws.cn/?nc2=h_m_mc" target="_blank"&gt;Amazon RDS
                Management Console&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;b&gt;&lt;br&gt; &lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
            <pubDate>Tue, 13 Jan 2026 17:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <category>marketing:marchitecture/databases,general:products/amazon-rds</category>
            <author>aws@amazon.com</author>
            <link>
                https://aws.amazon.com/about-aws/whats-new/2026/1/amazon-rds-for-postgresql-announces-extended-support-minor-12-22-rds-20251114-and-11-22-rds-20251114</link>
        </item>
        <item>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">5dc418585e96b12c91eaa908e3a5a72f95e9b6f7</guid>
            <title>Amazon Connect Cases now supports AWS CloudFormation</title>
            <description>
                &lt;p&gt;Amazon Connect Cases now supports AWS CloudFormation, enabling you
                to model, provision, and manage case resources as infrastructure as code. With this
                launch, administrators can create CloudFormation templates to programmatically
                deploy and update their Cases configuration—such as templates, fields, and
                layouts—across Amazon Connect instances, reducing manual setup time and minimizing
                configuration errors.&lt;br&gt; &lt;br&gt; Amazon Connect Cases is available in the
                following AWS Regions: US East (N. Virginia), US West (Oregon), Canada (Central),
                Europe (Frankfurt), Europe (London), Asia Pacific (Seoul), Asia Pacific (Singapore),
                Asia Pacific (Sydney), Asia Pacific (Tokyo), and Africa (Cape Town). To learn more
                and get started, visit the Amazon Connect Cases &lt;a
                href="https://aws.amazon.com/connect/cases/"&gt;webpage&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a
                href="https://docs.aws.amazon.com/AWSCloudFormation/latest/TemplateReference/AWS_Cases.html"&gt;documentation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
            <pubDate>Tue, 13 Jan 2026 16:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <category>
                marketing:marchitecture/business-productivity,marketing:marchitecture/contact-center,general:products/amazon-connect,marketing:marchitecture/messaging</category>
            <author>aws@amazon.com</author>
            <link>
                https://aws.amazon.com/about-aws/whats-new/2026/01/amazon-connect-cases-aws-cloudformation/</link>
        </item>
        <item>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">420deba322c4c7d870e755a301259532e84336e7</guid>
            <title>Amazon Lex launches improved speech recognition models for English</title>
            <description>&lt;p&gt;Amazon Lex now offers a neural automatic speech recognition (ASR)
                model for English that delivers improved recognition accuracy for your voice bots.
                Trained on data from multiple English locales, the model excels at recognizing
                conversational speech patterns across diverse speaking styles, including non-native
                English speakers and regional accents. This reduces the need for end-customers to
                repeat themselves and improves self-service success rates. To enable this feature,
                select "Neural" as the speech recognition option in your bot's locale
                settings.&lt;br&gt; &lt;br&gt; This feature is available in all AWS commercial
                regions where Amazon Connect and Lex operate. To learn more, visit the &lt;a
                href="https://docs.aws.amazon.com/lexv2/latest/dg/customizing-speech-model-preferences.html"
                target="_blank"&gt;Amazon Lex documentation&lt;/a&gt; or explore the Amazon Connect
                &lt;a href="https://aws.amazon.com/connect/self-service/"
                target="_blank"&gt;website&lt;/a&gt; to learn how Amazon Connect and Amazon Lex
                deliver seamless end-customer self-service experiences.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
            <pubDate>Tue, 13 Jan 2026 15:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <category>
                marketing:marchitecture/customer-enablement,marketing:marchitecture/business-productivity,marketing:marchitecture/artificial-intelligence,general:products/amazon-lex</category>
            <author>aws@amazon.com</author>
            <link>
                https://aws.amazon.com/about-aws/whats-new/2026/01/amazon-lex-improved-speech-recognition-models-english</link>
        </item>
        <item>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">d96529b553e44c5914b5b2b1f294bd0845ac83f1</guid>
            <title>Amazon MSK Connect is now available in three additional AWS Regions</title>
            <description>&lt;p&gt;Amazon MSK Connect is now available in three additional AWS
                Regions: Asia Pacific (New Zealand), AWS GovCloud (US-East), and AWS GovCloud
                (US-West).&lt;br&gt; &lt;br&gt; MSK Connect enables you to run fully managed Kafka
                Connect clusters with Amazon Managed Streaming for Apache Kafka (Amazon MSK). With a
                few clicks, MSK Connect allows you to easily deploy, monitor, and scale connectors
                that move data in and out of Apache Kafka and Amazon MSK clusters from external
                systems such as databases, file systems, and search indices. MSK Connect eliminates
                the need to provision and maintain cluster infrastructure. Connectors scale
                automatically in response to increases in usage and you pay only for the resources
                you use. With full compatibility with Kafka Connect, it is easy to migrate workloads
                without code changes. MSK Connect will support both Amazon MSK-managed and
                self-managed Apache Kafka clusters.&lt;br&gt; &lt;br&gt; You can get started with
                MSK Connect from the Amazon MSK console or the Amazon CLI. With this launch, MSK
                Connect is now available in thirty eight AWS Regions. To get started visit, the MSK
                Connect &lt;a href="https://aws.amazon.com/msk/features/msk-connect/"
                target="_blank"&gt;product page&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a
                href="https://aws.amazon.com/msk/pricing/" target="_blank"&gt;pricing
                page&lt;/a&gt;, and the &lt;a
                href="https://docs.aws.amazon.com/msk/latest/developerguide/msk-connect.html"
                target="_blank"&gt;Amazon MSK Developer Guide&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
            <pubDate>Tue, 13 Jan 2026 15:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <category>general:products/amazon-msk,marketing:marchitecture/analytics</category>
            <author>aws@amazon.com</author>
            <link>
                https://aws.amazon.com/about-aws/whats-new/2026/01/amazon-msk-connect-additional-aws-regions</link>
        </item>
        <item>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">1a41146883cf866fa3b5ebd5d5605d4cc99730c6</guid>
            <title>Amazon SageMaker HyperPod now validates service quotas before creating clusters
                on console</title>
            <description>&lt;p&gt;Amazon SageMaker HyperPod console now validates service
                quotas&amp;nbsp;for your AWS account before initiating cluster creation, enabling
                you to confirm sufficient quota availability before provisioning begins. SageMaker
                HyperPod helps you provision resilient clusters for running AI/ML workloads and
                developing state-of-the-art models such as large language models (LLMs), diffusion
                models, and foundation models (FMs).&lt;br&gt; &lt;br&gt; When creating large-scale
                AI/ML clusters, you need to ensure your account has sufficient quotas for instances,
                storage, and networking resources, but quota validation previously required manual
                checks across multiple AWS services, often resulting in failed cluster creation
                attempts and wasted time if you miss requesting quota limit increases. The new quota
                validation capability in the SageMaker HyperPod console automatically checks your
                account-level quotas against your cluster configuration, including instance type
                limits, EBS volume sizes, and VPC-related quotas when creating new resources. The
                validation displays a clear table showing expected utilization, applied quota
                values, and compliance status for each quota. When quotas may be exceeded, you
                receive a warning alert with direct links to the Service Quotas console to request
                increases.&lt;br&gt; &lt;br&gt; This feature is available in all AWS Regions where
                Amazon SageMaker HyperPod is supported. For a complete list of service quota
                validation checks performed, refer to the &lt;a
                href="https://docs.aws.amazon.com/sagemaker/latest/dg/sagemaker-hyperpod-prerequisites.html#sagemaker-hyperpod-prerequisites-quotas"&gt;Amazon
                SageMaker HyperPod User Guide&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
            <pubDate>Mon, 12 Jan 2026 18:10:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <category>
                marketing:marchitecture/artificial-intelligence,general:products/amazon-sagemaker</category>
            <author>aws@amazon.com</author>
            <link>
                https://aws.amazon.com/about-aws/whats-new/2026/01/amazon-sagemaker-hyperpod-validates-service-quotas/</link>
        </item>
        <item>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">c28ddcd866892f75d9bc445b4e385c3c263d9f81</guid>
            <title>Amazon Lex launches configurable voice activity detection sensitivity</title>
            <description>&lt;p&gt;Amazon Lex now provides three VAD sensitivity levels that can be
                configured for each bot locale: Default, High, and Maximum. The Default setting is
                suitable for most environments with typical background noise levels. High is
                designed for environments with consistent but moderate noise levels, such as busy
                offices or retail spaces. Maximum provides the highest tolerance for very noisy
                environments such as manufacturing floors, construction sites, or outdoor locations
                with significant ambient noise. You can configure VAD sensitivity when creating or
                updating a bot locale in the Amazon Connect's Conversational AI designer.&lt;/p&gt;
                &lt;p&gt;This feature is available in all AWS commercial regions where Amazon
                Connect and Lex operate. To learn more, visit the &lt;a target="_blank"
                href="https://docs.aws.amazon.com/lexv2/latest/dg/customizing-speech-vad-sensitivity.html"&gt;Amazon
                Lex documentation&lt;/a&gt; or explore the Amazon Connect &lt;a target="_blank"
                href="https://aws.amazon.com/connect/self-service/"&gt;website&lt;/a&gt; to learn
                how Amazon Connect and Amazon Lex deliver seamless end-customer self-service
                experiences.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
            <pubDate>Mon, 12 Jan 2026 18:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <category>
                marketing:marchitecture/artificial-intelligence,marketing:marchitecture/contact-center,general:products/amazon-lex</category>
            <author>aws@amazon.com</author>
            <link>
                https://aws.amazon.com/about-aws/whats-new/2026/01/amazon-lex-configurable-voice-activity-detection-sensitivity/</link>
        </item>
        <item>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">7e924cf08172b6429741609bee0f3c935a54398d</guid>
            <title>Amazon Connect now provides agent screen recording status tracking</title>
            <description>&lt;p&gt;Amazon Connect now offers customers the ability to view status of
                agent screen recordings in near real time in CloudWatch using Amazon EventBridge.
                With screen recording, supervisors can identify areas for agent coaching (e.g.,
                non-compliance with business processes) by not only listening to customer calls or
                reviewing chat transcripts, but also watching agents’ actions while handling a
                contact (i.e., a voice call, chat and task). Using Amazon EventBridge, customers can
                see status of each agent screen recording including success/failure, failure codes
                with description, installed client version, agent web browser version, agent
                operating system, screen recording start and end times from CloudWatch.&lt;br&gt;
                &lt;br&gt; Customers can start using Amazon Connect screen recording status tracking
                by subscribing to &lt;i&gt;Screen Recording Status Changed &lt;/i&gt;event type in
                Amazon EventBridge event bus.&lt;br&gt; &lt;br&gt; Screen recording status tracking
                is available in all the &lt;a
                href="https://docs.aws.amazon.com/general/latest/gr/connect_region.html"
                target="_blank"&gt;AWS Regions&lt;/a&gt; where Amazon Connect is already available.
                To learn more about screen recording, please visit the &lt;a
                href="https://docs.aws.amazon.com/connect/latest/adminguide/agent-screen-recording.html"
                target="_blank"&gt;documentation&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a
                href="https://aws.amazon.com/connect/contact-lens/"
                target="_blank"&gt;webpage&lt;/a&gt;. For information about screen recording
                pricing, visit the &lt;a href="https://aws.amazon.com/connect/pricing/"
                target="_blank"&gt;Amazon Connect pricing page.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
            <pubDate>Mon, 12 Jan 2026 15:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <category>general:products/amazon-connect,marketing:marchitecture/business-productivity</category>
            <author>aws@amazon.com</author>
            <link>
                https://aws.amazon.com/about-aws/whats-new/2026/01/amazon-connect-agent-screen-recording-status-tracking</link>
        </item>
        <item>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">9cd2835966de8c61141858e222bc3cca0fd84d4d</guid>
            <title>Amazon Redshift Serverless is now available in the AWS Asia Pacific (New Zealand)
                region</title>
            <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://aws.amazon.com/redshift/redshift-serverless/"
                target="_blank"&gt;Amazon Redshift Serverless&lt;/a&gt;, which allows you to run and
                scale analytics without having to provision and manage data warehouse clusters, is
                now generally available in the AWS Asia Pacific (New Zealand) region. With Amazon
                Redshift Serverless, all users, including data analysts, developers, and data
                scientists, can use Amazon Redshift to get insights from data in seconds. Amazon
                Redshift Serverless automatically provisions and intelligently scales data warehouse
                capacity to deliver high performance for all your analytics. You only pay for the
                compute used for the duration of the workloads on a per-second basis. You can
                benefit from this simplicity without making any changes to your existing analytics
                and business intelligence applications.&lt;br&gt; &lt;br&gt; With a few clicks in
                the AWS Management Console, you can get started with querying data using the Query
                Editor V2 or your tool of choice with Amazon Redshift Serverless. There is no need
                to choose node types, node count, workload management, scaling, and other manual
                configurations. You can create databases, schemas, and tables, and load your own
                data from Amazon S3, access data using Amazon Redshift data shares, or restore an
                existing Amazon Redshift provisioned cluster snapshot. With Amazon Redshift
                Serverless, you can directly query data in open formats, such as Apache Parquet,
                Apache Iceberg in Amazon S3 data lakes. Amazon Redshift Serverless provides unified
                billing for queries on any of these data sources, helping you efficiently monitor
                and manage costs.&lt;br&gt; &lt;br&gt; To get started, see the Amazon Redshift
                Serverless &lt;a href="https://aws.amazon.com/redshift/redshift-serverless/"
                target="_blank"&gt;feature page&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a
                href="https://docs.aws.amazon.com/redshift/latest/mgmt/working-with-serverless.html"
                target="_blank"&gt;user documentation&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a
                href="https://docs.aws.amazon.com/redshift-serverless/latest/APIReference/Welcome.html"
                target="_blank"&gt;API Reference&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
            <pubDate>Mon, 12 Jan 2026 14:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <category>
                marketing:marchitecture/databases,general:products/amazon-redshift,marketing:marchitecture/analytics</category>
            <author>aws@amazon.com</author>
            <link>
                https://aws.amazon.com/about-aws/whats-new/2026/01/amazon-redshift-serverless-aws-asia-pacific-new-zealand-region</link>
        </item>
        <item>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">846184d5b6cba66f2a84e000e46d4cce908f3a31</guid>
            <title>Amazon Inspector adds Java Gradle support and expands ecosystem coverage</title>
            <description>&lt;p&gt;Amazon Inspector scanning for Lambda functions and Elastic
                Container Registry (ECR) images now supports Java Gradle inventory and vulnerability
                scanning. This release also adds coverage for MySQL, MariaDB, PHP, Jenkins-core,
                7zip (on Windows), Elasticsearch, and Curl/LibCurl. This update enhances Amazon
                Inspector's ability to detect vulnerabilities and misconfigurations across a broader
                range of applications and environments. Amazon Inspector is an automated
                vulnerability management service that continually scans AWS workloads for software
                vulnerabilities and unintended network exposure, helping organizations improve their
                security posture and meet compliance requirements.&lt;br&gt; &lt;br&gt; The new Java
                Gradle support allows Inspector to scan Java dependencies based on gradle.lockfile
                content, providing comprehensive vulnerability assessments for Java applications.
                When you use Inspector to scan Lambda functions and ECR images, you will now see
                findings for MySQL, MariaDB, PHP, Jenkins-core, 7zip (on Windows), Elasticsearch,
                and Curl/LibCurl installations. These enhancements enable more accurate detection of
                vulnerabilities in packages installed outside of package managers, improving overall
                security coverage for AWS customers using these technologies.&lt;br&gt; &lt;br&gt;
                To learn more about Amazon Inspector and how it can help secure your AWS workloads,
                visit the &lt;a href="https://aws.amazon.com/inspector/"&gt;Amazon Inspector
                page&lt;/a&gt;. For a full list of Amazon Inspector supported operating systems and
                programming languages, see the &lt;a
                href="https://docs.aws.amazon.com/inspector/latest/user/supported.html"&gt;user
                guide&lt;/a&gt;. You can start using these new features today in all AWS Regions
                where Amazon Inspector is available.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
            <pubDate>Mon, 12 Jan 2026 13:51:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <category>
                general:products/amazon-inspector,general:products/aws-govcloud-us,marketing:marchitecture/security-identity-and-compliance</category>
            <author>aws@amazon.com</author>
            <link>
                https://aws.amazon.com/about-aws/whats-new/2026/01/amazon-inspector-java-gradle-ecosystem/</link>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>